<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:prism="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/prism/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society Current Issue</title>
    <link>http://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 22:48:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Silverchair</generator>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/226/6413462">
      <title>Macroecology of Southern Ocean benthic Ostracoda (Crustacea) from the continental margin and abyss</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/226/6413462?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Brandão S, Saeedi H, Brandt A. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The Southern Ocean (SO) is the least understood environment on earth, but anthropogenic impacts related to climate change, fishing activities and tourism are already well-established in the region. Herein, we investigate biodiversity patterns in the Atlantic Sector of the SO by investigating a considerable number of samples collected from a wide depth range (89–6224 m). Three topics are addressed: (1) which taxa occur in the SO; (2) if there are distinct shelf, slope and abyssal faunas; and (3) which abiotic parameters explain the ostracod assemblages. We also tested putative ecological preferences of ostracod genera, widely used in palaeoceanographical reconstruction. For this, almost 5000 living ostracods from 51 epibenthic sledge samples were identified to 140 species. Statistically significant differences were observed among the faunas from the shelf, slope and abyssal faunas, indicating that the shelf fauna survived in refugia during the glacial periods of the Quaternary. Our analyses showed that the main variables influencing ostracod distribution is depth, followed by nitrate and phosphate. Temperature, salinity and oxygen content do not seem to be as important as previously proposed. Putative ecological preferences of ostracod genera, for example, low oxygen for &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cytherella&lt;/span&gt;, could not be confirmed, suggesting that this topic requires further investigation.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">226</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">255</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab078</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab078</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/276/6408716">
      <title>Neolepetopsid true limpets (Gastropoda: Patellogastropoda) from Indian Ocean hot vents shed light on relationships among genera</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/276/6408716?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Chen C, Zhou Y, Watanabe H, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Neolepetopsidae is a family of true limpets restricted to deep-sea chemosynthesis-based ecosystems. It is a small and little-studied family with about a dozen species in three genera, namely &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Eulepetopsis&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Neolepetopsis&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Paralepetopsis&lt;/span&gt;, and all named species were from the Pacific or Atlantic Oceans. Here, we describe three new species from Indian Ocean vents, namely &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Eulepetopsis crystallina&lt;/span&gt; sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt; found across three ridges,&lt;strong&gt;Š&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Neolepetopsis ardua&lt;/span&gt; sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt; from the Southwest Indian Ridge and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Neolepetopsis prismatica&lt;/span&gt; sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt; from the Carlsberg Ridge. Given that &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Neolepetopsis&lt;/span&gt; appears to specialize on inactive sulfide deposits, the apparent wider distribution of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;E. crystallina&lt;/span&gt; is probably attributable to bias in sampling effort at inactive chimneys. The molecular phylogeny of Patellogastropoda, reconstructed using the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;COI&lt;/span&gt; gene, supported the monophyly of Neolepetopsidae. These are the first molecular data available for &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Neolepetopsis&lt;/span&gt;, confirming that the three genera are genetically distinct. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Eulepetopsis&lt;/span&gt; appears to be adapted to active vents, and its derived position compared with &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Paralepetopsis&lt;/span&gt; indicates a possible ‘stepping-stone’ evolutionary pathway from seeps and organic falls to vents. Our results provide new insights into this enigmatic family and highlight the importance of surveying the vent periphery, especially given that inactive vents are being eyed as a replacement for active ones in deep-sea mining.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">276</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">296</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab081</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab081</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/323/6377815">
      <title>Evolution and phylogeny of glass-sponge-associated zoantharians, with a description of two new genera and three new species</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/323/6377815?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kise H, Montenegro J, Santos M, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Hexactinellid sponges are important members of deep-sea benthic ecosystems because they provide available hard substrate habitats for filter-feeding invertebrates. However, symbioses between hexactinellid sponges and their symbionts are poorly known. Zoantharians associated with hexactinellid sponges have been reported widely from deep-sea marine ecosystems, either on the bodies or stalks of hexactinellid sponges. Despite these records, there has been a lack of research on their diversity and phylogenetic relationships. In this study, 20 specimens associated with amphidiscophoran and hexasterophoran sponges were collected from the waters of Australia and Japan in the Pacific, and from Curaçao in the southern Caribbean, and these were examined in addition to museum specimens. Based on molecular phylogenetic analyses and morphological observations, we formally describe two new genera and three new species of Zoantharia and report several previously described species. The results suggest at least two independent origins for the symbioses between hexactinellid sponges and zoantharians. Our results demonstrate that the diversity of hexactinellid sponge-associated zoantharians is much higher than has been previously thought. The new taxa described in this work further reconfirm that the deep-sea harbours high levels of undescribed zoantharian diversity.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">323</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">347</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab068</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab068</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/14/6374262">
      <title>New record of the wood-associated sea star Caymanostella, with notes on the phylogenetic position of the family Caymanostellidae (Asteroidea)</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/14/6374262?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dilman A, Minin K, Petrov N. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;In 2016, three specimens of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Caymanostella&lt;/span&gt; were collected from the Kuril-Kamchatka Trench area at depths of 5101–5134 m. Comparative morphological analysis revealed that the new specimens are similar to &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Caymanostella spinimarginata&lt;/span&gt;, the most geographically distant species (Atlantic Ocean). The new specimens were identified as &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;C.&lt;/span&gt; cf. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;spinimarginata.&lt;/span&gt; Multilocus genetic data were obtained for the family Caymanostellidae for the first time in this study. Molecular evidence based on the analyses of three mitochondrial and two nuclear markers recovers the family Caymanostellidae as a sister-taxon to Ophidiasteridae (order Valvatida). Phylogenetic data indicate that morphological features, which were previously used to imply asterinid, xyloplacid or korethrasterid affinities for the family Caymanostellidae, emerged independently. It is suggested that the family Caymanostellidae should be placed within the order Valvatida.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">14</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">35</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab060</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab060</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/136/6358980">
      <title>Phylogeny and biogeography of the pantropical whip spider family Charinidae (Arachnida: Amblypygi)</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/136/6358980?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>De Miranda G, Giupponi A, Scharff N, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The present contribution addresses the phylogeny and biogeography of the pantropical whip spider family Charinidae Quintero, 1986, the most species-rich in the arachnid order Amblypygi Thorell, 1883, based on morphology and multilocus DNA sequences, analysed simultaneously using parsimony, maximum likelihood and Bayesian inference. The morphological matrix comprises 138 characters, scored for four outgroup taxa and 103 ingroup terminals representing all genera and 64% of the species of Charinidae. The multilocus dataset comprises sequences from two nuclear and three mitochondrial gene loci for four outgroup taxa and 48 ingroup representing 30 (23%) taxa of Charinidae. Charinidae are monophyletic, with &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Weygoldtia&lt;/span&gt; Miranda &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;, 2018 sister to a monophyletic group comprising &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Charinus&lt;/span&gt; Simon, 1892 and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sarax&lt;/span&gt; Simon, 1892, neither of which are reciprocally monophyletic. Charinidae diverged from other amblypygid families in the Late Carboniferous, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c.&lt;/span&gt; 318 Mya, on the supercontinent Pangaea. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Weygoldtia&lt;/span&gt; diverged from the common ancestor of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Charinus&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sarax&lt;/span&gt; during the Late Permian, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c.&lt;/span&gt; 257 Mya, when changes in climate reduced tropical forests. The divergence of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Charinus&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sarax&lt;/span&gt; coincides with the fragmentation of Pangaea, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c.&lt;/span&gt; 216 Mya. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sarax&lt;/span&gt; colonized South-East Asia via Australia. The charinid fauna of New Caledonia originated before the Oligocene, when the island separated from Australia, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c.&lt;/span&gt; 80 Mya.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">136</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">180</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa101</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa101</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/297/6356088">
      <title>Revision of Beroidae (Ctenophora) in the southern seas of Europe: systematics and distribution based on genetics and morphology</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/297/6356088?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Shiganova T, Abyzova G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Genetic and morphological analyses were used to revise historical controversies in identities of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe&lt;/span&gt; species in the southern seas of Europe. DNA analyses with ITS sequences were used to explore their phylogenetic relationships. Three species of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe&lt;/span&gt; were initially listed as occurring in the Mediterranean Sea. Recently, the specimens were often re-identified using genetic analyses, causing confusions of identity. In 1997, a non-native &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe&lt;/span&gt; was introduced into the Black Sea, which established there and spread to the adjacent seas, adding more controversy and confusion to species identification in this group of comb jellies.Our revisions suggest the following systematic changes: (1) re-naming of the species from what was initially labelled as &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe ovata&lt;/span&gt;, and later as &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;B. cucumis&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;sensu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#CIT0068" class="reflinks"&gt;Mayer, 1912&lt;/a&gt;), to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe pseudocucumis&lt;/span&gt; sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt;. (2) &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe mitrata&lt;/span&gt; but not &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe&lt;/span&gt; ‘&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;anatoliensis&lt;/span&gt;’ inhabits the Aegean Sea, as was reported previously. (3) &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe ovata&lt;/span&gt; is the only species of Beroidae that became invasive and should be used with the authority of &lt;a href="#CIT0008" class="reflinks"&gt;Bruguière, 1789&lt;/a&gt;, but not in the sense of &lt;a href="#CIT0068" class="reflinks"&gt;Mayer, 1912&lt;/a&gt;. (4) &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe forskalii&lt;/span&gt; appears to be represented by two species in the Mediterranean and in the Antarctic, but further justification is needed. (5) &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe cucumis&lt;/span&gt; is a species of bipolar occurrence, inhabiting both subpolar areas and its recent definition as &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Beroe&lt;/span&gt; ‘&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;norvegica&lt;/span&gt;’ is incorrect.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">297</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">322</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab021</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab021</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/1/6320825">
      <title>Osteological characters of birds and reptiles are more congruent with molecular phylogenies than soft characters are</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/1/6320825?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Callender-Crowe L, Sansom R. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Despite increased use of genomic data in phylogenetics, morphological information remains vital for resolving evolutionary relationships, particularly for fossil taxa. The properties and models of evolution of molecular sequence data are well characterized and mature, relative to those of morphological data. Furthermore, heterogeneity, integration and relative homoplasy of empirical morphological data could prove problematic for phylogenetic reconstruction. Here we compare osteological and non-osteological characters of 28 morphological datasets of extant saurians in terms of their homoplasy relative to molecular trees. Analysis of individual avian datasets finds osteological characters to be significantly more consistent with molecular data than soft characters are. Significant differences between morphological partitions were also observed in the age at which characters resolved on molecular trees. Osteological character changes occur relatively earlier in deep branches, whilst soft-tissue character transitions are more recent in shallow branches. The combined results demonstrate differences in evolutionary dynamics between morphological partitions. This may reflect evolutionary constraints acting on osteological characters, compared with the relative lability of soft characters. Furthermore, it provides some support to phylogenetic interpretations of fossil data, including dinosaurs, which are predominately osteological. Recent advances in amphibian and mammal phylogenetics may make these patterns possible to test for all tetrapods.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">13</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa136</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa136</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/181/6304640">
      <title>Exploring the diversity of the deep sea—four new species of the amphipod genus Oedicerina described using morphological and molecular methods</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/181/6304640?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jażdżewska A, Brandt A, Martínez Arbizu P, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Collections of the amphipod genus &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Oedicerina&lt;/span&gt; were obtained during six expeditions devoted to the study of deep-sea environments of the Pacific Ocean. The material revealed four species new to science. Two species (&lt;strong&gt;Oedicerina henrici&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Oedicerina teresae sp. nov.&lt;/strong&gt;) were found at abyssal depths of the central eastern Pacific in the Clarion-Clipperton Zone; one species (Oedicerina claudei sp. nov.) was recovered in the Sea of Okhotsk (north-west Pacific), and one &lt;strong&gt;(Oedicerina lesci sp. nov.)&lt;/strong&gt; in the abyss adjacent to the Kuril-Kamchatka Trench (KKT). The four new species differ from each other and known species by the shapes of the rostrum, coxae 1 and 4, basis of pereopod 7, armatures of pereonite 7, pleonites and urosomites. An identification key for all known species is provided. The study of the cytochrome &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; oxidase subunit I gene of the four new species and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Oedicerina ingolfi&lt;/span&gt; collected in the North Atlantic confirmed their genetic distinction. However, small intraspecific variation within each of the studied species was observed. In the case of the new species occurring across the KKT, the same haplotype was found on both sides of the trench, providing evidence that the trench does not constitute an insurmountable barrier for population connectivity. None of the species have so far been found on both sides of the Pacific.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">181</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">225</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab032</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab032</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/256/6261015">
      <title>The balanced life: evolution of ventral shell weighting in gastropods</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/256/6261015?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Vermeij G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Exaggerated morphologies present challenges for understanding the factors that enable, prevent or compel lineages to evolve unusual functional traits. Here, I examine the case of gastropods whose adult shells are bottom heavy by virtue of a thick, often broad, convex ventral callus deposit on the inner lip and adapical to the aperture. Data on the spatial, temporal and phylogenetic distribution of callus-bearing gastropods were gleaned from the literature and from personal observations on fossil and living gastropods in collections. An exaggerated ventral callus has evolved in ≥ 72 lineages of gastropods, all in warm, shallow waters, beginning in the Late Ordovician but mostly during and after the Late Cretaceous. The phylogenetic distribution of these gastropods is highly clumped, with multiple acquisitions in some clades (e.g. Stromboidea and Buccinoidea) and none in others (e.g. Conoidea). Functional considerations and comparisons indicate that the enhanced gravitational stability provided by a ventral callus evolved only in conditions of low-cost calcification and when predators capable of dislodging or overturning gastropods or causing them to flee were important agents of selection.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">256</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">275</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab019</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab019</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/348/6259356">
      <title>Erratum to: From Arge to Zenarge: adult morphology and phylogenetics of argid sawflies (Hymenoptera: Argidae)</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/348/6259356?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Malagón-Aldana L, Smith D, Shinohara A, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;In the originally published version of this manuscript, Figure 2 appeared twice and Figure 1 was omitted. The duplicate Figure 2 has been removed and the correct Figure 1 reinstated.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">348</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">348</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab028</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab028</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/120/6211633">
      <title>A multigene phylogeny of the eristaline flower flies (Diptera: Syrphidae), with emphasis on the subtribe Criorhinina</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/120/6211633?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Moran K, Skevington J, Kelso S, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;We present the first multigene phylogeny focused on Eristalinae (Diptera: Syrphidae) utilizing a dataset containing 120 flower fly species from across all four subfamilies and representing 13 out of 16 tribes. Eight genes were used in the construction of the phylogeny: mitochondrial cytochrome &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; oxidase subunit I and the nuclear genes 28S ribosomal DNA, Alanylt RNA Synthetase, the carbamoyl phosphate synthase domain of CAD, Period, RNA-binding Protein 15 (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;RBP&lt;/span&gt;–15, 5’), Casein Kinase 1 and TULP for a total of ~6.7 kB of data. Eristalinae is recovered as paraphyletic with strong support for the elevation of Cerioidini, Merodontini and Volucellini to subfamilial status. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Deineches&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Flukea&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Malometasternum&lt;/span&gt; render Criorhinina paraphyletic with respect to the type genus &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Criorhina&lt;/span&gt;. A clade with &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Criorhina&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Matsumyia&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sphecomyia&lt;/span&gt; is strongly supported. The generic concept of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Criorhina&lt;/span&gt; is paraphyletic, while &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sphecomyia&lt;/span&gt; is monophyletic and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Matsumyia&lt;/span&gt; is monophyletic but requires expansion. Evidence supports the resurrection of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Romaleosyrphus&lt;/span&gt; and the creation of new genera. &lt;strong&gt;Criorhinina&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;stat. rev.&lt;/strong&gt;) is restricted to contain &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Criorhina&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Matsumyia&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Romaleosyrphus&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Sphecomyia&lt;/span&gt;. Thirteen changes to the higher classification of Syrphidae are proposed.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">120</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">135</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab006</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab006</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/80/6203404">
      <title>Phylogeny and generic classification of the Anthidiini bees from the Neotropical region (Hymenoptera: Apidae)</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/80/6203404?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Parizotto D, Urban D, Melo G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The Anthidiini is a highly diverse tribe of bees with approximately 700 described species worldwide, of which about 350 occur in the Neotropical region. However, the phylogenetic relationships within the Neotropical lineage are poorly understood and the generic limits of these clades are still controversial, with different proposals of classification. Therefore, we carried out a phylogenetic study to investigate the monophyly of Neotropical taxa, to understand the relationships among Neotropical genera, and to propose a classification congruent with the evolution of the group. We performed parsimony-based morphological analyses using a matrix of 204 characters from adults of 83 species (79 terminal taxa of Anthidiini and four outgroup taxa). The results provide strong support for the monophyly of the tribe, despite a representation biased towards the Neotropical taxa. The monophyly of a large group containing only species from Neotropical genera is also supported. The latter group is divided into six main clades, one of them composed of only cleptoparasitic taxa (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Austrostelis&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Hoplostelis&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Melostelis&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Rhynostelis&lt;/span&gt;). The morphological characters assembled here allowed scrutiny of the genus-level classification of the Neotropical clade and may be useful for future phylogenetic studies involving the Anthidiini from other biogeographic regions.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">80</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">101</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab005</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab005</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/36/6191802">
      <title>Morphology and Bayesian tip-dating recover deep Cretaceous-age divergences among major chrysidid lineages (Hymenoptera: Chrysididae)</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/36/6191802?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Lucena D, Almeida E. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;We integrated phylogenetic, biogeographic and palaeontological data to reconstruct the evolutionary history of the cuckoo wasps. We propose a phylogenetic hypothesis based on a comprehensive morphological study resulting in 300 characters coded for both living and extinct species. Phylogenetic relationships and divergence time estimation were simultaneously inferred in a Bayesian tip-dating framework, applying a relaxed morphological clock. Results unequivocally indicate Chrysididae to be monophyletic, as well as all traditionally recognized subfamilies and tribes. Within the Chrysidinae, Elampini was placed as the sister-group of the other three chrysidine tribes, with Parnopini as sister to the clade including Allocoeliini and Chrysidini. Dating analysis indicates that the major lineages started to differentiate around 130 Mya during the Early Cretaceous. The clades recognized as subfamilies started differentiating during the Palaeogene and the Neogene. Our results reveal an intricate process on the geographic evolution of chrysidid wasps and dispute previous ideas that Cretaceous-old splits in their early history could be associated with vicariant events related to the breakup between Africa and South America. The present-day southern disjunctions of some groups are interpreted as the outcome of more recent dispersals and extinctions of representatives from Nearctic and Palaearctic faunas during the Neogene, when northern continents became significantly colder.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">36</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">79</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab010</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab010</guid>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/102/6188944">
      <title>Integrative taxonomy: molecular phylogenetics of Polypedilum (Cerobregma) and revisited morphology of Yaethauma and Collartomyia (Diptera: Chironomidae) reveals synonymy and supports new classification</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/zoolinnean/article/194/1/102/6188944?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Tang H, Cheng Q, Han W, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;A recently described genus of Chironomini, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma&lt;/span&gt;, is newly associated with a pupa that resembles those in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; subgenus &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cerobregma&lt;/span&gt;. We derived molecular evidence from six concatenated markers from five loci (18S, 28S, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;CAD1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;CAD4&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;COI&lt;/span&gt;-5P, -3P) of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma longiligulatum&lt;/span&gt;, six species of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cerobregma&lt;/span&gt;), ingroup &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; (representing six other subgenera) and appropriate outgroups. Mixed-model Bayesian inference and maximum likelihood strongly supports (PP = 0.97, BS = 99) &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma&lt;/span&gt; belonging to &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt;, as sister to a monophyletic subgenus &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cerobregma&lt;/span&gt;. Integration of morphology of the male and pupa of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma&lt;/span&gt; if corroborated with the molecular evidence, thus we synonymize &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma&lt;/span&gt; (type species &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Yaethauma longiligulatum&lt;/span&gt;) with &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; type species &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum pelostolum&lt;/span&gt; (= &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Chironomus nubifer&lt;/span&gt;). Although molecular material of Afrotropical &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Collartomyia&lt;/span&gt; is lacking, when it is integrated into morphological analyses, its inclusion in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; near &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cerobregma&lt;/span&gt; is well supported. Implementation of this creates further new synonymies with the subjective taxonomic conclusion that &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Collartomyia&lt;/span&gt; (type species &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Collartomyia hirsuta&lt;/span&gt;) is also a junior synonym of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; and a senior synonym of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Cerobregma&lt;/span&gt;). Within &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Polypedilum&lt;/span&gt; only the subgenera &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Collartomyia&lt;/span&gt; subgen. nov&lt;/strong&gt;. and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Tripodura&lt;/span&gt; are recovered as monophyletic groups; the other subgenera are not monophyletic. The larvae of these chironomids often feed within retreats of hydropsychid caddisflies (Trichoptera), with commensurate morphological modifications in all life stages.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume xmlns:prism="prism">194</prism:volume>
      <prism:number xmlns:prism="prism">1</prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage xmlns:prism="prism">102</prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage xmlns:prism="prism">119</prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa187</prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlaa187</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>