
<rss version="0.91">
    <channel>
        <title>Latest Articles from MycoKeys</title>
        <description>Latest 100 Articles from MycoKeys</description>
        <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:59:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Pensoft FeedCreator</generator>
        <image>
            <url>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/i/logo.jpg</url>
            <title>Latest Articles from MycoKeys</title>
            <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Feed provided by https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/. Click to visit.]]></description>
        </image>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿New species and records of Chapsa (Graphidaceae) in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/76040/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 85: 73-85</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.85.76040</p>
					<p>Authors: Ming-Zhu Dou, Min Li, Ze-Feng Jia</p>
					<p>Abstract: We studied the genus Chapsa in China based on morphological characteristics, chemical traits and molecular phylogenetic analysis. One species new to science (C. murioelongata M.Z. Dou &amp; M. Li) and two records new to China were found (C. wolseleyana Weerakoon, Lumbsch &amp; Lücking and C. niveocarpa Mangold). Chapsa murioelongata sp. nov. is characterised by its lobed thalline margin, orange discs with white pruina, clear hymenium, and submuriform and long ascospores. Chapsa wolseleyana was recombined into Astrochapsa based on phenotypic traits. Sequences of this species are for the first time reported here and phylogenetic analyses of three loci (mtSSU, ITS and nuLSU) supported the position of this species within Chapsa. A key for the Chapsa species known in China is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/76040/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/76040/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/76040/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 14:55:43 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Morphological and molecular phylogenetic analyses reveal three species of Colletotrichum in Shandong province, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/75944/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 85: 57-71</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.85.75944</p>
					<p>Authors: Taichang Mu, Zhaoxue Zhang, Rongyu Liu, Shubin Liu, Zhuang Li, Xiuguo Zhang, Jiwen Xia</p>
					<p>Abstract: Colletotrichum has numerous host range and distribution. Its species are important plant pathogens, endophytes and saprobes. Colletotrichum can cause regular or irregular depressions and necrotic lesions in the epidermal tissues of plants. During this research Colletotrichum specimens were collected from Mengyin County, Shandong Province, China. A multi-locus phylogenetic analysis of ITS, GAPDH, CHS-1, ACT, TUB2, CAL and GS sequence data combined with morphology, revealed a new species and two known species, viz. C. mengyinense sp. nov., C. gloeosporioides and C. pandanicola, belonging to the C. gloeosporioides species complex. The new species is described and illustrated in this paper and compared with taxa in the C. gloeosporioides species complex.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/75944/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/75944/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/75944/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Dec 2021 11:37:18 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new asexual genera and six new asexual species in the family Microthyriaceae (Dothideomycetes, Ascomycota) from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70829/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 85: 1-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.85.70829</p>
					<p>Authors: Min Qiao, Hua Zheng, Ji-Shu Guo, Rafael F. Castañeda-Ruiz, Jian-Ping Xu, Jie Peng, Ke-Qin Zhang, Ze-Fen Yu</p>
					<p>Abstract: The family Microthyriaceae is represented by relatively few mycelial cultures and DNA sequences; as a result, the taxonomy and classification of this group of organisms remain poorly understood. During the investigation of the diversity of aquatic hyphomycetes from southern China, several isolates were collected. These isolates were cultured and sequenced and a BLAST search of its LSU sequences against data in GenBank revealed that the closest related taxa are in the genus Microthyrium. Phylogenetic analyses, based on the combined sequence data from the internal transcribed spacers (ITS) and the large subunit (LSU), revealed that these isolates represent eight new taxa in Microthyriaceae, including two new genera, Antidactylaria gen. nov. and Isthmomyces gen. nov. and six new species, Antidactylaria minifimbriata sp. nov., Isthmomyces oxysporus sp. nov., I. dissimilis sp. nov., I. macrosporus sp. nov., Triscelophorus anisopterioideus sp. nov. and T. sinensis sp. nov. These new taxa are described, illustrated for their morphologies and compared with similar taxa. In addition, two new combinations are proposed in this family.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70829/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70829/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70829/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 15:45:41 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Diaporthe (Diaporthaceae, Diaporthales) associated with tree cankers in ﻿the Netherlands</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73107/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 85: 31-56</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.85.73107</p>
					<p>Authors: Ning Jiang, Hermann Voglmayr, Chun-Gen Piao, Yong Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diaporthe (Diaporthaceae, Diaporthales) is a common fungal genus inhabiting plant tissues as endophytes, pathogens and saprobes. Some species are reported from tree branches associated with canker diseases. In the present study, Diaporthe samples were collected from Alnus glutinosa, Fraxinus excelsior and Quercus robur in Utrecht, the Netherlands. They were identified to species based on a polyphasic approach including morphology, pure culture characters, and phylogenetic analyses of a combined matrix of partial ITS, cal, his3, tef1 and tub2 gene regions. As a result, four species (viz. ﻿﻿Diaporthe pseudoalnea sp. nov. from Alnus glutinosa, Diaporthe silvicola sp. nov. from Fraxinus excelsior, D. foeniculacea and D. rudis from Quercus robur) were revealed from tree branches in the Netherlands. Diaporthe pseudoalnea differs from D. eres (syn. D. alnea) by its longer conidiophores. Diaporthe silvicola is distinguished from D. fraxinicola and D. fraxini-angustifoliae by larger alpha conidia.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73107/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73107/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73107/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:00:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and phylogenetic analyses reveal a new genus and two new species of Tubakiaceae from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73940/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 185-201</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.73940</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhaoxue Zhang, Taichang Mu, Shubin Liu, Rongyu Liu, Xiuguo Zhang, Jiwen Xia</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of Tubakiaceae have often been reported as plant pathogens or endophytes, commonly isolated from a wide range of plant hosts. The isolated fungi were studied through a complete examination, based on multilocus phylogenies from combined datasets of ITS/LSU/rpb2 and ITS/tef1/tub2, in conjunction with morphological characteristics. Five strains isolated from Lithocarpus fohaiensis and Quercus palustris in China represented a new genus of Tubakiaceae, Obovoideisporodochium and three species, viz. Obovoideisporodochium lithocarpi sp. nov., Tubakia lushanensis sp. nov. and T. dryinoides.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73940/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73940/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/73940/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:01:20 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Phylogenetic analyses and morphological characters reveal two new species of Ganoderma from Yunnan province, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69449/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 141-162</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.69449</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun He, Zong-Long Luo, Song-Ming Tang, Yong-Jun Li, Shu-Hong Li, Hong-Yan Su</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ganoderma dianzhongense sp. nov. and G. esculentum sp. nov. are proposed as two new species based on both phenotypic and genotypic evidences. Ganoderma dianzhongense is characterized by the stipitate basidiomata, laccate and oxblood red pileus, gray white pore surface, duplex context and broadly ellipsoid basidiospores (9.0–12.5 × 6.5–9.0 μm) with coarse interwall pillars. Ganoderma esculentum is characterized by its basidiomata with slender stipe, white pore surface, homogeneous pileus context, and slightly truncate, narrow basidiospores (8.0–12.5 × 5.0–8.0 µm). Phylogenetic analyses were carried out based on the internal transcribed spacer (ITS), translation elongation factor 1-α (TEF1-α) and the second subunit of RNA polymerase II (RPB2) sequence data. The illustrations and descriptions for the new taxa are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69449/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69449/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69449/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 17:33:20 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new lecanoroid lichen species from the forested wetlands of South Korea, with a key for Korean Protoparmeliopsis species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70798/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 163-183</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.70798</p>
					<p>Authors: Beeyoung Gun Lee, Jae-Seoun Hur</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lecanora parasymmicta Lee &amp; Hur and Protoparmeliopsis crystalliniformis Lee &amp; Hur are described as new lichen species to science from the forested wetlands in southern South Korea. Molecular analyses employing internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and mitochondrial small subunit (mtSSU) sequences strongly support the two lecanoroid species to be distinct in their genera. Lecanora parasymmicta is included in the Lecanora symmicta group. It is morphologically distinguished from Lecanora symmicta (Ach.) Ach., its most similar species, by areolate-rimose thallus, blackish hypothallus, larger apothecia, absence of thalline excipulum from the beginning, narrower paraphyses, larger ascospores, smaller pycnoconidia, and the presence of placodiolic acid. The second new species Protoparmeliopsis crystalliniformis is included in a clade with Protoparmeliopsis bipruinosa (Fink) S.Y. Kondr. and P. nashii (B.D. Ryan) S.Y. Kondr., differs from Protoparmeliopsis ertzii Bungartz &amp; Elix, its most morphologically similar species, by whitish thallus, flat to concave and paler disc, longer ascospores, thallus K+ yellow reaction, presence of atranorin and rhizocarpic acid, and the substrate preference to sandstone or basalt. A key is provided to assist in the identification of Protoparmeliopsis species in Korea.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70798/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70798/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70798/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 11:25:28 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two novel species and two new records of Distoseptispora from freshwater habitats in China and Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71905/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 79-101</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.71905</p>
					<p>Authors: Hong-Wei Shen, Dan-Feng Bao, Kevin D. Hyde, Hong-Yan Su, Darbhe J. Bhat, Zong-Long Luo</p>
					<p>Abstract: During investigations into freshwater fungi from the Great Mekong Subregion, four Distoseptispora taxa were collected from China and Thailand. Based on morphological characteristics, and phylogenetic analyses of combined LSU, ITS, SSU, TEF1-α, and RPB2 sequence data, two new species Distoseptispora bangkokensis and D. lancangjiangensis are introduced, and two known species D. clematidis and D. thysanolaenae were first reported in freshwater habitat. Illustrations and descriptions of these taxa are provided, along with comparisons with extant taxa in the genus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71905/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71905/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71905/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 19:49:36 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new Russula species in sect. Ingratae (Russulales, Basidiomycota) from southern China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68750/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 103-139</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.68750</p>
					<p>Authors: Guo-Jie Li, Shou-Mian Li, Bart Buyck, Shi-Yi Zhao, Xue-Jiao Xie, Lu-Yao Shi, Chun-Ying Deng, Qing-Feng Meng, Qi-Biao Sun, Jun-Qing Yan, Jing Wang, Ming Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Russulasection Ingratae, found in Guizhou and Jiangsu Provinces, southern China, are proposed: R. straminella, R. subpectinatoides and R. succinea. Photographs, line drawings and detailed morphological descriptions for these species are provided with comparisons against closely-related taxa. Phylogenetic analysis of the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) region supported the recognition of these specimens as new species. Additionally, R. indocatillus is reported for the first time from China and morphological and phylogenetic data are provided for the Chinese specimens.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68750/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68750/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68750/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 12:56:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Novel Mucor species (Mucoromycetes, Mucoraceae) from northern Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71530/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 57-78</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.71530</p>
					<p>Authors: Vedprakash G. Hurdeal, Eleni Gentekaki, Kevin D. Hyde, Thuong T. T. Nguyen, Hyang Burm Lee</p>
					<p>Abstract: Mucor species are common fast-growing fungi found in soil. Two new species of Mucor and one new geographical record of M. nederlandicus were collected from northern Thailand and are described in this study. Evidence from morphophysiological data and phylogenetic analysis supports the introduction of the new taxa. Phylogenetic analysis based on the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and large subunit of the nuclear ribosomal RNA (LSU) data showed that the new isolates cluster distinctly from other Mucor species with high or maximum bootstrap support. Mucor aseptatophorus is characterized by aseptate sporangiophores, globose columella, resistant and deliquescent sporangia, has sympodial, and monopodial branches and shows growth at 37 °C. It also differs from M. irregularis in having smaller sporangiospores, and larger sporangia. Mucor chiangraiensis has subglobose or slightly elongated globose columella, produces hyaline sporangiospores, and resistant and deliquescent sporangia. Furthermore, this species has wider sporangiophore, smaller sporangia and lower growth than M. nederlandicus. A detailed description of the species and illustrations are provided for the novel species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71530/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71530/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71530/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 1 Nov 2021 09:31:53 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new calcicolous caloplacoid lichens from South Korea, with a taxonomic key to the species of Huriella and Squamulea</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71227/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 35-55</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.71227</p>
					<p>Authors: Beeyoung Gun Lee, Jae-Seoun Hur</p>
					<p>Abstract: Pyrenodesmia rugosa Lee &amp; Hur and Huriella aeruginosa Lee &amp; Hur are described as new lichen-forming fungi from a calcareous mountain of South Korea. Pyrenodesmia rugosa is distinguishable from Pyrenodesmia micromontana (Frolov, Wilk &amp; Vondrák) Hafellner &amp; Türk, the most similar species, by thicker thallus, rugose areoles, larger apothecia, shorter hymenium, shorter hypothecium and narrower tip cells of paraphyses. Huriella aeruginosa, the second new species, differs from ‘Squamulea’ chelonia Bungartz &amp; Søchting by dark greenish-grey to grey thallus without pruina, gold to yellow-brown epihymenium, larger ascospores and thallus K– and KC– reaction. Molecular analyses employing internal transcribed spacer (ITS), mitochondrial small subunit (mtSSU) and nuclear large subunit ribosomal RNA (LSU) sequences strongly support the two caloplacoid species to be distinct in their genera. A surrogate key is provided to assist in the identification of all 20 taxa in Huriella and Squamulea.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71227/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71227/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71227/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 1 Nov 2021 09:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Characterization of Diaporthe species on Camellia oleifera in Hunan Province, with descriptions of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71701/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 15-33</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.71701</p>
					<p>Authors: Qin Yang, Jie Tang, Guo Y. Zhou</p>
					<p>Abstract: Tea-oil tree (Camellia oleifera Abel.) is an important edible oil woody plant with a planting area over 3,800,000 hectares in southern China. Species of Diaporthe inhabit a wide range of plant hosts as plant pathogens, endophytes and saprobes. At present, relatively little is known about the taxonomy and genetic diversity of Diaporthe on C. oleifera. Here, we conducted an extensive field survey in Hunan Province in China to identify and characterise Diaporthe species associated with tea-oil leaf spots. As a result, eleven isolates of Diaporthe were obtained from symptomatic C. oleifera leaves. These isolates were studied by applying a polyphasic approach including morphological and phylogenetic analyses of partial ITS, cal, his3, tef1 and tub2 gene regions. Two new Diaporthe species (D. camelliae-oleiferae and D. hunanensis) were proposed and described herein, and C. oleifera was revealed to be new host records of D. hubeiensis and D. sojae. This study indicated there is a potential of more undiscovered Diaporthe species from C. oleifera in China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71701/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71701/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71701/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:45:37 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Lack of knowledge on ecological determinants and cryptic lifestyles hinder our understanding of Terfezia diversity</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71372/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 84: 1-14</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.84.71372</p>
					<p>Authors: Celeste Santos-Silva, Rogério Louro, Bruno Natário, Tânia Nobre</p>
					<p>Abstract: Developing below the soil surface desert, truffles are hard to find. Within Terfezia genus, at least 18 species are described and many are endemic to the Mediterranean basin. Ecological and geographic information are key factors for species diagnosis, and so far Terfezia species are believed to be linked to either acidic or basic soils or to specific plant hosts. Thus, we have looked at Terfezia diversity within a relatively homogeneous geographical area in Portugal that is suitable for these species and that covered different soils and different dominant host species. We analyzed the observed intraspecific variability within the context of species ecological preferences (e. g. edaphic and putative host). One of our major findings was the discovery of T. grisea in acid soils in association with Tuberaria guttata, a puzzling information since, until now, this species was only found in alkaline soils. We also report on the linkage of different Terfezia lineages within species and ecologic parameters such as soil texture, soil pH and plant host. Additionally, by placing the collected specimens on the most recent genus phylogeny based on the ITS region, we also updated the number of known Terfezia species occurring in Portugal from three to ten. Terfezia dunensis is here reported for the first time for Portugal. Overall, our results show that the exploration of undersampled sites reveals itself as a good strategy to disclose unknown aspects of desert truffle diversity and ecology. These aspects are of prime importance when considering the economic value of the desert truffles for rural populations in the Mediterranean basin.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71372/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71372/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71372/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:44:56 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Ophiostomatoid species associated with pine trees (Pinus spp.) infested by Cryphalus piceae from eastern China, including five new species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70925/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 181-208</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.70925</p>
					<p>Authors: Runlei Chang, Xiuyu Zhang, Hongli Si, Guoyan Zhao, Xiaowen Yuan, Tengteng Liu, Tanay Bose, Meixue Dai</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cryphalus piceae attacks various economically important conifers. Similar to other bark beetles, Cr. piceae plays a role as a vector for an assortment of fungi and nematodes. Previously, several ophiostomatoid fungi were isolated from Cr. piceae in Poland and Japan. In the present study, we explored the diversity of ophiostomatoid fungi associated with Cr. piceae infesting pines in the Shandong Province of China. We isolated ophiostomatoid fungi from both galleries and beetles collected from our study sites. These fungal isolates were identified using both molecular and morphological data. In this study, we recovered 175 isolates of ophiostomatoid fungi representing seven species. Ophiostoma ips was the most frequently isolated species. Molecular and morphological data indicated that five ophiostomatoid fungal species recovered were previously undescribed. Thus, we proposed these five novel species as Ceratocystiopsis yantaiensis, C. weihaiensis, Graphilbum translucens, Gr. niveum, and Sporothrix villosa. These new ophiostomatoid fungi add to the increasing number of fungi known from China, and this evidence suggests that numerous novel taxa are awaiting discovery in other forests of China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70925/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70925/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/70925/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 09:25:20 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphology and molecular study of three new Cordycipitoid fungi and its related species collected from Jilin Province, northeast China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/72325/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 161-180</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.72325</p>
					<p>Authors: Jia-Jun Hu, Gui-Ping Zhao, Yong-Lan Tuo, Dan Dai, Di-Zhe Guo, Gu Rao, Zheng-Xiang Qi, Zhen-Hao Zhang, Yu Li, Bo Zhang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cordyceps species are notable medicinal fungi in China, which are pathogenic on insects and exhibit high biodiversity in tropical and subtropical regions. Recently, three new Cordyceps species, Cordyceps changchunensis and Cordyceps jingyuetanensis growing on pupae of Lepidoptera and Cordyceps changbaiensis growing on larvae of Lepidoptera, were found in Jilin Province, China and are described, based on morphological and ecological characteristics. These three new species are similar to the Cordyceps militaris group, but are distinctly distinguishable from the known species. Cordyceps changchunensis, characterised by its small and light yellow to orange stromata which is occasionally forked, covered with white mycelium at the base of stipe, globose to ovoid perithecia, is macroscopically similar to Cordyceps militaris. Cordyceps changbaiensis is clearly discriminated from other Cordyceps species by its white to orange and branched stromata, clavate to cylindrical fertile apical portion, immersed and globose to ovoid perithecia. Moreover, unbranched, clavate and orange to light red stromata, almond-shaped to ovoid and immersed perithecia separate Cordyceps jingyuetanensis from other Cordyceps species. nrITS, nrLSU and EF-1α sequences were undertaken and phylogenetic trees, based on Maximum Likelihood and Bayesian Inference analysis showed that the three new species clustered with Cordyceps militaris, but formed individual clades, as well as confirmed the results of our morphological study.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/72325/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/72325/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/72325/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 17:57:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and phylogenetic evidence for recognition of two new species of Hyphoderma (Basidiomycota) from southern China, with a key to all Chinese Hyphoderma</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69909/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 145-160</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.69909</p>
					<p>Authors: Qian-Xin Guan, Yi-Fei Li, Chang-Lin Zhao</p>
					<p>Abstract: Wood-inhabiting fungi play crucial roles as decomposers in forest ecosystems and, in this study, two new wood-inhabiting corticioid fungi, Hyphoderma puerense and H. tenuissimum spp. nov., are proposed, based on a combination of morphological features and molecular evidence. Hyphoderma puerense is characterised by effused basidiomata with smooth to floccose hymenial surface, a monomitic hyphal system with clamped generative hyphae and ellipsoid basidiospores. Hyphoderma tenuissimum is characterised by resupinate basidiomata with tuberculate to minutely-grandinioid hymenial surface, septate cystidia and cylindrical to allantoid basidiospores. Sequences of ITS and nLSU rRNA markers of the studied samples were generated and phylogenetic analyses were performed with Maximum Likelihood, maximum parsimony and Bayesian Inference methods. These analyses showed that the two new species clustered into Hyphoderma, in which H. puerense grouped with H. moniliforme and H. tenuissimum formed a singleton lineage. In addition, an identification key to Chinese Hyphoderma is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69909/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69909/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69909/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 10:50:49 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Rhytidhysteron (Dothideomycetes, Ascomycota) from Mexico</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68582/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 123-144</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.68582</p>
					<p>Authors: Aurora Cobos-Villagrán, Ricardo Valenzuela, César Hernández-Rodríguez, Rosa Paulina Calvillo-Medina, Lourdes Villa-Tanaca, Luz Elena Mateo-Cid, Abigail Pérez-Valdespino, César Ramiro Martínez-González, Tania Raymundo</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Rhytidhysteron is characterised by forming navicular to apothecial hysterothecia, exposing the green, yellow, orange, red, vinaceous or black colours of the hymenium which generally releases pigments in the presence of KOH. The exciple is smooth or striated, the asci bitunicate and ascospores have 1–5 transverse septa. To date, twenty-six Rhytidhysteron species have been described from the Tropics. The present study aims to describe three new species in the Neotropics of Mexico based on molecular methods and morphological features. Illustrations and a taxonomic key are provided for all known species of this genus. Rhytidhysteron cozumelense from the Isla Cozumel Biosphere Reserve, R. esperanzae from the Sierra Juárez, Oaxaca and R. mesophilum from the Sierra Madre Oriental, Hidalgo are described as new species. With the present study, the number of species of Rhytidhysteron known from Mexico is now increased to eight.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68582/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68582/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68582/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Review Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 10:56:44 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Phylogenetic and morphological analyses of Coniochaeta isolates recovered from Inner Mongolia and Yunnan revealed three new endolichenic fungal species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71140/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 105-121</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.71140</p>
					<p>Authors: Hong-Li Si, Yue-Min Su, Xiao-Xiao Zheng, Meng-Yao Ding, Tanay Bose, Run-Lei Chang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lichens are the result of a symbiotic interaction between fungi (mycobionts) and algae (phycobionts). Aside from mycobionts, lichen thalli can also contain non-lichenised fungal species, such as lichenicolous and endolichenic fungi. For this study, three surveys were conducted in China’s Yunnan Province and Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region between 2017 and 2020. Several samples of four lichen species were collected during these surveys: Candelaria fibrosa, Flavoparmelia caperata, Flavopunctelia flaventior and Ramalina sinensis. Six isolates of Coniochaeta were recovered from these four lichen species. The phylogenetic and morphological analyses revealed that two of these isolates were previously identified species, Coniochaeta velutinosa and C. acaciae. Those remaining were from potentially unknown species. We used molecular and morphological data to describe these previously-unknown species as Coniochaeta fibrosae sp. nov., C. mongoliae sp. nov. and C. sinensis sp. nov. The findings of this study significantly improve our understanding of the variety and habitat preferences of Coniochaeta in China and globally.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71140/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71140/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71140/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Sep 2021 16:09:43 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new psathyrelloid species of Coprinopsis (Agaricales, Psathyrellaceae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71405/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 85-103</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.71405</p>
					<p>Authors: Gu Rao, Dan Dai, Hui-Nan Zhao, Yi Liang, Yu Li, Bo Zhang</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, Coprinopsis jilinensis and Coprinopsis pusilla were introduced, based on their morphological characteristics, the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and large subunit ribosomal (LSU) region sequences of nrDNA. These new psathyrelloid species were found in Jilin Province, China. Coprinopsis jilinensis has brown pileus, utriform pleurocystidia, brown, smooth, dextrinoid basidiospores and tiny pore. It mainly grows on humus. Coprinopsis pusilla has small basidiomata, greyish-white pileus, thick and distinct veil at edges, subcolourless and verrucose basidiospores. It is poreless and it grows on the decaying wood of broad-leaved trees. Both of them belong to the C. sect. Melanthinae. A supplementary description of C. sect. Melanthinae was given in combination with the newly-discovered taxa and an identification key to the fourteen psathyrelloid species of Coprinopsis is provided. Coprinopsis sect. Canocipes and C. sect. Quartoconatae were evaluated and the phylogenetic position of the psathyrelloid species of Coprinopsis was discussed. Psathyrella subagraria, as a confusing species, was also discussed in this study.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71405/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71405/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71405/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Sep 2021 12:07:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of Yamadazyma from rotting wood in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71156/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 69-84</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.71156</p>
					<p>Authors: Wan-Li Gao, Ying Li, Chun-Yue Chai, Zhen-Li Yan, Feng-Li Hui</p>
					<p>Abstract: Yamadazyma is one of the largest genera in the family Debaryomycetaceae (Saccharomycetales, Saccharomycetes) with species mainly found in rotting wood, insects and their resulting frass, but also recovered from flowers, leaves, fruits, tree bark, mushrooms, sea water, minerals, and the atmosphere. In the present study, several strains obtained from rotting wood in Henan and Yunnan Provinces of China were isolated. Based on morphology and a molecular phylogeny of the rDNA internal transcribed spacer region (ITS) and the D1/D2 domain of the large subunit (LSU) rDNA, these strains were identified as three new species: Yamadazyma luoyangensis, Y. ovata and Y. paraaseri; and three previously described species, Y. insectorum, Y. akitaensis, and Y. olivae. The three new species are illustrated and their morphology and phylogenetic relationships with other Yamadazyma species are discussed. Our results indicate a high undiscovered diversity of Yamadazyma spp. inhabiting rotting wood in China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71156/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71156/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/71156/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 09:43:53 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A taxonomic study of Nemania from China, with six new species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69906/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 39-67</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.69906</p>
					<p>Authors: Yin Hui Pi, Si Han Long, You Peng Wu, Li Li Liu, Yan Lin, Qing De Long, Ji Chuan Kang, Ying Qian Kang, Chu Rui Chang, Xiang Chun Shen, Nalin N. Wijayawardene, Xu Zhang, Qi Rui Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: During an investigation of Xylariaceae from 2019 to 2020, isolates representing eight Nemania (Xylariacese) species were collected from Yunnan, Guizhou and Hainan Provinces in China. Morphological and multi-gene phylogenetic analyses, based on combined ITS, α-actin, rpb2 and β-tubulin sequences, confirmed that six of them are new to science, viz. Nemania camelliae, N. changningensis, N. cyclobalanopsina, N. feicuiensis, N. lishuicola and N. rubi; one is a new record (N. caries) for China and one is a known species (N. diffusa). Morphological descriptions and illustrations of all species are detailed. In addition, the characteristics of Nemania are summarised and prevailing contradictions in generic concepts are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69906/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69906/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69906/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 12:02:54 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New contributions to Diatrypaceae from karst areas in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68926/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 83: 1-37</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.83.68926</p>
					<p>Authors: Sihan Long, Lili Liu, Yinhui Pi, Youpeng Wu, Yan Lin, Xu Zhang, Qingde Long, Yingqian Kang, Jichuan Kang, Nalin N. Wijayawardene, Feng Wang, Xiangchun Shen, Qirui Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, fungal specimens of the family Diatrypaceae were collected from karst areas in Guizhou, Hainan and Yunnan Provinces, China. Morpho-molecular analyses confirmed that these new collections comprise a new genus Pseudodiatrype, three new species (Diatrype lancangensis, Diatrypella pseudooregonensis and Eutypa cerasi), a new combination (Diatrypella oregonensis), two new records (Allodiatrype thailandica and Diatrypella vulgaris) from China and two other known species (Neoeutypella baoshanensis and Paraeutypella citricola). The new taxa are introduced, based on multi-gene phylogenetic analyses (ITS, β-tubulin), as well as morphological analyses. The new genus Pseudodiatrype is characterised by its wart-like stromata with 5–20 ascomata immersed in one stroma and the endostroma composed of thin black outer and inner layers of large white cells with thin, powdery, yellowish cells. These characteristics separate this genus from two similar genera Allodiatrype and Diatrype. Based on morphological as well as phylogenetic analyses, Diatrype lancangensis is introduced as a new species of Diatrype. The stromata of Diatrype lancangensis are similar to those of D. subundulata and D. undulate, but the ascospores are larger. Based on phylogenetic analyses, Diatrype oregonensis is transferred to the genus Diatrypella as Diatrypella oregonensis while Diatrypella pseudooregonensis is introduced as a new species of Diatrypella with 8 spores in an ascus. In addition, multi-gene phylogenetic analyses show that Eutypa cerasi is closely related to E. lata, but the ascomata and asci of Eutypa cerasi are smaller. The polyphyletic nature of some genera of Diatrypaceae has led to confusion in the classification of the family, thus we discuss whether the number of ascospores per asci can still be used as a basis for classification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68926/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68926/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68926/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:21:58 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Two new brown rot polypores from tropical China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68299/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 173-197</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.68299</p>
					<p>Authors: Meng Zhou, Chao-Ge Wang, Ying-Da Wu, Shun Liu, Yuan Yuan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Brown-rot fungi are types of fungi that selectively degrade cellulose and hemicellulose from wood and are perhaps the most important agents involved in the degradation of wood products and dead wood in forest ecosystem. Two new brown-rot species, collected from southern China, are nested within the clades of Fomitopsis sensu stricto and Oligoporus sensu stricto, respectively. Their positions are strongly supported in the Maximum Likelihood phylogenetic tree of the concatenated the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) regions, the large subunit of nuclear ribosomal RNA gene (nLSU), the small subunit of nuclear ribosomal RNA gene (nuSSU), the small subunit of mitochondrial rRNA gene (mtSSU), the largest subunit of RNA polymerase II (RPB1), the second largest subunit of RNA polymerase II (RPB2) and the translation elongation factor 1-α gene (TEF1) sequences. Fomitopsis bambusae, only found on bamboo, is characterised by its resupinate to effused-reflexed or pileate basidiocarps, small pores (6–9 per mm), the absence of cystidia, short cylindrical to oblong-ellipsoid basidiospores measuring 4.2–6.1 × 2–2.3 μm. Oligoporus podocarpi is characterised by white to pale cream pore surface, round or sometimes angular pores (5–6 per mm), broadly ellipsoid to reniform basidiospores measuring 3.8–4.2 × 2–2.3 μm and growing on Podocarpus. Illustrated descriptions of these two novel species, Fomitopsis bambusae and Oligoporus podocarpi, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68299/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68299/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68299/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 17:57:41 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Greetings from belowground: two new species of truffles in the genus Pachyphlodes (Pezizaceae, Pezizales) from México</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67685/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 159-171</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.67685</p>
					<p>Authors: Carolina Piña Páez, Rosanne A. Healy, Gonzalo Guevara, Roberto Garibay Orijel, Michael A. Castellano, Efrén Cázares, James M. Trappe</p>
					<p>Abstract: Pachyphlodes is a lineage of ectomycorrhizal, hypogeous, sequestrate ascomycete fungi native to temperate and subtropical forests in the Northern Hemisphere. Pachyphlodes species form ectomycorrhizae mainly with Fagales hosts. Here we describe two new species of Pachyphlodes, P. brunnea, and P. coalescens, based on morphological and phylogenetic analysis. Pachyphlodes brunnea is distributed in the states of Tamaulipas and Nuevo León in northern México, occurring with Quercus and Juglans species. It is characterized by its dark brown peridium, white gleba, and spores with capitate columns. Pachyphlodes coalescens is distributed in the states of Michoacán and Tlaxcala in central and southwestern México co-occurring with Quercus and is distinguished by its reddish-brown peridium, light yellow gleba, and spore ornamentation. Both species, along with P. marronina, constitute the Marronina clade. This clade contains North American species characterized by a brown peridium and spores ornamented with capitate spines to coalesced spine tips that form a partial perispore.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67685/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67685/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67685/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:51:57 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and phylogenetic evidence for two new species of Russula subg. Heterophyllidia from Guangdong Province of China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64913/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 139-157</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.64913</p>
					<p>Authors: Bin Chen, Jie Song, Yanliu Chen, Jinhua Zhang, Junfeng Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Russula subg. Heterophyllidia from Guangdong Province of China were described and illustrated based on morphological characters, and their identity supported by molecular phylogeny. R. luofuensis is morphologically characterized by a grayish yellow to brownish orange pileus center with a purplish gray to grayish magenta margin, a surface that is cracked and broken into small golden-brown patches, subglobose to broadly ellipsoid basidiospores with warts fused in short or long chains and a suprapellis composed of hyphal extremities with inflated, ellipsoid or globose cells and attenuated terminal cell. R. subbubalina is distinguished by the blanched almond to dark salmon pileus that is cracked with age, subglobose to broadly ellipsoid basidiospores with wart fused in short or long chains and frequently connected by line connections, a suprapellis with hyphal ends composed of inflated or ellipsoid cells and attenuated terminal cell, and pileocystidia that are mainly clavate and sometimes with round or ellipsoid appendage. The phylogenetic analyses based on ITS-nrLSU-mtSSU-TEF1 dataset were performed using maximum likelihood and Bayesian analysis. In terms of morphological features and molecular data, the former species belongs to subsect. Virescentinae, whereas the latter comes under subsect. Heterophyllinae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64913/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64913/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64913/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 18:28:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Refining the picture: new records to the lichen biota of Italy</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69027/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 97-137</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.69027</p>
					<p>Authors: Juri Nascimbene, Gabriele Gheza, Josef Hafellner, Helmut Mayrhofer, Lucia Muggia, Walter Obermayer, Göran Thor, Pier Luigi Nimis</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on the analysis of both historical and recent collections, this paper reports an annotated list of taxa which are new to the lichen biota of Italy or of its administrative regions. Specimens were identified using a dissecting and a compound microscope; routine chemical spot tests and standardized thin-layer chromatography (TLC or HPTLC). The list includes 225 records of 153 taxa. Twenty taxa are new to Italy, the others are new to one or more administrative regions, with 15 second records and 5 third records for Italy. Some of the species belong to recently-described taxa, others are poorly known, sterile or ephemeral lichens which were largely overlooked in Italy. Several species are actually rare, either because of the rarity of their habitats (e.g. old-growth forests), or because in Italy they are at the margins of their bioclimatic distribution. The picture of the lichen biota of Italy has now new pixels, but its grain is still coarse. Further analysis of historical collections, increased efforts in the exploration of some areas, and the taxonomic revision of critical groups are still necessary to provide more complete distributional data for new biogeographic hypotheses, taxonomic and ecological research, and biodiversity conservation.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69027/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69027/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/69027/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 18:28:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Novel saprobic Hermatomyces species (Hermatomycetaceae, Pleosporales) from China (Yunnan Province) and Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67973/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 57-79</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.67973</p>
					<p>Authors: Guang-Cong Ren, Dhanushka N. Wanasinghe, Jutamart Monkai, Peter E. Mortimer, Kevin D. Hyde, Jian-Chu Xu, Aimin Pang, Heng Gui</p>
					<p>Abstract: During our survey of the diversity of woody litter fungi in China and Thailand, three Hermatomyces species were collected from dead woody twigs of Dipterocarpus sp. (Dipterocarpaceae) and Ehretia acuminata (Boraginaceae). Both morphology and multigene analyses revealed two taxa as new species (Hermatomyces turbinatus and H. jinghaensis) and the remaining collections as new records of H. sphaericus. Hermatomyces turbinatus is characterized by 1) dimorphic conidia, having circular to oval lenticular conidia and 2) turbinate conidia consisting of two columns with two septa composed of 2–3 cells in each column. Hermatomyces jinghaensis is characterized by dimorphic conidia, having circular to oval lenticular conidia and clavate or subcylindrical to cylindrical conidia and consisting of one or two columns with 6–8 cells in each column. Phylogenetic analyses of combined LSU, ITS, tub2, tef1-α and rpb2 sequence data supports the placement of these new taxa within Hermatomycetaceae with high statistical support.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67973/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67973/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67973/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Aug 2021 15:36:43 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Hirsutella (Ophiocordycipitaceae, Sordariomycetes) that are parasitic on lepidopteran insects from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66927/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 81-96</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.66927</p>
					<p>Authors: Jiaojiao Qu, Xiao Zou, Wei Cao, Zhongshun Xu, Zongqi Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Hirsutella are globally distributed entomopathogenic fungi that offer important economic applications in biological control and biomedicine. Hirsutella was suppressed in favour of Ophiocordyceps affected by the ending of dual nomenclature for pleomorphic fungi in 2011. Currently, Hirsutella has been resurrected as a genus under Ophiocordycipitaceae. In this study, we introduce two new species of Hirsutella, based on morphological and phylogenetic analyses. Hirsutella flava and H. kuankuoshuiensis are pathogenic on different species of larval Lepidoptera in China. Hirsutella flava primarily differs from related species by its awl-shaped base; long and narrow neck, 24–40.8 × 2.2–2.5 μm; long and narrow cymbiform or fusoid conidia, 6.5–10 × 2.1–4.3 μm. Hirsutella kuankuoshuiensis has two types of phialides and distinctive 9.9–12.6 × 2.7–4.5 μm, clavate or botuliform conidia. The distinctions amongst the new species and phylogenetic relationships with other Hirsutella species are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66927/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66927/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66927/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Aug 2021 11:24:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Four new species in the Tremella fibulifera complex (Tremellales, Basidiomycota)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63241/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 33-56</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.63241</p>
					<p>Authors: Long-Fei Fan, Renato Lúcio Mendes Alvarenga, Tatiana Baptista Gibertoni, Fang Wu, Yu-Cheng Dai</p>
					<p>Abstract: Samples of species close to Tremella fibulifera from China and Brazil are studied, and T. fibulifera is confirmed as a species complex including nine species. Five known species (T. cheejenii, T. fibulifera s.s., T. “neofibulifera”, T. lloydiae-candidae and T. olens) and four new species (T. australe, T. guangxiensis, T. latispora and T. subfibulifera) in the complex are recognized based on morphological characteristics, molecular evidence, and geographic distribution. Sequences of eight species of the complex were included in the phylogenetic analyses because T. olens lacks molecular data. The phylogenetic analyses were performed by a combined sequence dataset of the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and the partial nuclear large subunit rDNA (nLSU), and a combined sequence dataset of the ITS, partial nLSU, the small subunit mitochondrial rRNA gene (mtSSU), the translation elongation factor 1-α (TEF1), the largest and second largest subunits of RNA polymerase II (RPB1 and RPB2). The eight species formed eight independent lineages with robust support in phylogenies based on both datasets. Illustrated description of the six species including Tremella fibulifera s.s., T. “neofibulifera” and four new species, and discussions with their related species, are provided. A table of the comparison of the important characteristics of nine species in the T. fibulifera complex and a key to the whitish species in Tremella s.s. are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63241/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63241/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63241/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 4 Aug 2021 15:09:13 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Six new species of Sporothrix from hardwood trees in Poland</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66603/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 82: 1-32</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.82.66603</p>
					<p>Authors: Agnieszka Ostafińska, Robert Jankowiak, Piotr Bilański, Halvor Solheim, Michael J. Wingfield</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sporothrix (Sordariales, Ascomycota) is a well-supported monophyletic lineage within the Ophiostomatales, species of which occur in a diverse range of habitats including on forest trees, in the soil, associated with bark beetles and mites as well as on the fruiting bodies of some Basidiomycota. Several species have also been reported as important human and animal pathogens. During surveys of insect- and wound-associated Ophiostomatales from hardwood trees in Poland, many isolates with affinity to Sporothrix were recovered. In the present study, six undescribed Sporothrix spp. collected during these surveys are characterized based on their morphological characteristics and multi-locus phylogenenetic inference. They are described as Sporothrix cavum, Sporothrix cracoviensis, S. cryptarchum, S. fraxini, S. resoviensis, and S. undulata. Two of the Sporothrix spp. reside in the S. gossypina-complex, while one forms part of the S. stenoceras-complex. One Sporothrix sp. is a member of lineage F, and two other species grouped outside any of the currently defined species complexes. All the newly described species were recovered from hardwood habitats in association with sub-cortical insects, wounds or woodpecker cavities. These species were morphologically similar, with predominantly asexual states having hyaline or lightly pigmented conidia, which produce holoblastically on denticulate conidiogenous cells. Five of the new taxa produce ascomata with necks terminating in long ostiolar hyphae and allantoid ascospores without sheaths. The results suggest that Sporothrix species are common members of the Ophiostomatales in hardwood ecosystems of Poland.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66603/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66603/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66603/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 4 Aug 2021 15:08:55 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new toxic yellow Inocybe species from China: morphological characteristics, phylogenetic analyses and toxin detection</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68485/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 185-204</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.68485</p>
					<p>Authors: Sai Nan Li, Fei Xu, Ming Jiang, Feng Liu, Fang Wu, Ping Zhang, Yu Guang Fan, Zuo Hong Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Some species of Inocybe s. str. caused neurotoxic poisoning after consumption around the world. However, there are a large number of species in this genus that have not been studied for their toxicity or toxin content. In this study, we report two new toxic yellow Inocybe s. str. species from China based on morphological characteristics, phylogenetic analyses and toxin detection. Among the two species, Inocybe squarrosolutea is reported as a newly recorded species of China. We also describe a new species, I. squarrosofulva, which is morphologically similar to I. squarrosolutea. The new species is characterized by its ochraceous squarrose pileus, distinctly annulate cortina on the stipe, nodulose basidiospores and thick-walled pleurocystidia. Muscarine in the fruitbodies was detected by UPLC–MS/MS, the content in I. squarrosolutea and I. squarrosofulva were 136.4 ± 25.4 to 1683.0 ± 313 mg/kg dry weight and 31.2 ± 5.8 to 101.8 ± 18.9 mg/kg dry weight, respectively.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68485/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68485/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/68485/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 16:11:38 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Cyanescent Gyroporus (Gyroporaceae, Boletales) from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65660/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 165-183</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.65660</p>
					<p>Authors: Cong Huang, Ming Zhang, Xing-Liang Wu, Gang Wu, Jian-Ping Xu, Zhu L. Yang, Yan-Chun Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Gyroporus species with cyanescent oxidation reactions were investigated, based on morphology and phylogenetic analysis of DNA sequences from the nuclear ribosomal large subunit (nrLSU), the nuclear ribosomal internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and the mitochondrial adenosine triphosphate ATP synthase subunit 6 (atp6). Three species, including two new species, namely G. alpinus and G. flavocyanescens and one previously-described species, namely G. brunneofloccosus, are revealed from China. Collections formerly reported from China as “G. cyanescens” are either G. alpinus or G. flavocyanescens. The new species are documented and illustrated in detail, while the concept of G. brunneofloccosus is refined with additional recently-collected materials. Additionally, the cyanescent species G. pseudomicrosporus, previously described from China, is shown to be a member of the genus Gyrodon, based on re-examination of the type specimen. A key to the cyanescent Gyroporus species from China is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65660/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65660/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65660/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 09:44:46 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Updated description of Atheniella (Mycenaceae, Agaricales), including three new species with brightly coloured pilei from Yunnan Province, southwest China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67773/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 139-164</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.67773</p>
					<p>Authors: Yupeng Ge, Zewei Liu, Hui Zeng, Xianhao Cheng, Qin Na</p>
					<p>Abstract: An updated description of the genus Atheniella, combining macro- and micromorphological characters that elaborate on the original generic characterisation, is presented. Atheniella is characterised by a brightly coloured pileus, all tissues inamyloid and pileipellis covered with simple to branched excrescences. Previously, nine Atheniella species were known globally, of which three species were accepted in China. Three newly-recognised species classified in the genus are here formally described from Yunnan Province: Atheniella flavida sp. nov., A. rutila sp. nov. and A. taoyao sp. nov. The new species are characterised by a yellow, orange, pink or red pileus, fusiform cheilocystidia and pleurocystidia, non-smooth pileipellis, stipitipellis smooth or with cylindrical ornamentation, caulocystidia fusiform or subglobose, if present and all tissues inamyloid. Morphological descriptions, photographs, line drawings and comparisons with closely-related taxa are presented for the new species. A phylogenetic analysis of sequence data for the rDNA internal transcribed spacer region and nuclear large ribosomal subunit (ITS + nLSU) supported that Atheniella is resolved as monophyletic and also supported the taxonomic recognition of the new species. A key to the 12 species of Atheniella is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67773/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67773/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67773/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 11:50:10 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Unravelling unexplored diversity of cercosporoid fungi (Mycosphaerellaceae, Mycosphaerellales, Ascomycota) in tropical Africa</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67850/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 69-138</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.67850</p>
					<p>Authors: Yalemwork Meswaet, Ralph Mangelsdorff, Nourou S. Yorou, Meike Piepenbring</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cercosporoid fungi (Mycosphaerellaceae, Mycosphaerellales, Ascomycota) are one of the largest and most diverse groups of hyphomycetes causing a wide range of diseases of economically important plants as well as of plants in the wild. Although more than 6000 species are known for this group, the documentation of this fungal group is far from complete. Especially in the tropics, the diversity of cercosporoid fungi is poorly known. The present study aims to identify and characterise cercosporoid fungi collected on host plants belonging to Fabaceae in Benin, West Africa. Information on their morphology, host species and DNA sequence data (18S rDNA, 28S rDNA, ITS and tef1) is provided. DNA sequence data were obtained by a simple and non-culture-based method for DNA isolation which has been applied for cercosporoid fungi for the first time in the context of the present study. Among the loci used for the phylogenetic analysis, tef1 provided the best resolution together with the multigene dataset. Species delimitation in many cases, however, was only possible by combining molecular sequence data with morphological characteristics. Based on forty specimens recently collected in Benin, 18 species are presented with morphological descriptions, illustrations and sequence data. Among these, six species in the genus Cercospora and two species in Pseudocercospora are proposed as species new to science. The newly described species are Cercospora (C.) beninensis on Crotalaria macrocalyx, C. parakouensis on Desmodium tortuosum, C. rhynchophora on Vigna unguiculata, C. vignae-subterraneae on Vigna subterranea, C. tentaculifera on Vigna unguiculata, C. zorniicola on Zornia glochidiata, Pseudocercospora sennicola on Senna occidentalis and Pseudocercospora tabei on Vigna unguiculata. Eight species of cercosporoid fungi are reported for Benin for the first time, three of them, namely C. cf. canscorina, C. cf. fagopyri and C. phaseoli-lunati are new for West Africa. The presence of two species of cercosporoid fungi on Fabaceae previously reported from Benin, namely Nothopassalora personata and Passalora arachidicola, is confirmed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67850/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67850/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67850/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:13:43 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Soil fungal communities of ectomycorrhizal dominated woodlands across West Africa</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66249/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 45-68</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.66249</p>
					<p>Authors: Peter Meidl, Brendan Furneaux, Kassim I. Tchan, Kerri Kluting, Martin Ryberg, Marie-Laure Guissou, Bakary Soro, Aïssata Traoré, Gbamon Konomou, Nourou S. Yorou, Anna Rosling</p>
					<p>Abstract: Forests and woodlands in the West African Guineo-Sudanian transition zone contain many tree species that form symbiotic interactions with ectomycorrhizal (ECM) fungi. These fungi facilitate plant growth by increasing nutrient and water uptake and include many fruiting body-forming fungi, including some edible mushrooms. Despite their importance for ecosystem functioning and anthropogenic use, diversity and distribution of ECM fungi is severely under-documented in West Africa. We conducted a broad regional sampling across five West African countries using soil eDNA to characterize the ECM as well as the total soil fungal community in gallery forests and savanna woodlands dominated by ECM host tree species. We subsequently sequenced the entire ITS region and much of the LSU region to infer a phylogeny for all detected soil fungal species. Utilizing a long read sequencing approach allows for higher taxonomic resolution by using the full ITS region, while the highly conserved LSU gene allows for a more accurate higher-level assignment of species hypotheses, including species without ITS-based taxonomy assignments. We detect no overall difference in species richness between gallery forests and woodlands. However, additional gallery forest plots and more samples per plot would have been needed to firmly conclude this pattern. Based on both abundance and richness, species from the families Russulaceae and Inocybaceae dominate the ECM fungal soil communities across both vegetation types. The community structure of both total soil fungi and ECM fungi was significantly influenced by vegetation types and showed strong correlation within plots. However, we found no significant difference in fungal community structure between samples collected adjacent to different host tree species within each plot. We conclude that within plots, the fungal community is structured more by the overall ECM host plant community than by the species of the individual host tree that each sample was collected from.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66249/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66249/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66249/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 14:03:41 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Phylogeny and taxonomy of Catenularia and similar fungi with catenate conidia</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67785/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 81: 1-44</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.81.67785</p>
					<p>Authors: Martina Réblová, Jana Nekvindová, Andrew N. Miller</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Catenularia (Chaetosphaeriaceae) was reviewed, and its relationships with morphologically similar fungi were evaluated using molecular and morphological data. Eleven species are accepted, four of which have been verified with molecular DNA data. The correct epithet ‘cupulifera’ is proposed for the type species C. cupulifera comb. nov. Four other combinations are proposed, namely C. catenulata comb. nov., C. elsikii comb. nov., C. minor comb. nov. and C. novae-zelandiae comb. nov. Catenularia is an uncommon fungus inhabiting mainly decaying bark, wood and bamboo culms of various hosts and shows a widespread geographical distribution. It is circumscribed for fungi with mononematous, macronematous, simple conidiophores with terminal monophialides, usually accompanied with capitate hyphae. The conidia are aseptate, brown, cuneiform to rounded-obconic with an angular outline, adhering in chains. The diagnostic values of taxonomic characteristics of capitate hyphae and conidia (i.e. colour, shape in transverse section, setulae and formation) at the generic level were evaluated. An account of morphology, taxonomy and phylogeny of species accepted in Catenularia is provided. Based on ribosomal DNA sequences, Chalarodes obpyramidata sp. nov., characterised by catenate, angular, hyaline conidia with apical setulae, is revealed as closely related to Catenularia. The new genus Fuscocatenula gen. nov. is proposed for catenularia-like fungi having pigmented conidia with protracted maturation and round outline, with two species accepted, F. submersa comb. nov. and F. variegata comb. nov. A new species Nawawia antennata sp. nov. is introduced and Nawawia is compared with morphologically similar taxa.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67785/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67785/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67785/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 08:43:53 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new rare species of Candolleomyces with pale spores from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67166/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 149-161</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.67166</p>
					<p>Authors: Tolgor Bau, Jun-Qing Yan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Most species of Candolleomyces have brown or dark brown spores. Although pale-spored members are rare in the genus        we frequently collected two such species from many Provinces during our investigations in subtropical China from 2016–2020. As revealed by morphological characterisation and multigene phylogenetic analyses (ITS LSU β-tub and tef-1α) these species        which we have named C. subcacao and C. subminutisporus        are unique and distinct from known taxa. In addition a new combination        C. cladii-marisci        is proposed on the basis of ITS sequence analysis of the type specimen. Detailed descriptions colour photos illustrations and a key to related species are presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67166/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67166/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67166/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 3 Jun 2021 13:43:51 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new Melanoleuca species (Agaricales, Basidiomycota) from north-eastern China, supported by morphological and molecular data</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64369/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 133-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.64369</p>
					<p>Authors: Ying Pei, Hong-Bo Guo, Tie-Zhi Liu, Wei-Qiang Qin, Di Zhao, Xiao-Jian Qi, Xiao-Dan Yu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new Melanoleuca species, M. chifengense, M. griseoflava and M. pallidorosea, were discovered in the northeast of China. Melanoleuca chifengense is morphologically characterised by its grey to yellowish-grey pileus, decurrent lamellae, grey to yellowish-brown stipe, yellowish-grey context, ellipsoid basidiospores with irregular warts and lack of hymenial cystidia. Melanoleuca griseoflava is mainly characterised by its greyish-brown pileus, adnexed to adnate lamellae, greyish-yellow context, fusiform cystidia and almost reticulate basidiospores. Melanoleuca pallidorosea is characterised by its pinkish-white pileus, white and decurrent lamellae, ellipsoid basidiospores with round and scattered warts and lack of hymenial cystidia. The phylogenetic relationship of the three species was determined by the analyses of the ITS region and the combined data matrix (ITS-nrLSU-RPB2), respectively. The results showed that the three species formed three independent lineages. Based on the combination of both morphological and molecular data, M. chifengense, M. griseoflava and M. pallidorosea were confirmed to be new species. The morphological similarities of the three new species is also discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64369/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64369/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64369/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 3 Jun 2021 13:10:56 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Corrigendum: Pykälä J, Kantelinen A, Myllys L (2020) Taxonomy of Verrucaria species characterised by large spores, perithecia leaving pits in the rock and a pale thin thallus in Finland. MycoKeys 72: 43–92. https://doi.org/10.3897/mycokeys.72.56223</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67870/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 163-164</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.67870</p>
					<p>Authors: Juha Pykälä, Annina Kantelinen, Leena Myllys</p>
					<p>Abstract: Corrigendum</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67870/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67870/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/67870/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Corrigenda</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 3 Jun 2021 12:01:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new genus and four new species in the /Psathyrella s.l. clade from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65123/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 115-131</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.65123</p>
					<p>Authors: Tolgor Bau, Jun-Qing Yan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on traditional morphological and phylogenetic analyses (ITS, LSU, tef-1α and β-tub) of psathyrelloid specimens collected from China, four new species are here described: Heteropsathyrella macrocystidia, Psathyrella amygdalinospora, P. piluliformoides, and P. truncatisporoides. H. macrocystidia forms a distinct lineage and groups together with Cystoagaricus, Kauffmania, and Typhrasa in the /Psathyrella s.l. clade, based on the Maximum Likelihood and Bayesian analyses. Thus, the monospecific genus Heteropsathyrella gen. nov. is introduced for the single species. Detailed descriptions, colour photos, and illustrations are presented in this paper.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65123/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65123/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65123/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:27:05 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species and a new record of yellow Cantharellus from tropical Quercus forests in eastern Mexico with the proposal of a new name for the replacement of Craterellus confluens</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61443/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 91-114</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.61443</p>
					<p>Authors: Leticia Montoya, Mariana Herrera, Victor M. Bandala, Antero Ramos</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of yellow Cantharellus and a new record of Cantharellus tabernensis associated with tropical species of Quercus are presented, based on the taxonomic study of fresh specimens and in a phylogenetic analysis of transcription elongation factor 1-alpha (tef-1α) and the large subunit of the ribosome (nLSU) sequences. One of the new species proposed here, corresponds to a choice edible mushroom, which, in our molecular phylogeny, resulted in it being related to the group of species around C. lateritius and sister with Craterellus confluens type specimen. This latter is here formally transferred to Cantharellus and consequently a new name, Cantharellus furcatus, is proposed to replace the homonym Cantharellus confluens (Schwein.) Schwein. 1834 a later synonym of Byssomerulius corium. Detailed macroscopic and microscopic descriptions accompanied with illustrations and a taxonomic discussion are presented for each species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61443/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61443/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61443/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 15:33:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Characterization of Diaporthe species associated with peach constriction canker, with two novel species from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63816/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 77-90</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.63816</p>
					<p>Authors: Xianhong Wang, Yashuang Guo, Yamin Du, Ziling Yang, Xinzhong Huang, Ni Hong, Wenxing Xu, Guoping Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of Diaporthe infect a wide range of plants and live in vivo as endophytes, saprobes or pathogens. However, those in peach plants are poorly characterized. In this study, 52 Diaporthe strains were isolated from peach branches with buds, showing constriction canker symptoms. Phylogenetic analyses were conducted using five gene regions: internal transcribed spacer of the ribosomal DNA (ITS), translation elongation factor 1-α (TEF), ß-tubulin (TUB), histone (HIS), and calmodulin (CAL). These results coupled with morphology revealed seven species of Diaporthe, including five known species (D. caryae, D. cercidis, D. eres, D. hongkongensis, and D. unshiuensis). In addition, two novel species D. jinxiu and D. zaofenghuang are introduced. Except for the previously reported D. eres, this study represents the first characterization of Diaporthe species associated with peach constriction canker in China, and contributes useful data for practicable disease management.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63816/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63816/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63816/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:11:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diversity of Plectosphaerella within aquatic plants from southwest China, with P. endophytica and P. sichuanensis spp. nov.</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64624/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 57-75</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.64624</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao Qian Yang, Shi Yun Ma, Ze Xiang Peng, Zhong Qiao Wang, Min Qiao, Zefen Yu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Members of Plectosphaerella inhabit different substrates, including plants, soil and insects, and most species are pathogens causing large losses in agriculture. During a survey of endophytic fungi in aquatic plants in southwest China, 112 strains of Plectosphaerella were isolated, representing two new species, P. endophytica sp. nov. and P. sichuanensis sp. nov., as well as two known species, P. cucumerina and P. pauciseptata. The novel taxa are described and illustrated here using combined morphological and multi-locus phylogenetic (LSU-ITS-TEF-1α-TUB2) analyses. Our result revealed Plectosphaerella species inhabiting within aquatic plants in southwest China, and the separation frequency of each species was presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64624/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64624/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64624/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 15:31:59 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Brahmaculus gen. nov. (Leotiomycetes, Chlorociboriaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64435/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 19-43</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.64435</p>
					<p>Authors: Peter R. Johnston, Duckchul Park, Matthew E. Smith, Alija B. Mujic, Tom W. May</p>
					<p>Abstract: A second genus in Chlorociboriaceae is described here as Brahmaculus gen. nov. Macroscopically distinctive, all species have bright yellow apothecia with several apothecial cups held on short branches at the tip of a long stipe. The genus is widely distributed across the Southern Hemisphere; the four new species described here include two from Chile (B. magellanicus sp. nov., B. osornoensis sp. nov.) and one each from New Zealand (B. moonlighticus sp. nov.) and Australia (B. packhamiae sp. nov.). They differ from species referred to Chlorociboria, the only other genus in Chlorociboriaceae, in their terrestrial habitat and ascomata that are noticeably more hairy than the known Chlorociboria species, most of which have apothecia with short, macroscopically indistinct hair-like elements. Based on our analyses, Chlorociboria as accepted here is paraphyletic. Additional study is needed to clarify where alternative, monophyletic generic limits should be drawn and how these genera may be recognised morphologically. Also described here are three new Chlorociboria spp. from New Zealand (C. metrosideri sp. nov., C. solandri sp. nov., C. subtilis sp. nov.), distinctive in developing on dead leaves rather than wood and in two of them not forming the green pigmentation characteristic of most Chlorociboria species. New Zealand specimens previously incorrectly identified as Chlorociboria argentinensis are provided with a new name, C. novae-zelandiae sp. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64435/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64435/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64435/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2021 15:51:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Multi-gene phylogenetic evidence indicates that Pleurodesmospora belongs in Cordycipitaceae (Hypocreales, Hypocreomycetidae) and Pleurodesmospora lepidopterorum sp. nov. on pupa from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66794/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 45-55</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.66794</p>
					<p>Authors: Wan-Hao Chen, Yan-Feng Han, Jian-Dong Liang, Wei-Yi Tian, Zong-Qi Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Pleurodesmospora lepidopterorum, isolated from a pupa, is introduced. Morphological comparisons and phylogenetic analyses based on multigene datasets (ITS+RPB1+RPB2+TEF) support the establishment of the new species. Pleurodesmospora lepidopterorum is distinguished from P. coccorum by its longer conidiogenous pegs located in the terminal or lateral conidiophores, and smaller subglobose or ellipsoidal conidia. A combined dataset of RPB1, RPB2, and TEF confirmed the taxonomic placement of Pleurodesmospora in Cordycipitaceae for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66794/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66794/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66794/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2021 12:52:08 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Hymenochaetaceae on Dracaena cambodiana from tropical China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63997/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 80: 1-17</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.80.63997</p>
					<p>Authors: Ping Du, Tian-Xu Cao, Ying-Da Wu, Meng Zhou, Zhan-Bo Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new wood-rotting fungi in the family Hymenochaetaceae, Fulvifomes dracaenicola sp. nov. and Hymenochaete dracaenicola sp. nov., are described and illustrated from tropical China based on morphological characteristics and molecular data. It is worth to mention that both of them grow on Dracaena cambodiana which is a kind of angiosperm tree distributed in tropical regions. F. dracaenicola is characterised by perennial, pileate, triquetrous basidioma with yellowish brown fresh pores which becoming honey yellow with silk sheening upon drying, a dimitic hyphal system in trama and monomitic in context, and subglobose basidiospores measuring 4.8–5 × 4–4.1 μm. H. dracaenicola is characterised by annual, resupinate basidioma with a clay buff hymenophore, a dimitic hyphal system, absence of tomentum and cortex, presence of subulate setae, absence of cystidia, presence of cystidioles and simple hyphidia, and oblong ellipsoid basidiospores measuring 5.2–5.8 × 2.5–2.8 µm. The phylogenetic analyses based on ITS + nLSU rDNA sequences confirm the placement of two new species respectively in Fulvifomes and Hymenochaete. Phylogenetically closely related species to the two new species are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63997/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63997/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63997/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 5 May 2021 12:00:36 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morpho-molecular characterization of Discosia ravennica sp. nov. and a new host record for Sporocadus rosigena</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60662/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 173-192</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.60662</p>
					<p>Authors: Digvijayini Bundhun, Rajesh Jeewon, Indunil C. Senanayake, Erio Camporesi, Janith V. S. Aluthmuhandiram, Alvin M. C. Tang, Ji-Chuan Kang, Vishwakalyan Bhoyroo, Kevin D. Hyde</p>
					<p>Abstract: Collections of fungal samples from two dead leaf specimens from Italy were subjected to morphological examination and phylogenetic analyses. Two coelomycetous taxa belonging to two different genera in Xylariomycetidae, Sordariomycetes, namely Discosia and Sporocadus, were identified. The Discosia taxon is revealed as a new species and is herein introduced as Discosia ravennica sp. nov. while the Sporocadus taxon is identified as Sporocadus rosigena. Multi-locus phylogeny based on DNA sequence data of the large subunit (LSU) and internal transcribed spacer (ITS) of nuclear ribosomal genes, β-tubulin (β-tub) and RNA polymerase II second largest subunit (rpb2) showed that D. ravennica is related to D. neofraxinea but it forms an independent lineage that supports its new species status. The new taxon also differs from other Discosia species by its unilocular to bilocular, superficial and applanate conidiomata with basal stroma composed of cells of textura angularis, elongate-ampulliform conidiogenous cells and conidia smaller in size. Sporocadus rosigena is here reported as a new host record from Quercus ilex from Italy. Descriptions, illustrations and molecular data for both species are provided in this paper.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60662/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60662/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60662/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 07:54:51 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new clitocyboid genus Spodocybe and a new subfamily Cuphophylloideae in the family Hygrophoraceae (Agaricales)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66302/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 129-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.66302</p>
					<p>Authors: Zheng-Mi He, Zhu L. Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Phylogenetically, the genera Cuphophyllus, Ampulloclitocybe and Cantharocybe are treated as basal in the family Hygrophoraceae, despite weak support. However, the exact phylogenetic positions of the three genera have remained unresolved, and taxa related to these genera are poorly known. In this study, a new clitocyboid genus Spodocybe was proposed based on multigenic phylogenetic inference datasets and morphological evidence. The analyses of ITS as well as two combined datasets ITS-nrLSU-rpb2 and ITS-nrLSU-rpb1-rpb2-tef1-α-atp6 supported that (1) Spodocybe formed a well-supported monophyletic clade; and (2) sisters Spodocybe and Ampulloclitocybe, along with Cantharocybe and Cuphophyllus also formed a monophyletic lineage, as sister to the rest of the Hygrophoraceae. Meanwhile, two new species, namely S. rugosiceps and S. bispora, from southwestern China, were documented and illustrated. These results support the new proposed genus Spodocybe, and that Spodocybe, Ampulloclitocybe, Cantharocybe and Cuphophyllus should be retained in the Hygrophoraceae as a new subfamily Cuphophylloideae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66302/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66302/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/66302/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 16:08:08 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Phylogeny and diversity of Bjerkandera (Polyporales, Basidiomycota), including four new species from South America and Asia</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63908/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 149-172</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.63908</p>
					<p>Authors: Chao-Ge Wang, Josef Vlasák, Yu-Cheng Dai</p>
					<p>Abstract: Four new species of Bjerkandera, viz. B. ecuadorensis, B. fulgida, B. minispora, and B. resupinata spp. nov., are described from tropical America and Asia. B. ecuadorensis is characterised by dark grey to black pore surface, a monomitic hyphal system, hyaline to yellowish-brown generative hyphae, and ellipsoid basidiospores measuring 3.9–4.5 × 2.7–3 μm. B. fulgida is distinguished from the other species in the genus by clay buff to pale brown and shiny pore surface. B. minispora is characterised by white tomentose pore mouth and small basidiospores measuring 3.1–4.2 × 2–2.8 μm. B. resupinata is characterised by resupinate basidiomata, pinkish buff to pale brownish pore surface, and ellipsoid to broadly ellipsoid basidiospores measuring 4.5–6 × 3.2–4.1 µm. All these new species grow on angiosperm trunks or rotten wood, and cause a white rot. The closely related taxa to four new species are discussed. An identification key to the ten accepted species of Bjerkandera is provided, and a phylogeny comprising all known Bjerkandera species is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63908/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63908/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63908/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 14:58:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First record of the rare genus Typhrasa (Psathyrellaceae, Agaricales) from China with description of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63700/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 119-128</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.63700</p>
					<p>Authors: Sheng-Nan Wang, Ya-Ping Hu, Jun-Liang Chen, Liang-Liang Qi, Hui Zeng, Hui Ding, Guang-Hua Huo, Lin-Ping Zhang, Fu-Sheng Chen, Jun-Qing Yan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Typhrasa is a rare genus that comprises two species and that has previously been reported only from Europe and North America. The present study expands the geographical scope of the genus by describing two new species – T. polycystis and T. rugocephala – from subtropical China. The new species are supported by morphological characteristics and phylogenetic analyses (ITS, LSU and tef-1α). The new species have very similar morphological characteristics and are 98% similar in their ITS region. However, T. rugocephala has two types of long gills at the same time, rarely fusiform pleurocystidia with rostrum. Detailed descriptions, colour photos, illustrations and a key to related species are presented in this paper.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63700/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63700/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63700/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:52:39 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A survey of Hebeloma (Hymenogastraceae) in Greenland</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63363/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 17-118</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.63363</p>
					<p>Authors: Ursula Eberhardt, Henry J. Beker, Torbjørn Borgen, Henning Knudsen, Nicole Schütz, Steen A. Elborne</p>
					<p>Abstract: This is the first study exclusively dedicated to the study of Hebeloma in Greenland. It is based on almost 400 collections, the great majority of which were collected by three of the co-authors over a period of 40 years and were lodged in the fungarium of the Natural History Museum in Copenhagen. The material was identified using molecular and morphological methods. In total, 28 species were recognized, 27 belonging to three sections, H. sects Hebeloma, Denudata and Velutipes. One species sampled was new to science and is here described as H. arcticum. For all species, a description, a distribution map within Greenland and macro and microphotographs are presented. A key is provided for the 28 species. The distribution of species within Greenland is discussed. The findings are placed in the context of studies of arctic and alpine Hebeloma from other parts of the world where comparable data exist. Notably, H. grandisporum, H. louiseae and H. islandicum, previously only known from Romania, Svalbard, Iceland or Norway, respectively, have been found in Greenland. The latter is also the only species encountered that does not belong to any of the above sections. Hebeloma excedens and H. colvinii – for the latter we here publish the first modern description – are to date only known from continental North America and now Greenland.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63363/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63363/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/63363/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Monograph</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 12:00:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Micromelanconis kaihuiae gen. et sp. nov., a new diaporthalean fungus from Chinese chestnut branches in southern China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65221/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 79: 1-16</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.79.65221</p>
					<p>Authors: Ning Jiang, Qin Yang, Xin-Lei Fan, Cheng-Ming Tian</p>
					<p>Abstract: Melanconis-like fungi are distributed in several families of Diaporthales, mainly Juglanconidaceae, Melanconidaceae, Melanconiellaceae and Pseudomelanconidaceae. A new Melanconis-like genus of Pseudomelanconidaceae was discovered on branches of Chinese chestnut (Castanea mollissima) in southern China, which was confirmed by both morphology and phylogenetic analysis of combined ITS, LSU, tef1a and rpb2 sequences. The new genus Micromelanconis is characterized by two types of conidia from natural substrate and manual media of PDA, respectively. Conidia from Chinese chestnut branches are pale brown, ellipsoid, multiguttulate, aseptate with hyaline sheath. While conidia from PDA plates are pale brown, long dumbbell-shaped, narrow at the middle and wide at both ends, multiguttulate, aseptate, and also with hyaline sheath. All Pseudomelanconidaceae species were only reported on tree branches in China until now. More interesting taxa may be discovered if detailed surveys on tree-inhabiting fungi are carried out in East Asia in the future.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65221/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65221/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/65221/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:52:55 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and molecular identification of two new Alternaria species (Ascomycota, Pleosporaceae) in section Radicina from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64853/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 187-198</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.64853</p>
					<p>Authors: Lin He, Hong Cheng, Lin Zhao, Aye Aye Htun, Zhi He Yu, Jian Xin Deng, Qi Li Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: The fungal genus Alternaria was distributed widely and found in different habitats such as plant or indoor environment. During an investigation into this genus in China, two new Alternaria species, Alternaria vulgarae and A. divaricatae were respectively isolated from diseased leaves of Foeniculum vulgare and Saposhnikovia divaricata, which both belonged to Umbelliferae. Phylogenetically, they were determined as new species belonging in the section Radicina of Alternaria based on the combined four gene fragments of ITS, TEF1, GAPDH and RPB2. Morphologically, the two species were illustrated and compared with other relevant Alternaria species in section Radicina.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64853/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64853/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/64853/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 9 Apr 2021 10:05:35 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Multiple-marker phylogeny and morphological evidence reveal two new species in Steccherinaceae (Polyporales, Basidiomycota) from Asia</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57823/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 169-186</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.57823</p>
					<p>Authors: Ting Cao, Jia-Rui Yu, Trang Thị Thu Nguyễn, Hai-Sheng Yuan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new wood-inhabiting fungi, Mycorrhaphium subadustum sp. nov. and Trullella conifericola sp. nov., are proposed and described from Asia based on ITS, nrLSU and tef1 molecular phylogeny and morphological characteristics. Mycorrhaphium subadustum is characterized by a stipitate basidiocarp, velutinate pileal surface concentrically zoned, hydnoid hymenophore, a dimitic hyphal system in spine trama and monomitic in context, absence of gloeocystidia, presence of cystidioles and the non-amyloid, cylindrical to ellipsoid basidiospores. Trullella conifericola is characterized by a laterally stipitate basidiocarp with flabelliform to semicircular pileus, hirtellous pileal surface with appressed coarse hair and concentrically zoned and sulcate, tiny pores (10–12 per mm), a dimitic hyphal system, absence of any type of cystidia, short clavate basidia and thin-walled, smooth, cylindrical to allantoid basidiospores. Phylogenetic analyses based on a three-marker dataset were performed using maximum likelihood and Bayesian inference methods. The two new species formed isolated lineages with full support in Steccherinaceae. The distinguishing characters of the two new species as well as allied species are discussed, and a key to species of Mycorrhaphium is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57823/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57823/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57823/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 5 Apr 2021 10:15:21 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Novel taxa and species diversity of Cordyceps sensu lato (Hypocreales, Ascomycota) developing on wireworms (Elateroidea and Tenebrionoidea, Coleoptera)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61836/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 79-117</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.61836</p>
					<p>Authors: Ling-Sheng Zha, Vadim Yu Kryukov, Jian-Hua Ding, Rajesh Jeewon, Putarak Chomnunti</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of Cordyceps sensu lato (Hypocreales, Sordariomycetes) have always attracted much scientific attention for their abundant species diversity, important medicinal values and biological control applications. The insect superfamilies Elateroidea and Tenebrionoidea are two large groups of Coleoptera and their larvae are generally called wireworms. Most wireworms inhabit humid soil or fallen wood and are often infected with Cordyceps s.l. However, the species diversity of Cordyceps s.l. on Elateroidea and Tenebrionoidea is poorly known. In the present work, we summarise taxonomic information of 63 Cordyceps s.l. species that have been reported as pathogens of wireworms. We review their hosts and geographic distributions and provide taxonomic notes for species. Of those, 60 fungal species are accepted as natural pathogens of wireworms and three species (Cordyceps militaris, Ophiocordyceps ferruginosa and O. variabilis) are excluded. Two new species, O. borealis from Russia (Primorsky Krai) and O. spicatus from China (Guizhou), are described and compared with their closest allies. Polycephalomyces formosus is also described because it is reported as a pathogen of wireworms for the first time. Phylogeny was reconstructed from a combined dataset, comprising SSU, LSU and TEF1-α gene sequences. The results, presented in this study, support the establishment of the new species and confirm the identification of P. formosus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61836/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61836/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/61836/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 10:43:16 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The lichens of the Majella National Park (Central Italy): an annotated checklist</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62362/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 119-168</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.62362</p>
					<p>Authors: Gabriele Gheza, Luca Di Nuzzo, Chiara Vallese, Renato Benesperi, Elisabetta Bianchi, Valter Di Cecco, Luciano Di Martino, Paolo Giordani, Josef Hafellner, Helmut Mayrhofer, Pier Luigi Nimis, Mauro Tretiach, Juri Nascimbene</p>
					<p>Abstract: The botanical exploration of the Majella National Park has a long tradition dating back to the eighteenth century. However, the lichen biota of this area is still poorly investigated. To provide a baseline for future investigations, in this annotated checklist, we summarised all available information on the occurrence of lichens in the Majella National Park, retrieved from previous literature, herbarium material and original data produced by recent research.        The checklist includes 342 infrageneric taxa. However, seven taxa are considered as dubious, thus setting the number of accepted taxa at 335, i.e. 45.8% of those currently known to occur in the Abruzzo Region. This checklist provides a baseline of the lichens known to occur in the Majella National Park, highlighting the potential of this area as a hotspot of lichen biodiversity, especially from a biogeographical point of view as indicated by the occurrence of several arctic-alpine species that form disjunct populations in the summit area of the massif.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62362/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62362/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62362/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 09:10:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and phylogenetic analyses reveal three new species of Diaporthe from Yunnan, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60878/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 49-77</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.60878</p>
					<p>Authors: Shengting Huang, Jiwen Xia, Xiuguo Zhang, WenXiu Sun</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of Diaporthe have often been reported as plant pathogens, endophytes or saprobes, commonly isolated from a wide range of plant hosts. Sixteen strains isolated from species of ten host genera in Yunnan Province, China, represented three new species of Diaporthe, D. chrysalidocarpi, D. machili and D. pometiae as well as five known species D. arecae, D. hongkongensis, D. middletonii, D. osmanthi and D. pandanicola. Morphological comparisons with known species and DNA-based phylogenies based on the analysis of a multigene (ITS, TUB, TEF, CAL and HIS) dataset support the establishment of the new species. This study reveals that a high species diversity of Diaporthe with wide host ranges occur in tropical rainforest in Yunnan Province, China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60878/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60878/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60878/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:35:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Notes on Trochila (Ascomycota, Leotiomycetes), with new species and combinations</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62046/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 21-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.62046</p>
					<p>Authors: Paula Andrea Gómez-Zapata, Danny Haelewaters, Luis Quijada, Donald H. Pfister, M. Catherine Aime</p>
					<p>Abstract: Studies of Trochila (Leotiomycetes, Helotiales, Cenangiaceae) are scarce. Here, we describe two new species based on molecular phylogenetic data and morphology. Trochila bostonensis was collected at the Boston Harbor Islands National Recreation Area, Massachusetts. It was found on the stem of Asclepias syriaca, representing the first report of any Trochila species from a plant host in the family Apocynaceae. Trochila urediniophila is associated with the uredinia of the rust fungus Cerotelium fici. It was discovered during a survey for rust hyperparasites conducted at the Arthur Fungarium, in a single sample from 1912 collected in Trinidad. Macro- and micromorphological descriptions, illustrations, and molecular phylogenetic analyses are presented. The two new species are placed in Trochila with high support in both our six-locus (SSU, ITS, LSU, rpb1, rpb2, tef1) and two-locus (ITS, LSU) phylogenetic reconstructions. In addition, two species are combined in Trochila: Trochila colensoi (formerly placed in Pseudopeziza) and T. xishuangbanna (originally described as the only species in Calycellinopsis). This study reveals new host plant families, a new ecological strategy, and a new country record for the genus Trochila. Finally, our work emphasizes the importance of specimens deposited in biological collections such as fungaria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62046/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62046/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/62046/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Cryptic diversity found in Didymellaceae from Australian native legumes</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60063/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 78: 1-20</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.78.60063</p>
					<p>Authors: Elizabeth C. Keirnan, Yu Pei Tan, Matthew H. Laurence, Allison A. Mertin, Edward C. Y. Liew, Brett A. Summerell, Roger G. Shivas</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ascochyta koolunga (Didymellaceae, Pleosporales) was first described in 2009 (as Phoma koolunga) and identified as the causal agent of Ascochyta blight of Pisum sativum (field pea) in South Australia. Since then A. koolunga has not been reported anywhere else in the world, and its origins and occurrence on other legume (Fabaceae) species remains unknown. Blight and leaf spot diseases of Australian native, pasture and naturalised legumes were studied to investigate a possible native origin of A. koolunga.                  Ascochyta koolunga was not detected on native, naturalised or pasture legumes that had leaf spot symptoms, in any of the studied regions in southern Australia, and only one isolate was recovered from P. sativum. However, we isolated five novel species in the Didymellaceae from leaf spots of Australian native legumes from commercial field pea regions throughout southern Australia. The novel species were classified on the basis of morphology and phylogenetic analyses of the internal transcribed spacer region and part of the RNA polymerase II subunit B gene region. Three of these species, Nothophoma garlbiwalawarda sp. nov., Nothophoma naiawu sp. nov. and Nothophoma ngayawang sp. nov., were isolated from Senna artemisioides. The other species described here are Epicoccum djirangnandiri sp. nov. from Swainsona galegifolia and Neodidymelliopsis tinkyukuku sp. nov. from Hardenbergia violacea. In addition, we report three new host-pathogen associations in Australia, namely Didymella pinodes on S. artemisioides and Vicia cracca, and D. lethalis on Lathyrus tingitanus. This is also the first report of Didymella prosopidis in Australia.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60063/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60063/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60063/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Feb 2021 16:14:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Inosperma (Agaricales, Inocybaceae) from Tropical Africa</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60084/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 97-116</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.60084</p>
					<p>Authors: Hyppolite L. Aïgnon, Sana Jabeen, Arooj Naseer, Nourou S. Yorou, Martin Ryberg</p>
					<p>Abstract: Here, we describe three new species of Inosperma from Tropical Africa: Inosperma africanum, I. bulbomarginatum and I. flavobrunneum. Morphological and molecular data show that these species have not been described before, hence need to be described as new. The phylogenetic placements of these species were inferred, based on molecular evidence from sequences of 28S and RPB2. Additional analysis using ITS dataset shows interspecific variation between each species. Phylogenetic analyses resolve I. flavobrunneum in Old World Tropical clade 1 with weak support, I. bulbomarginatum is sister of Old World Tropical clade 1 and I. africanum is indicated as sister to the rest of Inosperma. Complete description and illustrations, including photographs and line drawings, are presented for each species. A new combination of Inocybe shawarensis into Inosperma is also proposed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60084/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60084/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60084/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 17:14:24 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Hebeloma in the Malay Peninsula: Masquerading within Psathyrella</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57394/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 117-141</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.57394</p>
					<p>Authors: Ursula Eberhardt, Nicole Schütz, Henry J. Beker, Su See Lee, Egon Horak</p>
					<p>Abstract: In 1994 Corner published five new species within the genus Psathyrella, all having been collected on the Malay Peninsula between 1929 and 1930. Three of these species belong to the genus Hebeloma and with their vinaceous colored lamellae and spore print, when fresh, they belong to H. sect. Porphyrospora. Of these three species, only one, P. flavidifolia, was validly published and thus we herewith recombine it as H. flavidifolium. The other two species, P. splendens and P. verrucispora, are synonyms of H. parvisporum and H. lactariolens, respectively. We also describe a new Malayan species, H. radicans, which also belongs to H. sect. Porphyrospora. These findings confirm the western Pacific Rim as a diversity hotspot for H. sect. Porphyrospora. The records described within this paper, represent the first recognition that the genus Hebeloma, and indeed that members of the ectomycorrhizal Hymenogastraceae, are present on the Malay Peninsula.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57394/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57394/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57394/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 13:36:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and molecular identification of Diaporthe species in south-western China, with description of eight new species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59852/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 65-95</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.59852</p>
					<p>Authors: Wenxiu Sun, Shengting Huang, Jiwen Xia, Xiuguo Zhang, Zhuang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diaporthe species have often been reported as plant pathogens, endophytes and saprophytes, commonly isolated from a wide range of infected plant hosts. In the present study, twenty strains obtained from leaf spots of twelve host plants in Yunnan Province of China were isolated. Based on a combination of morphology, culture characteristics and multilocus sequence analysis of the rDNA internal transcribed spacer region (ITS), translation elongation factor 1-α (TEF), β-tubulin (TUB), calmodulin (CAL), and histone (HIS) genes, these strains were identified as eight new species: Diaporthe camelliae-sinensis, D. grandiflori, D. heliconiae, D. heterostemmatis, D. litchii, D. lutescens, D. melastomatis, D. pungensis and two previously described species, D. subclavata and D. tectonendophytica. This study showed high species diversity of Diaporthe in tropical rain forests and its hosts in south-western China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59852/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59852/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59852/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Review Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:58:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species and records of Diaporthe from Jiangxi Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59999/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 41-64</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.59999</p>
					<p>Authors: Qin Yang, Ning Jiang, Cheng-Ming Tian</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diaporthe species have often been reported as important plant pathogens, saprobes and endophytes on a wide range of plant hosts. Although several Diaporthe species have been recorded, little is known about species able to infect forest trees in Jiangxi Province. Hence, extensive surveys were recently conducted in Jiangxi Province, China. A total of 24 isolates were identified and analysed using comparisons of DNA sequence data for the nuclear ribosomal internal transcribed spacer (ITS), calmodulin (cal), histone H3 (his3), partial translation elongation factor-1α (tef1) and β-tubulin (tub2) gene regions, as well as their morphological features. Results revealed five novel taxa, D. bauhiniae, D. ganzhouensis, D. schimae, D. verniciicola, D. xunwuensis spp. nov. and three known species, D. apiculatum, D. citri and D. multigutullata.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59999/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59999/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59999/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 15:07:17 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diversity of the genus Sugiyamaella and description of two new species from rotting wood in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60077/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 27-39</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.60077</p>
					<p>Authors: Cheng-Feng Shi, Kai-Hong Zhang, Chun-Yue Chai, Zhen-Li Yan, Feng-Li Hui</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of the genus Sugiyamaella (Trichomonascaceae, Saccharomycetales), found in rotting wood in China, were investigated using morphology and the molecular phylogeny of a combined ITS and nrLSU dataset. Nine taxa were collected in China: two were new species (viz. Sugiyamaella chuxiong sp. nov. and S. yunanensis sp. nov.) and seven were known species, S. americana, S. ayubii, S. novakii, S. paludigena, S. valenteae, S. valdiviana and S. xiaguanensis. The two new species are illustrated and their morphology and phylogenetic relationships with other Sugiyamaella species are discussed. Our results indicate a potentially great diversity of Sugiyamaella spp. inhabiting rotting wood in China just waiting to be discovered.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60077/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60077/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60077/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 08:15:34 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Novel species of Cladosporium from environmental sources in Spain</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60862/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 77: 1-25</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.77.60862</p>
					<p>Authors: Isabel Iturrieta-González, Dania García, Josepa Gené</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cladosporium is a monophyletic genus in Cladosporiaceae (Cladosporiales, Dothideomycetes) whose species are mainly found as saprobes and endophytes, but it also includes fungi pathogenic for plants, animals and human. Species identification is currently based on three genetic markers, viz., the internal transcribed spacer regions (ITS) of the rDNA, and partial fragments of actin (act) and the translation elongation factor 1-α (tef1) genes. Using this phylogenetic approach and from morphological differences, we have recognized six new species originating from soil, herbivore dung and plant material collected at different Spanish locations. They are proposed as Cladosporium caprifimosum, C. coprophilum, C. fuscoviride and C. lentulum belonging in the C. cladosporioides species complex, and C. pseudotenellum and C. submersum belonging in the C. herbarum species complex. This study revealed that herbivore dung represented a reservoir of novel lineages in the genus Cladosporium.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60862/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60862/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/60862/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 5 Jan 2021 08:15:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morpho-phylogenetic evidence reveals new species in Rhytismataceae (Rhytismatales, Leotiomycetes, Ascomycota) from Guizhou Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58465/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 76: 81-106</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.76.58465</p>
					<p>Authors: Jin-Feng Zhang, Jian-Kui Liu, Kevin D. Hyde, Anusha H. Ekanayaka, Zuo-Yi Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Karst formations represent a unique eco-environment. Research in the microfungi inhabiting this area is limited. During an ongoing survey of ascomycetous microfungi from karst terrains in Guizhou Province, China, we discovered four new species, which are introduced here as Hypoderma paralinderae, Terriera karsti, T. meitanensis and T. sigmoideospora placed in Rhytismataceae, based on phylogenetic analyses and morphological characters. Molecular analyses, based on concatenated LSU-ITS-mtSSU sequence data, were used to infer phylogenetic affinities. Detail descriptions and comprehensive illustrations of these new taxa are provided and relationships with the allied species are discussed, based on comparative morphology and molecular data.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58465/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58465/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58465/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:58:16 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cryphonectriaceae associated with rust-infected Syzygium jambos in Hawaii</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58406/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 76: 49-79</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.76.58406</p>
					<p>Authors: Jolanda Roux, Gilbert Kamgan Nkuekam, Seonju Marincowitz, Nicolaas A. van der Merwe, Janice Uchida, Michael J. Wingfield, ShuaiFei Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Syzygium jambos (Myrtales, Myrtaceae) trees in Hawaii are severely affected by a rust disease caused by Austropuccinia psidii (Pucciniales, Sphaerophragmiaceae), but they are commonly co-infected with species of Cryphonectriaceae (Diaporthales). In this study, S. jambos and other trees in the Myrtales were examined on three Hawaiian Islands for the presence of Cryphonectriaceae. Bark samples with fruiting bodies were collected from infected trees and fungi were isolated directly from these structures. Pure cultures were produced and the fungi were identified using DNA sequence data for the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) region, part of the β-tubulin (BT1) gene and the transcription elongation factor-1α (TEF1) gene. Five species in three genera of Cryphonectriaceae were identified from Myrtaceae tree samples. These included Chrysoporthe deuterocubensis, Microthia havanensis and three previously-unknown taxa described here as Celoporthe hauoliensis sp. nov., Cel. hawaiiensis sp. nov. and Cel. paradisiaca sp. nov. Representative isolates of Cel. hauoliensis, Cel. hawaiiensis, Cel. paradisiaca, Chr. deuterocubensis and Mic. havanensis were used in artificial inoculation studies to consider their pathogenicity on S. jambos. Celoporthe hawaiiensis, Cel. paradisiaca and Chr. deuterocubensis produced lesions on young S. jambos trees in inoculation trials, suggesting that, together with A. psidii, they may contribute to the death of trees. Microsatellite markers were subsequently used to consider the diversity of Chr. deuterocubensis on the Islands and thus to gain insights into its possible origin in Hawaii. Isolates of this important Myrtaceae and particularly Eucalyptus pathogen were found to be clonal. This provides evidence that Chr. deuterocubensis was introduced to the Hawaiian Islands as a single introduction, from a currently unknown source.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58406/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58406/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58406/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 12:50:05 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Phialolunulospora vermispora (Chaetosphaeriaceae, Sordariomycetes), a novel asexual genus and species from freshwater in southern China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57410/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 76: 17-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.76.57410</p>
					<p>Authors: Hua Zheng, Yake Wan, Jie Li, Rafael F. Castañeda-Ruiz, Zefen Yu</p>
					<p>Abstract: The asexual taxon Phialolunulospora vermispora gen. et sp. nov., collected from submerged dicotyledonous leaves in Hainan, China, is described and illustrated herein. Phialolunulospora gen. nov. is characterized by macronematous, semimacronematous, septate and pigmented conidiophores and acrogenous, long lunate, vermiform to sigmoid, hyaline conidia with an eccentric basal appendage. Complete sequences of internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and partial sequences of nuclear large subunits ribosomal DNA (LSU) genes are provided. Phylogenetic analyses of combined ITS and LSU sequences revealed its placement in the Chaetosphaeriaceae. The new fungus is compared with morphologically similar genera.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57410/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57410/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57410/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 13:56:18 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New Cantharellus species from South Korea</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58179/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 76: 31-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.76.58179</p>
					<p>Authors: Bart Buyck, Valérie Hofstetter, Rhim Ryoo, Kang-Hyeon Ka, Vladimír Antonín</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this third contribution involving new Cantharellus species from South Korea, two new species are introduced. In addition, we document a first report of the recently described Japanese Cantharellus anzutake outside of Japan based on identical ITS sequence data. Cantharellus citrinus sp. nov. is introduced as a new member of subgenus Cinnabarini, to which the closely related Korean C. albovenosus and Chinese C. phloginus also belong. Cantharellus curvatus sp. nov. is introduced as a new member of subgenus Parvocantharellus, in which the Korean C. koreanus was recently placed. The respective placements of the new taxa are significantly supported by a phylogenetic analysis of sequences from the transcription elongation factor (tef-1).</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58179/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58179/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58179/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 13:31:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The insights into the evolutionary history of Translucidithyrium: based on a newly-discovered species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58628/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 76: 1-16</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.76.58628</p>
					<p>Authors: Xinhao Li, Hai-Xia Wu, Jinchen Li, Hang Chen, Wei Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: During the field studies, a Translucidithyrium-like taxon was collected in Xishuangbanna of Yunnan Province, during an investigation into the diversity of microfungi in the southwest of China. Morphological observations and phylogenetic analysis of combined LSU and ITS sequences revealed that the new taxon is a member of the genus Translucidithyrium and it is distinct from other species. Therefore, Translucidithyrium chinense sp. nov. is introduced here. The Maximum Clade Credibility (MCC) tree from LSU rDNA of Translucidithyrium and related species indicated the divergence time of existing and new species of Translucidithyrium was crown age at 16 (4–33) Mya. Combining the estimated divergence time, paleoecology and plate tectonic movements with the corresponding geological time scale, we proposed a hypothesis that the speciation (estimated divergence time) of T. chinense was earlier than T. thailandicum. Our findings provided new insights into the species of Translucidithyrium about ecological adaptation and speciation in two separate areas.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58628/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58628/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/58628/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 08:48:31 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species from Guangdong Province of China, and a molecular assessment of Hygrocybe subsection Hygrocybe</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59600/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 75: 145-161</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.75.59600</p>
					<p>Authors: Chao-Qun Wang, Ming Zhang, Tai-Hui Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Blackening waxcaps (Hygrocybe subsect. Hygrocybe) are a group of colorful and attractive mushrooms. However, the species diversity of subsect. Hygrocybe in China is still poorly known due to the limited sampling. In this study, three new species of this group from Guangdong Province, China are described and illustrated based on their morphological characteristics and molecular analyses of the internal transcribed spacer and large subunit ribosomal DNA regions. Hygrocybe debilipes from grasslands of South China Sea islands is mainly characterized by its orange red to vivid red pileus, fragile stipe, and ellipsoid to oblong basidiospores; H. griseonigricans from woodlands is characterized by its whitish to dull yellow pileus, quick black discoloration and the globose, subglobose to broadly ovoid basidiospores; H. rubroconica from woodlands is characterized by the hemispheric to plano-convex pileus when mature, semitranslucent fibrose stipe, and globose to ellipsoid basidiospores.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59600/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59600/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59600/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 9 Dec 2020 14:08:06 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A global meta-analysis of ITS rDNA sequences from material belonging to the genus Ganoderma (Basidiomycota, Polyporales) including new data from selected taxa</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59872/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 75: 71-143</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.75.59872</p>
					<p>Authors: Vassiliki Fryssouli, Georgios Zervakis, Elias Polemis, Milton A. Typas</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ganoderma P. Karst. is a cosmopolitan genus of white-rot fungi which comprises species with highly-prized pharmaceutical properties, valuable biotechnological applications and of significant phytopathological interest. However, the status of the taxonomy within the genus is still highly controversial and ambiguous despite the progress made through molecular approaches. A metadata analysis of 3908 nuclear ribosomal internal transcribed spacer (ITS) rDNA sequences obtained from GenBank/ENA/DDBJ and UNITE was performed by targeting sequences annotated as Ganoderma, but also sequences from environmental samples and from material examined for the first time. Ganoderma taxa segregated into five main lineages (Clades A to E). Clade A corresponds to the core of laccate species and includes G. shanxiense and three major well-supported clusters: Cluster A.1 (‘G. lucidum sensu lato’) consists of taxa from Eurasia and North America, Cluster A.2 of material with worldwide occurrence including G. resinaceum and Cluster A.3 is composed of species originating from all continents except Europe and comprises G. lingzhi. Clade B includes G. applanatum and allied species with a Holarctic distribution. Clade C comprises taxa from Asia and Africa only. Clade D consists of laccate taxa with tropical/subtropical occurrence, while clade E harbours the highest number of non-laccate species with a cosmopolitan distribution. The 92 Ganoderma-associated names, initially used for sequences labelling, correspond to at least 80 taxa. Amongst them, 21 constitute putatively new phylospecies after our application of criteria relevant to the robustness/support of the terminal clades, intra- and interspecific genetic divergence and available biogeographic data. Moreover, several other groups or individual sequences seem to represent distinct taxonomic entities and merit further investigation. A particularly large number of the public sequences was revealed to be insufficiently and/or incorrectly identified, for example, 87% and 78% of entries labelled as G. australe and G. lucidum, respectively. In general, ITS demonstrated high efficacy in resolving relationships amongst most of the Ganoderma taxa; however, it was not equally useful at elucidating species barriers across the entire genus and such cases are outlined. Furthermore, we draw conclusions on biogeography by evaluating species occurrence on a global scale in conjunction with phylogenetic structure/patterns. The sequence variability assessed in ITS spacers could be further exploited for diagnostic purposes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59872/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59872/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59872/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 1 Dec 2020 19:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The taxonomy of the model filamentous fungus Podospora anserina</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55968/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 75: 51-69</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.75.55968</p>
					<p>Authors: S. Lorena Ament-Velásquez, Hanna Johannesson, Tatiana Giraud, Robert Debuchy, Sven J. Saupe, Alfons J. M. Debets, Eric Bastiaans, Fabienne Malagnac, Pierre Grognet, Leonardo Peraza-Reyes, Pierre Gladieux, Åsa Kruys, Philippe Silar, Sabine M. Huhndorf, Andrew N. Miller, Aaron A. Vogan</p>
					<p>Abstract: The filamentous fungus Podospora anserina has been used as a model organism for more than 100 years and has proved to be an invaluable resource in numerous areas of research. Throughout this period, P. anserina has been embroiled in a number of taxonomic controversies regarding the proper name under which it should be called. The most recent taxonomic treatment proposed to change the name of this important species to Triangularia anserina. The results of past name changes of this species indicate that the broader research community is unlikely to accept this change, which will lead to nomenclatural instability and confusion in literature. Here, we review the phylogeny of the species closely related to P. anserina and provide evidence that currently available marker information is insufficient to resolve the relationships amongst many of the lineages. We argue that it is not only premature to propose a new name for P. anserina based on current data, but also that every effort should be made to retain P. anserina as the current name to ensure stability and to minimise confusion in scientific literature. Therefore, we synonymise Triangularia with Podospora and suggest that either the type species of Podospora be moved to P. anserina from P. fimiseda or that all species within the Podosporaceae be placed in the genus Podospora.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55968/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55968/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55968/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:16:39 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic revision of Russula subsection Amoeninae from South Korea</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53673/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 75: 1-29</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.75.53673</p>
					<p>Authors: Komsit Wisitrassameewong, Myung Soo Park, Hyun Lee, Aniket Ghosh, Kanad Das, Bart Buyck, Brian P. Looney, Miroslav Caboň, Slavomír Adamčík, Changmu Kim, Chang Sun Kim, Young Woon Lim</p>
					<p>Abstract: Russula subsection Amoeninae is morphologically defined by a dry velvety pileus surface, a complete absence of cystidia with heteromorphous contents in all tissues, and spores without amyloid suprahilar spot. Thirty-four species within subsection Amoeninae have been published worldwide. Although most Russula species in South Korea have been assigned European or North American names, recent molecular studies have shown that Russula species from different continents are not conspecific. Therefore, the present study aims to: 1) define which species of Russula subsection Amoeninae occur on each continent using molecular phylogenetic analyses; 2) revise the taxonomy of Korean Amoeninae. The phylogenetic analyses using the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and multilocus sequences showed that subsection Amoeninae is monophyletic within subgenus Heterophyllidiae section Heterophyllae. A total of 21 Russula subsection Amoeninae species were confirmed from Asia, Australia, Europe, North America, and Central America, and species from different continents formed separate clades. Three species were recognized from South Korea and were clearly separated from the European and North American species. These species are R. bella, also reported from Japan, a new species described herein, Russula orientipurpurea, and a new species undescribed due to insufficient material.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53673/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53673/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53673/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Nov 2020 08:49:40 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Five new additions to the genus Spathaspora (Saccharomycetales, Debaryomycetaceae) from southwest China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57192/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 75: 31-49</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.75.57192</p>
					<p>Authors: Shi-Long Lv, Chun-Yue Chai, Yun Wang, Zhen-Li Yan, Feng-Li Hui</p>
					<p>Abstract: Spathaspora is an important genus of d-xylose-fermenting yeasts that are poorly studied in China. During recent yeast collections in Yunnan Province in China, 13 isolates of Spathaspora were obtained from rotting wood and all represent undescribed taxa. Based on morphological and phylogenetic analyses (ITS and nuc 28S), five new species are proposed: Spathaspora elongata, Sp. mengyangensis, Sp. jiuxiensis, Sp. parajiuxiensis and Sp. rosae. Our results indicate a high species diversity of Spathaspora waiting to be discovered in rotting wood from tropical and subtropical southwest China. In addition, the two Candida species, C. jeffriesii and C. materiae, which are members of the Spathaspora clade based on phylogeny, are transferred to Spathaspora as new combinations.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57192/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57192/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57192/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Nov 2020 08:32:57 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>                                    Cortinarius pakistanicus           and C. pseudotorvus: two new species in oak forests in the Pakistan Himalayas</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/49734/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 74: 91-108</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.74.49734</p>
					<p>Authors: Arooj Naseer, Isaac Garrido-Benavent, Junaid Khan, Josep Ballarà, Rafael Mahiques, Abdul Nasir Khalid, Hassan Sher</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus of basidiomycetous fungi Cortinarius occurs worldwide, from subtropical to boreal latitudes. Although molecular systematics has triggered the study of these fungi in the Americas and Europe in the last two decades, there is still limited research on its diversity in large portions of the planet, such as the high mountain ranges of Asia. Several collections of Cortinarius were made during mycological field trips conducted between 2014 and 2018 in pure oak forests in the Pakistan Himalayas. An integrative framework combining morphological and phylogenetic data was employed for their study. As a result, the two species C. pakistanicus and C. pseudotorvus are here described as new to science. Detailed macro- and micro-morphological descriptions, including SEM images of spores, and a molecular phylogenetic reconstruction based on nrITS sequence data are provided and used to discriminate the new species from morphologically and phylogenetically close taxa. Whereas our phylogenetic tree inference gave unequivocal support for the inclusion of C. pseudotorvus within C. sect. Telamonia, the assignment of C. pakistanicus to any known sections remained elusive. These species likely establish ectomycorrhizal associations with trees in the genus Quercus, making this type of forest in the Pakistan Himalayas a promising focus for future research on the diversity of Cortinarius.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/49734/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/49734/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/49734/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:34:43 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Corrigendum: Spjut R, Simon A, Guissard M, Magain N, Sérusiaux E (2020) The fruticose genera in the Ramalinaceae (Ascomycota, Lecanoromycetes): their diversity and evolutionary history. MycoKeys 73: 1–68. https://doi.org/10.3897/mycokeys.73.47287</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59175/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 74: 109-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.74.59175</p>
					<p>Authors: Richard Spjut, Antoine Simon, Martin Guissard, Nicolas Magain, Emmanuël Sérusiaux</p>
					<p>Abstract: None</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59175/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59175/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/59175/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Corrigenda</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 08:55:29 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Mrakia panshiensis sp. nov. a new member of the Cystofilobasidiales from soil in China, and description of the teleomorphic-stage of M. arctica</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53433/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 74: 75-90</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.74.53433</p>
					<p>Authors: Kai-Hong Zhang, Cheng-Feng Shi, Chun-Yue Chai, Feng-Li Hui</p>
					<p>Abstract: In a study on the fungal diversity in Northeast China, twelve yeast isolates were obtained from soils collected in three provinces, Helongjiang, Jilin and Liaoning. Morphological assessment and phylogenetic analyses of the nuc rDNA internal transcribed spacer (ITS) region and the D1/D2 domains of the nuc 28S rDNA (nuc 28S) gene of the 12 cultures placed them in the genus Mrakia, namely Mrakia aquatica, Mrakia arctica, Mrakia frigida, Mrakia gelida and Mrakia robertii. A total of three isolates represented a hitherto undescribed species, which is described here as M. panshiensis sp. nov. (MB 834813). The species M. panshiensis sp. nov. shares several morphological characters with M. niccombsii, M. aquatica, M. fibulata and M. hoshinonis. These species can be distinguished based on physiological traits and pairwise rDNA sequence similarities. The study also describes for the first time the formation of teliospores by previously described M. arctica.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53433/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53433/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53433/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 08:29:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Delimitation, new species and teleomorph-anamorph relationships in Codinaea, Dendrophoma, Paragaeumannomyces and Striatosphaeria (Chaetosphaeriaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57824/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 74: 17-74</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.74.57824</p>
					<p>Authors: Martina Réblová, Jana Nekvindová, Jacques Fournier, Andrew N. Miller</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Chaetosphaeriaceae are a diverse group of pigmented, predominantly phialidic hyphomycetes comprised of several holomorphic genera including Chaetosphaeria, the most prominent genus of the family. Although the morphology of the teleomorphs of the majority of Chaetosphaeria is rather uniform, their associated anamorphs primarily exhibit the variability and evolutionary change observed in the genus. An exception from the morphological monotony among Chaetosphaeria species is a group characterised by scolecosporous, hyaline to light pink, multiseptate, asymmetrical ascospores and a unique three-layered ascomatal wall. Paragaeumannomyces sphaerocellularis, the type species of the genus, exhibits these morphological traits and is compared with similar Chaetosphaeria with craspedodidymum- and chloridium-like synanamorphs. Morphological comparison and phylogenetic analyses of the combined ITS-28S sequences of 35 isolates and vouchers with these characteristics revealed a strongly-supported, morphologically well-delimited clade in the Chaetosphaeriaceae containing 16 species. The generic name Paragaeumannomyces is applied to this monophyletic clade; eight new combinations and five new species, i.e. P. abietinus sp. nov., P. elegans sp. nov., P. granulatus sp. nov., P. sabinianus sp. nov. and P. smokiensis sp. nov., are proposed. A key to Paragaeumannomyces is provided. Using morphology, cultivation studies and phylogenetic analyses of ITS and 28S rDNA, two additional new species from freshwater and terrestrial habitats, Codinaea paniculata sp. nov. and Striatosphaeria castanea sp. nov., are described in the family. A codinaea-like anamorph of S. castanea forms conidia with setulae at each end in axenic culture; this feature expands the known morphology of Striatosphaeria. A chaetosphaeria-like teleomorph is experimentally linked to Dendrophoma cytisporoides, a sporodochial hyphomycete and type species of Dendrophoma, for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57824/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57824/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/57824/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 16:50:49 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and phylogenetic characterisations reveal three new species of Samsoniella (Cordycipitaceae, Hypocreales) from Guizhou, China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56655/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 74: 1-15</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.74.56655</p>
					<p>Authors: Wan-Hao Chen, Yan-Feng Han, Jian-Dong Liang, Wei-Yi Tian, Zong-Qi Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Samsoniella species have been found on lepidopteran larvae or pupae buried in soil or leaf litter. Three new species, Samsoniella hymenopterorum, S. coleopterorum and S. lepidopterorum, parasitic on hymenopteran larvae, coleopteran larvae and lepidopteran pupae, respectively, are reported. Morphological comparisons with extant species and DNA-based phylogenies from analysis of a multigene (ITS, RPB1, RPB2 and TEF) dataset supported the establishment of the new species. Unusually, all three new species have mononematous conidiophores. The new species are clearly distinct from other species in Samsoniella occurring in separate subclades.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56655/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56655/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56655/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 16:42:34 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Four new species of Trichoderma in the Harzianum clade from northern China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51424/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 73: 109-132</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.73.51424</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin Gu, Rui Wang, Quan Sun, Bing Wu, Jing-Zu Sun</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Harzianum clade of Trichoderma comprises many species, which are associated with a wide variety of substrates. In this study, four new species of Trichoderma, namely T. lentinulae, T. vermifimicola, T. xixiacum, and T. zelobreve, were encountered from a fruiting body and compost of Lentinula, soil, and vermicompost. Their colony and mycelial morphology, including features of asexual states, were described. For each species, their DNA sequences were obtained from three loci, the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) regions of the ribosomal DNA, the gene encoding the second largest nuclear RNA polymerase subunit (RPB2), the translation elongation factor 1-α encoding gene (TEF1-α). The analysis combining sequences of the three gene regions distinguished four new species in the Harzianum clade of Trichoderma. Among them, T. lentinulae and T. xixiacum clustered with T. lixii, from which these new species differ in having shorter phialides and smaller conidia. Additionally, T. lentinulae differs from T. xixiacum in forming phialides with inequilateral to a strongly-curved apex, cultural characteristics, and slow growth on PDA. Trichoderma vermifimicola is closely related to T. simmonsii, but it differs from the latter by producing phialides in verticillate whorls and smaller conidia. Trichoderma zelobreve is the sister species of T. breve but is distinguished from T. breve by producing shorter and narrower phialides, smaller conidia, and by forming concentric zones on agar plates. This study updates our knowledge of species diversity of Trichoderma.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51424/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51424/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51424/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 8 Oct 2020 13:38:03 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Conidiobolus sensu stricto from plant debris in eastern China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56905/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 73: 133-149</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.73.56905</p>
					<p>Authors: Yong Nie, Yue Cai, Yang Gao, De-Shui Yu, Zi-Min Wang, Xiao-Yong Liu, Bo Huang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Conidiobolus Bref. is widely distributed and the Conidiobolus sensu lato contained three other genera, Capillidium, Microconidiobolus and Neoconidiobolus. A molecular phylogeny based on the nuclear large subunit of rDNA (nucLSU), the mitochondrial small subunit of rDNA (mtSSU) and the translation elongation factor 1-alpha gene (TEF1) revealed three novel species within the clade of Conidiobolus s.s., i.e. C. bifurcatus sp. nov., C. taihushanensis sp. nov. and C. variabilis sp. nov. These three species were isolated from plant debris in eastern China. Morphologically, C. bifurcatus sp. nov. is characterised by its secondary conidiophores often branched at the tip to form two short stipes each bearing a secondary conidium. C. taihushanensis sp. nov. is different from the others in its straight apical mycelia and the production of 2–5 conidia. C. variabilis sp. nov. is distinctive because of its various shapes of primary conidia. All these three new taxa are illustrated herein with an update key to the species of the genus Conidiobolus s.s.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56905/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56905/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56905/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 8 Oct 2020 11:11:34 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Caliciopsis moriondi, a new species for a fungus long confused with the pine pathogen C. pinea</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53028/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 73: 87-108</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.73.53028</p>
					<p>Authors: Duccio Migliorini, Nicola Luchi, Alessia Lucia Pepori, Francesco Pecori, Chiara Aglietti, Fabio Maccioni, Isabel Munck, Stephen Wyka, Kirk Broders, Michael J. Wingfield, Alberto Santini</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Caliciopsis (Eurotiomycetes, Coryneliales) includes saprobic and plant pathogenic species. Caliciopsis canker is caused by Caliciopsis pinea Peck, a species first reported in the 19th century in North America. In recent years, increasing numbers of outbreaks of Caliciopsis canker have been reported on different Pinus spp. in the eastern USA. In Europe, the disease has only occasionally been reported causing cankers, mostly on Pinus radiata in stressed plantations. The aim of this study was to clarify the taxonomy of Caliciopsis specimens collected from infected Pinus spp. in Europe and North America using an integrative approach, combining morphology and phylogenetic analyses of three loci. The pathogenicity of the fungus was also considered. Two distinct groups were evident, based on morphology and multilocus phylogenetic analyses. These represent the known pathogen Caliciopsis pinea that occurs in North America and a morphologically similar, but phylogenetically distinct, species described here as Caliciopsis moriondi sp. nov., found in Europe and at least one location in eastern North America. Caliciopsis moriondi differs from C. pinea in various morphological features including the length of the ascomata, as well as their distribution on the stromata.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53028/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53028/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53028/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 08:31:16 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The fruticose genera in the Ramalinaceae (Ascomycota, Lecanoromycetes): their diversity and evolutionary history</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/47287/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 73: 1-68</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.73.47287</p>
					<p>Authors: Richard Spjut, Antoine Simon, Martin Guissard, Nicolas Magain, Emmanuël Sérusiaux</p>
					<p>Abstract: We present phylogenetic analyses of the fruticose Ramalinaceae based on extensive collections from many parts of the world, with a special focus on the Vizcaíno deserts in north-western Mexico and the coastal desert in Namibia. We generate a four-locus DNA sequence dataset for accessions of Ramalina and two additional loci for Niebla and Vermilacinia. Four genera are strongly supported: the subcosmopolitan Ramalina, the new genus Namibialina endemic to SW Africa, and a duo formed by Niebla and Vermilacinia, endemic to the New World except the sorediate V. zebrina that disjunctly occurs in Namibia. The latter three genera are restricted to coastal desert and chaparral where vegetation depends on moisture from ocean fog. Ramalina is subcosmopolitan and much more diverse in its ecology.        We show that Ramalina and its sister genus Namibialina diverged from each other at c. 48 Myrs, whereas Vermilacinia and Niebla split at c. 30 Myrs. The phylogeny of the fruticose genera remains unresolved to their ancestral crustose genera.        Species delimitation within Namibialina and Ramalina is rather straightforward. The phylogeny and taxonomy of Vermilacinia are fully resolved, except for the two youngest clades of corticolous taxa, and support current taxonomy, including four new taxa described here. Secondary metabolite variation in Niebla generally coincides with major clades which are comprised of species complexes with still unresolved phylogenetic relationships. A micro-endemism pattern of allopatric species is strongly suspected for both genera, except for the corticolous taxa within Vermilacinia. Both Niebla and saxicolous Vermilacinia have chemotypes unique to species clades that are largely endemic to the Vizcaíno deserts.        The following new taxa are described: Namibialina gen. nov. with N. melanothrix (comb. nov.) as type species, a single new species of Ramalina (R. krogiae) and four new species of Vermilacinia (V. breviloba, V. lacunosa, V. pustulata and V. reticulata). The new combination V. granulans is introduced. Two epithets are re-introduced for European Ramalina species: R. crispans (= R. peruviana auct. eur.) and R. rosacea (= R. bourgeana auct. p.p). A lectotype is designated for Vermilacinia procera. A key to saxicolous species of Vermilacinia is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/47287/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/47287/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/47287/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 14:49:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Neodactylariales, Neodactylariaceae (Dothideomycetes, Ascomycota): new order and family, with a new species from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54054/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 73: 69-85</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.73.54054</p>
					<p>Authors: Min Qiao, Hua Zheng, Ruili Lv, Zefen Yu</p>
					<p>Abstract: During a mycological survey of aquatic hyphomycetes on submerged decaying leaves in southwest China, a distinct new fungus was collected. The collection was cultured and sequenced and a BLAST search of its ITS and LSU sequence against data in GenBank revealed a dothideomycetous affiliation, with the closest related taxa in the genus Neodactylaria. Phylogenetic analyses of a multigene matrix containing sequences from four genes (LSU, SSU, rpb2, and tef1), representing broad groups of Dothideomycetes, revealed its placement within Dothideomycetes, but without a supported familial or ordinal affiliation. Based on further phylogenetic analyses and morphological investigations, the new fungus is described here as a new species of Neodactylaria, N. simaoensis sp. nov., and placed in a new family Neodactylariaceae fam. nov. and a new order Neodactylariales ord. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54054/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54054/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54054/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 08:57:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>When mycologists describe new species, not all relevant information is provided (clearly enough)</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56691/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 72: 109-128</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.72.56691</p>
					<p>Authors: Louisa Durkin, Tobias Jansson, Marisol Sanchez, Maryia Khomich, Martin Ryberg, Erik Kristiansson, R. Henrik Nilsson</p>
					<p>Abstract: Taxonomic mycology struggles with what seems to be a perpetual shortage of resources. Logically, fungal taxonomists should therefore leverage every opportunity to highlight and visualize the importance of taxonomic work, the usefulness of taxonomic data far beyond taxonomy, and the integrative and collaborative nature of modern taxonomy at large. Is mycology really doing that, though? In this study, we went through ten years’ worth (2009–2018) of species descriptions of extant fungal taxa – 1,097 studies describing at most ten new species – in five major mycological journals plus one plant journal. We estimated the frequency at which a range of key words, illustrations, and concepts related to ecology, geography, taxonomy, molecular data, and data availability were provided with the descriptions. We also considered a range of science-demographical aspects such as gender bias and the rejuvenation of taxonomy and taxonomists as well as public availability of the results. Our results show that the target audience of fungal species descriptions appears to be other fungal taxonomists, because many aspects of the new species were presented only implicitly, if at all. Although many of the parameters we estimated show a gradual, and in some cases marked, change for the better over time, they still paint a somewhat bleak picture of mycological taxonomy as a male-dominated field where the wants and needs of an extended target audience are often not understood or even considered. This study hopes to leave a mark on the way fungal species are described by putting the focus on ways in which fungal taxonomy can better anticipate the end users of species descriptions – be they mycologists, other researchers, the public at large, or even algorithms. In the end, fungal taxonomy, too, is likely to benefit from such measures.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56691/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56691/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56691/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 13:09:56 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Microdochium from Indocalamus longiauritus in south-western China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55445/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 72: 93-108</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.72.55445</p>
					<p>Authors: Shengting Huang, Jiwen Xia, Xiuguo Zhang, Wenxiu Sun, Zhuang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Microdochium species have often been reported as plant pathogens and saprophytes and are commonly isolated from some diseased plant hosts. The primary aim of the present study was to describe and illustrate two new Microdochium species isolated from the leaf spot of Indocalamus longiauritus in Yunnan Province, China, namely Microdochium yunnanense and M. indocalami, spp. nov., based on their morphology and multilocus phylogenetic analyses of the combined ITS, LSU, TUB2, and RPB2. DNA sequence data indicate that six strains represent three independent groups from related and similar species in Microdochium. Microdochium indocalami sp. nov. clustered with M. fisheri, M. lycopodinum, M. rhopalostylidis, and M. phragmitis. Microdochium yunnanense sp. nov. grouped with M. bolleyi. In addition, the strain SAUCC1017 is recorded as an unidentified species in Microdochium. Descriptions and illustrations of the new species in the genus and Microdochium sp. indet. are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55445/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55445/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55445/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:57:50 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomy of Verrucaria species characterised by large spores, perithecia leaving pits in the rock and a pale thin thallus in Finland</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56223/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 72: 43-92</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.72.56223</p>
					<p>Authors: Juha Pykälä, Annina Kantelinen, Leena Myllys</p>
					<p>Abstract: Species of Verrucaria, characterised by large spores (at least some spores exceeding 25 µm in length), perithecia leaving pits in the rock and a pale thin thallus, form a taxonomically-difficult and poorly-known group. In this study, such species occurring in Finland are revised, based on ITS sequences and morphology. Maximum likelihood analysis of ITS sequence data was used to examine if the species belong to the Thelidium group, as suggested by BLAST search. Twelve species are accepted in Finland: Verrucaria bifurcata sp. nov., V. cavernarum sp. nov., V. devergens, V. difficilis sp. nov., V. foveolata, V. fuscozonata sp. nov., V. karelica, V. kuusamoensis sp. nov., V. subdevergens sp. nov., V. subjunctiva, V. subtilis and V. vacillans sp. nov. Verrucaria foveolata is nested in V. subjunctiva in the phylogeny, but due to morphological and ecogeographical differences, the two taxa are treated as separate species pending further studies. Based on the analysis, the study species belong to the Thelidium group. The studied species show a rather high infraspecific morphological, but a low genetic variation. Furthermore, they show considerable overlap in their morphology and many specimens cannot be reliably identified, based on morphology only. All species are restricted to calcareous rocks. Verrucaria alpigena, V. cinereorufa and V. hochstetteri are excluded from the lichen flora of Finland. Verrucaria grossa is considered a species with unresolved identity. Verrucaria foveolata and V. subtilis are rather common on calcareous rocks of Finland while V. devergens and V. kuusamoensis are restricted to northern Finland. Verrucaria subjunctiva occurs mainly in northern Finland. Verrucaria bifurcata has been found only from southern Finland. Verrucaria difficilis has few localities both in SW and NE Finland. Verrucaria vacillans is restricted to calcareous rocks (dolomite) on the mountains of the NW corner of Finland. Verrucaria fuscozonata, V. karelica and V. subdevergens occur only in the Oulanka area in NE Finland. A lectotype is designated for V. subjunctiva. The morphology of the Finnish species was compared with 51 European species of Verrucaria presumably belonging to the Thelidium group.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56223/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56223/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56223/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 2 Sep 2020 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Phylogeny- and morphology-based recognition of new species in the spider-parasitic genus Gibellula (Hypocreales, Cordycipitaceae) from Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55088/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 72: 17-42</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.72.55088</p>
					<p>Authors: Wilawan Kuephadungphan, Kanoksri Tasanathai, Booppa Petcharad, Artit Khonsanit, Marc Stadler, J. Jennifer Luangsa-ard</p>
					<p>Abstract: Thailand is known to be a part of what is called the Indo-Burma biodiversity hotspot, hosting a vast array of organisms across its diverse ecosystems. This is reflected by the increasing number of new species described over time, especially fungi. However, a very few fungal species from the specialized spider-parasitic genus Gibellula have ever been reported from this region. A survey of invertebrate-pathogenic fungi in Thailand over several decades has led to the discovery of a number of fungal specimens with affinities to this genus. Integration of morphological traits into multi-locus phylogenetic analysis uncovered four new species: G. cebrennini, G. fusiformispora, G. pigmentosinum, and G. scorpioides. All these appear to be exclusively linked with torrubiella-like sexual morphs with the presence of granulomanus-like asexual morph in G. pigmentosinum and G. cebrennini. A remarkably high host specificity of these new species towards their spider hosts was revealed, and for the first time, evidence is presented for manipulation of host behavior in G. scorpioides.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55088/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55088/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55088/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 2 Sep 2020 08:23:13 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Junghuhnia (Polyporales, Basidiomycota) from China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51872/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 72: 1-16</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.72.51872</p>
					<p>Authors: Ping Du, Wu Fang, Xue-Mei Tian</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, taxonomic and phylogenetic analyses of Junghuhnia were performed. Three new species were characterised according to morphological characteristics and molecular phylogenetic analysis using ITS and nLSU sequences. They are J. austrosinensis sp. nov., J. nandinae sp. nov. and J. subcollabens sp. nov. Junghuhnia austrosinensis is characterised by resupinate, thin basidiomata with white to buff-yellow hymenophore, small pores (9–11 per mm), clamped generative hyphae possessing hymenial cystidia, ellipsoid basidiospores (2.5–3 × 1.7–2 µm) and growth on fallen bamboo or angiosperm branch. Junghuhnia nandinae is characterised by resupinate basidiomata with pink to salmon pores and a distinct white margin, clamp generative hyphae, interwoven tramal hyphae, ellipsoid basidiospores measuring 2.6–3.2 × 1.8–2 µm and growth on Nandina domestica. Junghuhnia subcollabens is characterised by resupinate basidiomata with pale salmon to brownish vinaceous hymenophore, small pores (10–12 per mm), generative hyphae with simple septa and clamp connections, interwoven tramal hyphae, lunate basidiospores measuring 2.9–3.4 × 1.6–1.8 µm and thriving on rotten wood of angiosperms.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51872/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51872/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51872/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 08:46:56 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Ascomycetes from the Qilian Mountains, China – Hypocreales</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55009/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 71: 119-137</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.71.55009</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhao-Qing Zeng, Huan-Di Zheng, Xin-Cun Wang, Sheng-Long Wei, Wen-Ying Zhuang</p>
					<p>Abstract: To investigate fungi from the Qilian Mountains in Gansu Province, ascomycetous specimens were collected and hypocrealean fungi were examined. Eighteen species belonging to six genera in the families Hypocreaceae and Nectriaceae were identified, including 11 species of Hypomyces and Trichoderma in Hypocreaceae and seven species of Nectria, Stylonectria, Thelonectria, and Thyronectria in Nectriaceae. Among them, Stylonectria qilianshanensis and Trichoderma gansuanum are new to science. DNA sequence analyses of combined ACL1, ITS, RPB2, and TEF1 regions confirmed their taxonomic placements. Morphological distinctions between the new species and their close relatives are discussed. Hypomyces tremellicola is reported for the first time in China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55009/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55009/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55009/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 09:12:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new Scheffersomyces species associated with insects and rotting wood in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56168/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 71: 87-99</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.71.56168</p>
					<p>Authors: Ran-Ran Jia, Shi-Long Lv, Chun-Yue Chai, Feng-Li Hui</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three species of Scheffersomyces were identified during a diversity study of yeasts. All three are associated with insects and rotting wood in China. Phylogenetic analyses of a genomic dataset combining ITS and nrLSU revealed that these new collections are distinct from known species, thus three new species are introduced i.e. S. jinghongensis, S. paraergatensis, and S. anoplophorae. In our phylogenetic analyses, Scheffersomyces jinghongensis possesses a strong independent lineage and is closely related to S. titanus. S. paraergatensis is closely related to S. ergatensis, while S. anoplophorae is related to S. stambukii. Several differences in physiological traits and molecular data indicate that S. jinghongensis, S. paraergatensis, and S. anoplophorae are three newly identified species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56168/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56168/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/56168/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 5 Aug 2020 13:16:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Multi-gene phylogenetic evidence suggests Dictyoarthrinium belongs in Didymosphaeriaceae (Pleosporales, Dothideomycetes) and Dictyoarthrinium musae sp. nov. on Musa from Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55493/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 71: 101-118</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.71.55493</p>
					<p>Authors: Binu C. Samarakoon, Dhanushka N. Wanasinghe, Milan C. Samarakoon, Rungtiwa Phookamsak, Eric H.C. McKenzie, Putarak Chomnunti, Kevin D. Hyde, Saisamorn Lumyong, Samantha C. Karunarathna</p>
					<p>Abstract: Dead leaves of Musa sp. (banana) were collected in northern Thailand during an investigation of saprobic fungi. Preliminary morphological observations revealed that three specimens belong to Dictyoarthrinium. Phylogenetic analyses of combined SSU, LSU, ITS and tef1-α sequence data revealed that Dictyoarthrinium forms a clade in Didymosphaeriaceae (Massarineae, Pleosporales, Dothideomycetes) sister to Spegazzinia. Based on contrasting morphological features with the extant taxa of Dictyoarthrinium, coupled with the multigene analyses, Dictyoarthrinium musae sp. nov. is introduced herein. Our study provides the first detailed molecular investigation for Dictyoarthrinium and supports its placement in Didymosphaeriaceae (Massarineae, Pleosporales, Dothideomycetes). Previously, Dictyoarthrinium was classified in Apiosporaceae (Xylariales, Sordariomycetes).</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55493/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55493/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55493/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 5 Aug 2020 08:19:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diversity of Akanthomyces on moths (Lepidoptera) in Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55126/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 71: 1-22</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.71.55126</p>
					<p>Authors: Arifah Nur Aini, Suchada Mongkolsamrit, Wijanarka Wijanarka, Donnaya Thanakitpipattana, J. Jennifer Luangsa-ard, Anto Budiharjo</p>
					<p>Abstract: Akanthomyces is a genus of invertebrate-pathogenic fungi from the family Cordycipitaceae (Ascomycota, Hypocreales). Its species occurs on two different types of hosts, spiders and insects, and in the latter case specifically Lepidoptera adults. Three new species of Akanthomyces, A. noctuidarum, A. pyralidarum, and A. tortricidarum occurring on adult moths from Thailand are proposed based on the differences of their morphological characteristics and molecular data. Phylogenetic analyses using a combined dataset, including the internal transcribed spacer regions, the large subunit of the ribosomal DNA, translation elongation factor 1-α, the largest subunit of RNA polymerase II, and the second largest subunit of RNA polymerase II, support the delimitation of these new species in Akanthomyces.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55126/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55126/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/55126/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 09:04:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Checklist of thallus-forming Laboulbeniomycetes from Belgium and the Netherlands, including Hesperomyces halyziae and Laboulbenia quarantenae spp. nov.</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53421/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 71: 23-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.71.53421</p>
					<p>Authors: Danny Haelewaters, André De Kesel</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this paper we present an updated checklist of thallus-forming Laboulbeniomycetes (Ascomycota, Pezizomycotina), that is, the orders Herpomycetales and Laboulbeniales, from Belgium and the Netherlands. Two species are newly described based on morphology, molecular data (ITS, LSU ribosomal DNA) and ecology (host association). These are Hesperomyces halyziae on Halyzia sedecimguttata (Coleoptera, Coccinellidae) from both countries and Laboulbenia quarantenae on Bembidion biguttatum (Coleoptera, Carabidae) from Belgium. In addition, nine new country records are presented. For Belgium: Laboulbenia aubryi on Amara aranea (Coleoptera, Carabidae) and Rhachomyces spinosus on Syntomus foveatus (Coleoptera, Carabidae). For the Netherlands: Chitonomyces melanurus on Laccophilus minutus (Coleoptera, Dytiscidae), Euphoriomyces agathidii on Agathidium laevigatum (Coleoptera, Leiodidae), Laboulbenia fasciculata on Omophron limbatum (Coleoptera, Carabidae), Laboulbenia metableti on Syntomus foveatus and S. truncatellus (Coleoptera, Carabidae), Laboulbenia pseudomasei on Pterostichus melanarius (Coleoptera, Carabidae), Rhachomyces canariensis on Trechus obtusus (Coleoptera, Carabidae), and Stigmatomyces hydrelliae on Hydrellia albilabris (Diptera, Ephydridae). Finally, an identification key to 140 species of thallus-forming Laboulbeniomycetes in Belgium and the Netherlands is provided. Based on the combined data, we are able to identify mutual gaps that need to be filled as well as weigh the impact of chosen strategies (fieldwork, museum collections) and techniques in these neighboring countries. The aim of this work is to serve as a reference for studying Laboulbeniomycetes fungi in Europe.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53421/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53421/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53421/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 09:01:52 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The genus Clavariadelphus (Clavariadelphaceae, Gomphales) in China</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54149/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 70: 89-121</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.70.54149</p>
					<p>Authors: Hong-Yan Huang, Jie Zhao, Ping Zhang, Zai-Wei Ge, Xian Li, Li-Ping Tang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Clavariadelphus species (Clavariadelphaceae, Gomphales) in China were examined using morphology, molecular phylogenetic analyses of ITS data and chemical reactions. Eleven taxa were identified in China, including four species known previously to occur in China (C. griseoclavus, C. ligula, C. sachalinensis and C. yunnanensis), two new record species from China (C. elongatus and C. himalayensis), four novel species (C. alpinus, C. amplus, C. gansuensis and C. khinganensis) and one species that could not be described due to the paucity of material. Finally, we also provided a taxonomic key for the identification of Clavariadelphus species in China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54149/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54149/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54149/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 08:39:25 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Additions to Phaeosphaeriaceae (Pleosporales): Elongaticollum gen. nov., Ophiosphaerella taiwanensis sp. nov., Phaeosphaeriopsis beaucarneae sp. nov. and a new host record of Neosetophoma poaceicola from Musaceae</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53674/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 70: 59-88</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.70.53674</p>
					<p>Authors: Danushka S. Tennakoon, Kasun M. Thambugala, Dhanushka N. Wanasinghe, Eleni Gentekaki, Itthayakorn Promputtha, Chang-Hsin Kuo, Kevin D. Hyde</p>
					<p>Abstract: A novel ascomycetous genus, Elongaticollum, occurring on leaf litter of Hedychium coronarium (Zingiberaceae) in Taiwan, is described and illustrated. Elongaticollum is characterized by dark brown to black, superficial, obpyriform, pycnidial conidiomata with a distinct elongate neck, and oval to oblong, hyaline, aseptate conidia. Phylogenetic analyses (maximum likelihood, maximum parsimony and Bayesian) of combined ITS, LSU, SSU and tef1-α sequence data revealed Elongaticollum as a distinct genus within the family Phaeosphaeriaceae with high statistical support. In addition, Ophiosphaerella taiwanensis and Phaeosphaeriopsis beaucarneae are described as new species from dead leaves of Agave tequilana and Beaucarnea recurvata (Asparagaceae), respectively. Neosetophoma poaceicola is reported as a new host record from dead leaves of Musa acuminata (Musaceae). Newly described taxa are compared with other similar species and comprehensive descriptions and micrographs are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53674/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53674/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/53674/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 08:22:50 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new lichenized fungus, Lecanora baekdudaeganensis, from South Korea, with a taxonomic key for Korean Lecanora species</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51569/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 70: 39-58</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.70.51569</p>
					<p>Authors: Beeyoung Gun Lee, Jae-Seoun Hur</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lecanora baekdudaeganensis Lee &amp; Hur is described as a new lichenized fungus from Baekdudaegan Mountains, South Korea. The new species is classified into the Lecanora subfusca group – allophana type and distinguishable from Lecanora imshaugii Brodo by a darker thallus, brownish disc, K–insoluble granules on the surface of the epihymenium, shorter hypothecium, and the presence of oil droplets in the apothecial section. Molecular analyses employing internal transcribed spacer (ITS) and mitochondrial small subunit (mtSSU) sequences strongly support Lecanora baekdudaeganensis as a distinct species in the genus Lecanora. A surrogate key is provided to assist in the identification of all 52 taxa in the genus Lecanora of Korea.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51569/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51569/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/51569/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 09:06:19 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomy and phylogenetic appraisal of Spegazzinia musae sp. nov. and S. deightonii (Didymosphaeriaceae, Pleosporales) on Musaceae from Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/52043/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 70: 19-37</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.70.52043</p>
					<p>Authors: Binu C. Samarakoon, Rungtiwa Phookamsak, Dhanushka N. Wanasinghe, Putarak Chomnunti, Kevin D. Hyde, Eric H. C. Mckenzie, Itthayakorn Promputtha, Jian-Chu Xu, Yun-Ju Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Tropical plants host a range of fungal niches including endophytes, pathogens, epiphytes and saprobes. A study undertaken to discover the saprobic fungal species associated with Musa sp. (banana) from northern Thailand found two hyphomycetous taxa of Spegazzinia (Didymosphaeriaceae, Pleosporales). These were collected during the dry season and their morpho-molecular taxonomic relationships were investigated. Based on phylogenetic analysis of combined SSU, LSU, ITS and TEF1-α sequence data (77% ML, 0.99 BYPP) and contrasting morphological features to the sister taxon, we introduce Spegazzinia musae as a novel species from a decaying leaf of Musa sp. Details on the taxonomy, ecology and geographical distribution of Spegazzinia species are provided. In addition, we report S. deightonii as a new host record from Musa sp. Our data further validate the taxonomic placement of Spegazzinia in Didymosphaeriaceae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/52043/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/52043/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/52043/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 17:01:04 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morpho-molecular diversity of Linocarpaceae (Chaetosphaeriales): Claviformispora gen. nov. from decaying branches of Phyllostachys heteroclada</title>
		    <link>https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54231/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>MycoKeys 70: 1-17</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/mycokeys.70.54231</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiu-Lan Xu, Chun-Lin Yang, Rajesh Jeewon, Dhanushka N. Wanasinghe, Ying-Gao Liu, Qian-Gang Xiao</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this paper, Claviformispora gen. nov. in Linocarpaceae is introduced from Phyllostachys heteroclada in Sichuan Province, China. The new genus is characterised by its distinct morphological characters, such as ostiole with periphyses, asci with a thick doughnut-shaped, J- apical ring and clavate ascospore without septum-like band and appendage. Maximum Likelihood and Bayesian Inference phylogenetic analyses, based on DNA sequence data from ITS, LSU, SSU and TEF-1α regions, provide further evidence that the fungus is a distinct genus within this family. The new genus is compared with similar genera, such as Linocarpon and Neolinocarpon. Descriptions, illustrations and notes are provided for the new taxon.</p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54231/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54231/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://mycokeys.pensoft.net/article/54231/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:12:51 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
	