
<rss version="0.91">
    <channel>
        <title>Latest Articles from PhytoKeys</title>
        <description>Latest 100 Articles from PhytoKeys</description>
        <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:59:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Pensoft FeedCreator</generator>
        <image>
            <url>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/i/logo.jpg</url>
            <title>Latest Articles from PhytoKeys</title>
            <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Feed provided by https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/. Click to visit.]]></description>
        </image>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Vicia mingyueshanensis (Fabeae, Papilionoideae, Fabaceae), a new species from western Jiangxi, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71960/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 187: 71-76</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.187.71960</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi-Yong Xiao, Xiao-Chun Li, Ying Luo, Chuan-Sheng Zeng, Bang-Gui Qiu, Fu-Liang Cao</p>
					<p>Abstract: Vicia mingyueshanensis, a new species from the Mingyue Mountain Region of western Jiangxi, China, is described and illustrated. It is a perennial climbing liana that always links to riparian woods. A morphological comparison indicated that the new species is closely similar to Vicia taipaica K. T. Fu and Vicia dichroantha Diels; however, it differs from the other two species by several salient characters, such as plant indumentum, stipule shape, corolla colour, bractlet shape and calyx shape. Photographs, a preliminary conservation assessment, table of morphological characters and distribution map comparing this new species to two morphologically-similar species are also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71960/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71960/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71960/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 16:00:36 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿New and poorly known “araphid” diatom species (Bacillariophyta) from regions near Lake Titicaca, South America and a discussion on the continued use of morphological characters in “araphid” diatom taxonomy</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73338/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 187: 23-70</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.187.73338</p>
					<p>Authors: Eduardo A. Morales, Carlos E. Wetzel, Luc Ector</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on two Andean Altiplano samples and on light and scanning electron microscopy analyses, we present six new species of “araphid” diatoms in the genus Pseudostaurosira, P. aedes sp. nov., P. frankenae sp. nov., P. heteropolaris sp. nov., P. oblonga sp. nov., P. occulta sp. nov., and P. pulchra sp. nov. Additional data are provided for four other known taxa, Nanofrustulum cataractarum, N. rarissimum, P. sajamaensis and P. vulpina, the latter species corresponding to a stat. nov. based on a variety of P. laucensis. Each taxon is described morphologically and compared with closely related published taxa, using characters such as axial area, virgae, vimines, areolar shape, volae, internal striae depositions, spines, flaps and apical pore fields, which are not usually used for species distinction within the genus. It is our intention that the detailed morphological descriptions of each taxon and the elaborate comparative tables we provide serve as a basis for correction of neo and paleo-databases for the Altiplano to produce a better account of autecological data and ecological change in the region. Some arguments for our continued use of a morphologically based approach are given in the context of rapid environmental degradation in the Andes and the difficulties in applying molecular approaches in countries such as Bolivia.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73338/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73338/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73338/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 16:00:04 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Primulina scutellifolia, a new species of Gesneriaceae from southern Vietnam</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77856/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 187: 15-21</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.187.77856</p>
					<p>Authors: Ngoc Long Vu, Tran Quoc Trung Nguyen, Gioi Tran, Quoc Dat Nguyen, Hong Truong Luu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Primulina scutellifolia is described as a new species from Khanh Hoa Province, southern Central Vietnam. It is distinct in the genus in having scutellate leaves that make it a highly potential ornamental plant. The new species looks like P. annamensis in general shapes, sizes and colours of habit, inflorescence, flower, and leaf but is distinguishable by adaxially glabrous and abaxially strigose leaves with serrate margins, scutellate leaf blade and appressed downwards tomentose petiole, sparsely glandular hairs on apical 1/2 of the gynoecium and trapeziform one-lipped stigma with slightly emarginated apex.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77856/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77856/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77856/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 14:42:54 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Typification of 14 names in the Dianthus virgineus group (Caryophyllaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75534/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 187: 1-14</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.187.75534</p>
					<p>Authors: Gianniantonio Domina, Giovanni Astuti, Gianluigi Bacchetta, Giulio Barone, Ivana Rešetnik, Ana Terlević, Melanie Thiébaut, Lorenzo Peruzzi</p>
					<p>Abstract: The nomenclature of 14 taxa from Central and Southern Europe within the Dianthus virgineus group is discussed. Dianthus aggericola Jord., D. collivagus Jord., D. consimilis Jord., D. orophilus Jord., D. saxicola Jord., D. juratensis Jord. are here lectotypified by specimens from the Jordan herbarium in LY, while D. godronianus Jord. by a specimen in P. Dianthus subacaulis Vill. is neotypified by a specimen collected on Mont Ventoux (S. France) and housed in MPU. For D. sylvestris Wulfen, a lectotype is here designated and its previous neotypification is discussed. Dianthus caryophyllus var. tenuifolius Moris, D. caryophyllus f. minor Moris and D. sylvestris var. garganicus Ten. are lectotypified by specimens housed in herbarium Moris (TO) and herbarium Tenore (K). Dianthus virgineus var. tergestinus Rchb. is lectotypified by a drawing from the Icones florae Germanicae &amp; Helveticae, while D. contractus var. evolutus Lojac. is neotypified by a specimen in P. For each taxon the currently accepted name is provided including new synonymies. The type indication is followed by nomenclatural and taxonomic notes, in which the original material found is commented and the reasons for the identification of the types are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75534/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75534/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75534/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 14:41:57 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Phelypaea boissieri f. lutea (Orobanchaceae), a peculiar new form from Turkey and typification of the name of this species</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77575/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 159-167</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.77575</p>
					<p>Authors: Ümit Subaşı, Óscar Sánchez Pedraja, Renata Piwowarczyk</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Phelypaea includes three holoparasite species with one of the most intense red flowers among all plants worldwide. So far, there are few references to other colour taxa of this genus. We describe a new yellow-coloured form, Phelypaea boissieri f. lutea, from Hakkari province in the Cilo Mountains of SE Turkey, found at an altitude of 2,470 m. In typical P. boissieri, here typified by us, the flowers are deeply red, and stems, calyx and scales are red to brown, or rarely pale-brown, whereas in the entire population of f. lutea the corolla, calyx, and scales are yellow to orange with black folds in the corolla, while only the stem is brownish.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77575/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77575/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/77575/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 13:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿On the identity of Thymus humifusus var. aureopunctatus (Lamiaceae) and taxonomic notes on the Th. richardii complex</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75412/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 139-158</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.75412</p>
					<p>Authors: Llorenç Sáez, Faruk Bogunić, Salvatore Cambria, Jesús Riera, Sandro Bogdanović</p>
					<p>Abstract: The name Thymus humifusus var. aureopunctatus, described from Bosnia and Herzegovina, is lectotypified, and its taxonomic value is discussed. Thymus richardii subsp. richardii is currently considered an endemic subspecies common to Mallorca (Balearic Islands) and Bosnia and Herzegovina from the Balkan Peninsula. Specimens identified as Th. richardii from both Balearic Islands and Bosnia and Herzegovina were studied to determine if they are indeed the same taxonomic entity. Detailed micromorphological observations and morphometric analysis, suggest that the Balkan plants (Th. humifusus var. aureopunctatus) and the Majorcan populations (Th. richardii subsp. richardii) are clearly separate entities. For the former name, based on morphological, phytochemical, biogeographical and present results, we propose the subspecific rank, as Th. richardii subsp. aureopunctatus comb. &amp; stat. nov. Full descriptions of all five subspecies currently accepted within Th. richardii are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75412/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75412/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75412/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:49:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Systematic reinstatement of highly sacred Ficus krishnae based on differences in morphology and DNA barcoding from Ficus benghalensis (Moraceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/74086/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 121-138</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.74086</p>
					<p>Authors: Karthikeyan Mahima, Senthilkumar Umapathy, Jana Venkata Sudhakar, Ramalingam Sathishkumar</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ficus krishnae is considered as native to India and is well-known for the peculiarity in nature of its cup-shaped leaves where both the vernacular name (Krishna Fig) and specific epithet were derived. The taxonomic status of Ficus krishnae is still unclear and currently treated as a subspecies or variety under Ficus benghalensis. In the present study, morphological characters and molecular analysis were employed to address their species delimitation. The spacer markers ITS2 and trnH-psbA were used for constructing phylogenetic trees along with morphometric analysis. Ficus krishnae distinctly differs from Ficus benghalensis by having cup-forming leaves and the nature of the aerial roots, stipules, petioles, ostiolar bracts of the receptacle, DNA content, chromosome differences and nodal anatomy. The results showed that the highest divergence is observed in trnH-psbA (20.8 ± 12.2), followed by ITS2 (5.7 ± 3.2). The phylogenetic tree construction using Bayesian analysis showed a divergent boundary between the two species suggesting that F. krishnae could be an independent species, not a variety of F. benghalensis. The present study’s findings support the view that these two floras can be treated as different species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/74086/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/74086/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/74086/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:48:49 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Dipteris shenzhenensis, a new endangered species of Dipteridaceae from Shenzhen, southern China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73739/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 111-120</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.73739</p>
					<p>Authors: Zuo-Ying Wei, Yu-Feng Gu, Zeng-Qiang Xia, Li-Jun Chen, Ting Wang, Shou-Zhou Zhang, Guo-Hua Zhao, Jian-Bing Chen, Jian-Guo Cao, Yue-Hong Yan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Dipteris shenzhenensis, a new species of ferns from Shenzhen, Guangdong, southern China, is identified and described. It closely resembles D. chinensis but possesses several unique traits, such as long rhizome scales, castaneous stipe, and abaxially pale fronds with two fan-shaped fronds connected by a broad wing. Molecular evidence showed that D. shenzhenensis is allied to D. conjugata, whereas it has morphologically significant differences (P &lt; 0.05) on the basis of quantitative trait statistical analysis. Overall, the morphological evidence, taken together with the result of cpDNA indicated that D. shenzhenensis is a distinct species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73739/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73739/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73739/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:48:11 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Notes on Brazilian Pachira (Malvaceae, Bombacoideae) II: Additional typifications and new synonymies</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71445/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 53-72</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.71445</p>
					<p>Authors: Jefferson Carvalho-Sobrinho, Vânia Nobuko Yoshikawa, Laurence J. Dorr</p>
					<p>Abstract: The typification and status of the names of 14 species of Pachira (Malvaceae: Bombacoideae) found in Brazil are discussed, including type material from Brazil, the Guianas, Colombia, Venezuela, and cultivated in Algeria. We designate 11 lectotypes, three neotypes, and four epitypes for these names. Six names are newly considered to be synonyms of the species accepted here. The results support a forthcoming taxonomic treatment of Pachira for the Flora of Brazil.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71445/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71445/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71445/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 6 Dec 2021 17:06:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic studies on the genus Isotrema (Aristolochiaceae) from China III: I. pseudohei, a new species from Yunnan, Southwest China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63543/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 43-52</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.63543</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun Wang, Guo-Dong Li, Juan-Juan Yang, Bin Shen, Chun-Xia Pu, Xin-Xin Zhu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Isotrema pseudohei, a new species from Yunnan, Southwest China, is described and illustrated. It is morphologically similar to I. hei and I. moupinense, but differs from the former in the colour of flower and throat, the size of throat and the shape of gynostemium lobes, and from the latter in the shape of lamina and gynostemium lobes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63543/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63543/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63543/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 6 Dec 2021 17:05:53 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿ Coleus (Lamiaceae) in Peninsular Malaysia including two new species</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62018/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 93-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.62018</p>
					<p>Authors: Ruth Kiew, Imin Kamin</p>
					<p>Abstract: In Peninsular Malaysia, Coleus is represented by five species. Two, C. hairulii Kiew and C. rafidahiae Kiew, are new species. Both are narrowly endemic and restricted to limestone hills as is C. kunstleri (Prain) A.J.Paton. All three are Critically Endangered. Coleus scutellarioides (L.) Benth., although widespread, is probably not indigenous. It is also a common ornamental, while C. monostachyus (P.Beauv.) A.J.Paton is a recent introduction that has spread rapidly and threatens to become a troublesome weed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62018/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62018/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62018/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 6 Dec 2021 12:20:51 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Morphological and molecular evidence reveals three new species of Lithocarpus (Fagaceae) from Bidoup-Nui Ba National Park, Vietnam</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69878/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 73-92</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.69878</p>
					<p>Authors: Nguyen Van Ngoc, Hoang Thi Binh, Ai Nagahama, Shuichiro Tagane, Hironori Toyama, Ayumi Matsuo, Yoshihisa Suyama, Tetsukazu Yahara</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species, Lithocarpus bidoupensis Ngoc &amp; Tagane, L. congtroiensis Ngoc &amp; Yahara, and L. hongiaoensis Ngoc &amp; Binh are described from Bidoup-Nui Ba National Park, Central Highland of Vietnam. Morphological analyses and Maximum likelihood tree based on genome-wide SNPs support the distinction of those species from the previously known taxa in the region. The three new species are considered to be endemic to the Bidoup-Nui Ba National Park and the preliminary conservation status for each species is evaluated as Critically Endangered.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69878/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69878/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69878/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 6 Dec 2021 12:20:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Materials to the revision of the genus Cranichis (Orchidaceae) in Bolivia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71499/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 11-41</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.71499</p>
					<p>Authors: Marta Kolanowska, Przemysław Baranow, Sławomir Nowak, Alfredo Fuentes</p>
					<p>Abstract: The diversity of Cranichis in Bolivia is evaluated. An updated key for identifying species is provided. Morphological characteristics of 15 species of Bolivian Cranichis are presented together with illustrations of their floral segments. The occurrence of C. diphylla, C. lehmannii, and C. muscosa in this country was not confirmed. In our opinion the previously published Bolivian record for C. polyantha is doubtful. For the first time, C. badia and C. longipetiolata are reported in this country. Two new species of Cranichis are described.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71499/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71499/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71499/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 09:14:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Glossoloma wiehleri (Gesneriaceae), a new species from the northwestern Andes of Ecuador</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73554/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 186: 1-9</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.186.73554</p>
					<p>Authors: John L. Clark, Francisco Tobar</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Glossoloma is described from the western Andean slopes of the Pichincha Province in northern Ecuador. Glossoloma wiehleri J.L.Clark &amp; Tobar is differentiated from all other congeners by an epiphytic habit, elongate scandent shoots that exceed four meters in length, and coriaceous leaves with a velutinous indument on the lower leaf surface. The new species is illustrated, featured with field images from recent expeditions, and assigned the category of Endangered (EN) according to IUCN Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73554/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73554/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73554/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 09:04:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Primulina silaniae sp. nov. (Gesneriaceae) from the limestone area of Guizhou Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72099/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 123-130</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.72099</p>
					<p>Authors: Jin-Quan Zhang, Hong Huang, Mei-Jun Li, Mei Huang, Quan-Yuan Li, Yu-Lu Zhou, Yi Chen, Fang Wen, Xin-Xiang Bai</p>
					<p>Abstract: Primulina silaniae X.X.Bai &amp; F.Wen, a new species of Primulina Hance (Gesneriaceae) from the limestone area of Wangmo County, Guizhou Province, is described and illustrated. The new species is similar to P. spiradiclioides Z.B.Xin &amp; F.Wen, but can be easily distinguished from the latter by a combination of characteristics, especially in the lateral veins of its leaf and floral shape and tube. At present, three populations in one locality of this new taxon were found, totaling about 600 mature individuals. According to the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria (Version 3.1), the species is provisionally assessed as Vulnerable [VU D1].</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72099/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72099/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72099/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 16:14:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Lectotypification of Chamaecyparis hodginsii of the Cupressaceae</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75796/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 117-122</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.75796</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi Yang, Yong Yang, Keith Rushforth</p>
					<p>Abstract: Recent phylogenetic studies have suggested that the monotypic Fokienia A.Henry &amp; H.H.Thomas is nested within Chamaecyparis Spach, which is in agreement with separate morphological studies. Here the authors confirm a previous taxonomic treatment that incorporated Fokienia hodginsii (Dunn) A.Henry &amp; H.H.Thomas into Chamaecyparis based on the monophyly requirement of taxonomy, i.e. Chamaecyparis hodginsii (Dunn) Rushforth. In addition, the type collection of the basionym Cupressus hodginsii Dunn was found to contain three sheets of specimens, one in K including a vegetative branch (K000088294) and a separate ovulate cone (K001090486), a second one in A (A00022477), and a third one in IBSC (IBSC0016081). All three specimens are marked with Hongkong Herbarium No. 3505, but only the two specimens in K and IBSC possess similar handwriting of “Cupressus hodginsii Dunn”. The two specimens should be considered as syntypes according to the Shenzhen Code. The specimen in K is better preserved but it is a mixture according to the collection label: cones from Foochow (Fuzhou) and foliage from Yenping (Nanping). We lectotypified the name Cupressus hodginsii with K000088294 because the specimen is well preserved and has enough characters for identification. Moreover, an ovulate cone (K001090486) is on the same sheet.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75796/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75796/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75796/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 09:00:28 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Calceolaria flavida (Calceolariaceae) a new endemic species to central Chile</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71755/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 99-116</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.71755</p>
					<p>Authors: Nicolás Lavandero, Ludovica Santilli, Fernanda Pérez</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Calceolaria sect. Cheiloncos endemic to central Chile is described. A comparison with the morphologically similar species Calceolaria asperula and Calceolaria petioalaris is made, and a key as well as detailed images to differentiate them is provided. The species is only known from the Natural Sanctuary Cerro El Roble, which is part of the coastal mountain range of central Chile and can be considered as Critically Endangered (CR) under the IUCN categories and criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71755/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71755/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71755/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 08:23:52 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Studies in Austral Bryaceae (Bryopsida). III. A Preliminary Account with Keys to Rosulabryum J.R. Spence in Chile</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70407/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 87-98</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.70407</p>
					<p>Authors: John R. Spence</p>
					<p>Abstract: A preliminary study of the genus Rosulabryum J.R. Spence in Chile is presented, with brief species descriptions, notes on ecology and distributions, and a taxonomic key. The following 12 species are confirmed with vouchered specimens; Rosulabryum andicola (Hook.) Ochyra, Rosulabryum billarderii (Schwägr.) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum campylothecium (Taylor) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum capillare (Hedw.) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum coloratum (Müll. Hal.) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum densifolium (Brid.) Ochyra, Rosulabryum longidens (Thér.) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum macrophyllum (Cardot &amp; Broth.) Ochyra, Rosulabryum perlimbatum (Cardot) Ochyra, Rosulabryum puconense (Herzog &amp; Thér.) J.R. Spence, Rosulabryum rubens (Mitt.) J.R. Spence, and Rosulabryum torquescens (Bruch ex De Not.) J.R. Spence. Rosulabryum canariense (Brid.) Ochyra is tentatively excluded as the Chilean material can be referred to R. coloratum. Similarly, Rosulabryum viridescens (Welw. &amp; Duby) Ochyra is tentatively excluded since the Chilean plants do not match the African type, but instead appear to be atypical plants of R. campylothecium.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70407/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70407/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70407/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 19:30:53 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Leaf epidermal micromorphology in Aspidistra (Asparagaceae): diversity and taxonomic significance</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72259/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 65-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.72259</p>
					<p>Authors: Nikolay A. Vislobokov, Long-Fei Fu, Yi-Gang Wei, Maxim S. Nuraliev</p>
					<p>Abstract: Micromorphological characters of leaf epidermis were investigated in 69 species of Aspidistra using scanning electron microscopy. Sculpture of epidermis varies from smooth to verrucose and rugose in the genus. The abaxial epidermis of some species bears papillae, whereas the adaxial surface uniformly lacks the papillae. Sculpture type of epidermis and density of papillae are generally found to be stable characters at a species level. The infraspecific variation of epidermis sculpture, where present, ranges from smooth to verrucose or from verrucose to rugose. Micromorphological characters of leaf epidermis are shown to have potential taxonomic significance in Aspidistra; in combination with the type of shoot structure, they allow to subdivide the species into 13 groups. The groups are largely incongruent with floral morphological traits. An identification key to the studied species of Aspidistra based on vegetative characters (gross leaf and shoot morphology and characters of leaf epidermis) is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72259/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72259/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72259/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 19:00:02 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Causonis sessilifolia (Vitaceae), a new species from Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75570/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 55-64</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.75570</p>
					<p>Authors: Anna Trias-Blasi, Manop Poopath, Li-Min Lu, Gaurav Parmar</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Causonis sessilifolia, from Thailand is described, based on morphological and phylogenetical methods. A full description, conservation assessment, a key, images and phylogenetic tree are provided. Diagnostic characters for this species are sessile leaves that are sometimes opposite and inflorescence insertion interfoliar.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75570/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75570/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/75570/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 09:13:28 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Lespedeza danxiaensis (Fabaceae), a new species from Guangdong, China, based on molecular and morphological data</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72788/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 43-53</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.72788</p>
					<p>Authors: Wan-Yi Zhao, Kai-Wen Jiang, Zai-Xiong Chen , Bin Tian, Qiang Fan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lespedeza danxiaensis (Fabaceae), a new species from Danxiashan National Nature Reserve in Guangdong Province, is described and illustrated. The new species is morphologically similar to Lespedeza pilosa, but it can be easily distinguished by its thin leathery leaflets and long peduncles. Phylogenetic analysis based on ITS confirmed that the new species belongs to Lespedeza subg. Macrolespedeza. The new species is the first known species of Lespedeza endemic to Danxia landform and is currently only known from Mount Danxia, Guangdong.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72788/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72788/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72788/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 09:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Rubus kaznowskii (Rosaceae), a new bramble species from south-central Poland</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71193/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 27-41</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.71193</p>
					<p>Authors: Piotr Kosiński, Tomasz Maliński, Marcin Nobis, Magdalena Rojek-Jelonek, Dominik Tomaszewski, Monika Dering, Jerzy Zieliński</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on field research in south-central Poland, supplemented with a review of herbarium materials, we identified a stable bramble biotype with a range large enough (190 km distance between the outermost stands) to be described as a new regional agamic species, Rubus kaznowskii sp.nov. It belongs to the series Subthyrsoidei(sect. Corylifolii). Although R. kaznowskii has a unique combination of features, it can be potentially mistaken for R. gothicus. It differs from the latter species in many aspects, including: pruinose primocanes, denser indumentum of the abaxial leaf surface, and more curved prickles on the petiole. R. kaznowskii has mainly been observed on rusty soils, in habitats of mixed coniferous and mixed broadleaf forests, usually in sunny places, along forest margins and roads, in clearings and roadside thickets.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71193/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71193/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71193/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 16:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Dryopteris wulingshanensis (Dryopteridaceae), a new species from Hunan, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72019/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 17-26</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.72019</p>
					<p>Authors: Jiang-Ping Shu, Zi-Yue Liu, Zhi-Rong Gu, Li-Jun Chen, Hong-Jin Wei, Xi-Le Zhou, Yue-Hong Yan, Rui-Jiang Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Dryopteris wulingshanensis, a new species growing on limestone in the Wulingshan Mountains, Hunan, China, is described and illustrated. This species is most similar to D. jishouensis and D. gymnophylla on general morphological traits, such as the form of scales, rhizome and sori, but differs by the number of vascular bundles at the base of the petiole, length to width ratio of lamina, stalk length of basal pinnae, division of the lamina, apex form of the pinnule and habitat. Moreover, molecular phylogenetic analysis using the chloroplast rbcL gene suggested that D. wulingshanensis, as the sister group of D. jishouensis, is a monophyletic clade. According to its restricted geographic range, small populations and few individuals, D. wulingshanensis should be considered endangered, according to the IUCN Red List criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72019/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72019/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72019/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 13:05:27 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Living in extreme environments: distribution of Lycium humile (Solanaceae), an endemic halophyte from the Altiplano-Puna region, South America</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71377/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 185: 1-15</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.185.71377</p>
					<p>Authors: María Virginia Palchetti, Juan José Cantero, Vanezza Morales-Fierro, Gloria E. Barboza, Andrés Moreira-Muñoz</p>
					<p>Abstract: Very few Solanaceae species are able to grow in saline soils; one of them is Lycium humile. This species is endemic to the Altiplano-Puna region (Central Andes, South America) where there are multiple extreme environmental conditions such as hypersaline soils. Here we present an updated description and distribution of L. humile including its new record for Bolivia at the edges of “Salar de Uyuni”, the largest salt flat in the world; we discuss its ecological role in saline environments by analyzing soil salinity and cover-abundance values ​​of the studied sites. According to IUCN criteria, we recommend a category of Least Concern for L. humile, but the growing development of lithium mining in saline environments of the Altiplano-Puna region may potentially threaten exclusive communities.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71377/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71377/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71377/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 09:19:38 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Spiradiclis detianensis (Rubiaceae, Ophiorrhizeae), a new species from southwestern Guangxi, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69886/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 103-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.69886</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhao-Jie Wen, Yun-Fen Huang, Yan-Hua Hu, Khang Sinh Nguyen, Lei Wu</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Rubiaceae, Spiradiclis detianensis is described from a limestone karst area of southwestern China. This new species is morphologically similar to S. cordata and S. spathulata. All of them have rosetted habit and long peduncles, but it differs from the former by the cuneate leaf bases (vs. basally cordate) and much longer corolla tubes (1.8–2.2 cm long vs. ca. 5 mm long), and from the latter mainly by its tubular-funnel shaped corolla (vs. slenderly salver shaped), 4.5–6.8 (vs. 1.5–2) mm in diam, inside throat and corolla densely puberulent (vs. glabrous except a ring of long hairs at the middle). It also resembles to S. tubiflora, but differs clearly by its subrosulate habit (vs. procumbent to creeping), longer leaf blades (7.0–10.5 cm vs. 0.5–2.5 cm) and longer corolla tubes (18–22 mm vs. 14–16 mm). At same time, color photos, illustrations, detailed descriptions and conservation status of the new species are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69886/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69886/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69886/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 5 Nov 2021 16:54:58 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species and a new combination from Zhejiang, East China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73327/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 111-126</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.73327</p>
					<p>Authors: Yi-Fei Lu, Yue-Liang Xu, Wen-Yuan Xie, Hong-Wei Zhang, Zi-Hong Zheng, Xin Cai, Xiao-Feng Jin</p>
					<p>Abstract: As the supplement of the flora of Zhejiang, East China, two new species were described with illustrations. Cerastium huadingense Y.F.Lu, W.Y.Xie &amp; X.F.Jin (Caryophyllaceae) differs from C. qingliangfengicum in having sterile stems absent, leaves sessile, petals slightly longer than sepals, and stamens slightly shorter than sepals. Ixeridium dimorphifolium Y.L.Xu, Y.F.Lu &amp; X.Cai (Asteraceae) differs from I. beauverdianum in having plant stoloniferous, basal leaves dimorphic, involucre 8‒10 mm long, inner phyllaries 8, and florets 7‒10. Paraphlomis setulosa C.Y.Wu &amp; H.W.Li (Lamiaceae) was reviewed and morphological characters of the corolla and stamens of its type and the specimens collected in the field survey were critically examined. With barbate anthers and strongly divergent anther cells, Paraphlomis setulosa was transferred to Sinopogonanthera, and S. setulosa (C.Y.Wu &amp; H.W.Li) H.W.Zhang &amp; X.F.Jin was consequently combined.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73327/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73327/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73327/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 5 Nov 2021 16:18:14 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Plagiothecium schofieldii, a new species from the Aleutian Islands (Alaska, USA)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69970/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 127-138</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.69970</p>
					<p>Authors: Grzegorz J. Wolski, Paulina Nowicka-Krawczyk, William R. Buck</p>
					<p>Abstract: Plagiothecium schofieldii sp. nov. is described from the Aleutian Islands, Alaska, U.S.A. Some morphological features of this species correspond to P. lamprostachys (Southern Hemisphere species); however, Plagiothecium schofieldii is genetically and morphologically different from this and other common Northern Hemisphere species e.g., P. denticulatum, P. platyphyllum, or P. ruthei. The most important distinguishing morphological features differentiating this species are: the arrangement of the leaves on the stem; dimensions, concavity and symmetry of the leaves; dimensions of cells and their areolation; orientation of capsules. Additionally, due to the strong concavity of the leaves, they are very often badly damaged under the microscope. We present the results of DNA research of the analyzed samples, and a detailed description of the morphological features. The new species is illustrated, and its ecological preferences and currently known geographical distribution are presented. Additionally, the authors propose to add this species to Plagiothecium section, which is confirmed by morphological features and genetic analysis.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69970/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69970/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69970/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 5 Nov 2021 13:49:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Genetic diversity of Salix lapponum populations in Central Europe</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71641/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 83-101</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.71641</p>
					<p>Authors: Jacek Urbaniak, Paweł Kwiatkowski, Paweł Pawlikowski</p>
					<p>Abstract: Salix lapponum is a cold-tolerant relict species in Europe that occurs in several sites, probably reflecting previous migration routes of S. lapponum during the Pleistocene. However, only a few data are available on the genetic structures of populations of S. lapponum. In this study, we use PCR-ISSR markers to investigate genetic variation in 19 European populations of S. lapponum L. AMOVA analysis shows that most of the variation (55.8%) occurs within populations; variability among groups accounts for 19.7%. An AMOVA analysis based on four groups determined by STRUCTURE analysis shows similar results: variability of 54.1% within the population and variability of 18.9% between the four population groups, based on geographic regions. Within individual geographic groups, which are characterised by the studied populations, the lowest variability (as well as the highest homogeneity) was found in populations located in Belarus. The obtained results are consistent with our expectations that the European Lowland could be a significant geographic barrier for gene flow over large geographic distances for S. lapponum. Both the Scandinavian and Belarusian populations, as well as those coming from NE Poland, are characterised by significant genetic distinctiveness. However, some populations from NE Poland and the Sudetes show similarities with populations from other geographic regions, indicating existing genetic relationships between them. Moreover, the results suggest a fairly clear division of the population into 4 emerging geographic regions, although separated by a geographical barrier: the Polish lowland, which forms part of the larger geographic unit known as the European Lowland.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71641/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71641/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71641/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 5 Nov 2021 09:52:15 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Updated description of Diospyros dussaudii Lecomte (Ebenaceae), with lectotypification and notes on its distribution</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71045/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 67-82</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.71045</p>
					<p>Authors: Sutee Duangjai, Aroon Sinbumroong, Porntawat Chalermwong, Padungsak Suekaew, Kwanjai Khammongkol, Wittawat Kiewbang, Sukid Rueangruea, Theerawat Thananthaisong, Somran Suddee</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diospyros dussaudii is a poorly known species and previous descriptions lacked details about its female flowers and fruits. The species had not been recorded since type collections were made in 1913. As a result of our Diospyros research in Thailand, new specimens and data are now available for this species. In this study, we provide an updated morphological description, illustrations, lectotypification and a distribution map. The species was previously reported to be endemic to Laos; as such, the occurrences in Thailand greatly expand the distribution of the species. In addition, we analysed the phylogenetic relationships between D. dussaudii and other Diospyros species from Southeast Asia and other regions, using DNA sequence data from eight plastid regions. Our phylogenetic analyses indicate that D. dussaudii is closely related to D. castanea, D. dasyphylla and D. insidiosa. Their taxonomic affinities are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71045/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71045/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71045/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 07:59:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Epidendrum L. (Orchidaceae) of pendulous habit from Peru</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70844/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 55-66</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.70844</p>
					<p>Authors: Luis Ocupa Horna, Eric Hágsater, Marco M. Jiménez</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Epidendrum L. from northern Peru is described, illustrated, and compared with related species. This new species belongs to the Laxicaule Group and shares morphological characteristics with Epidendrum laxicaule D.E. Benn &amp; Christenson but differs in the shape and length of the dorsal sepal; the shape of the petals and the lip, ribs position of the lip, shape of the vesicle formed between the ovary and the column as well as the section of the stem.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70844/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70844/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70844/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 3 Nov 2021 09:40:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Vitis shizishanensis, a new species of the grape genus from Hubei province, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70045/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 45-54</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.70045</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi-Yao Ma, Jun Wen, Qiang Fu, Xiu-Qun Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Vitis shizishanensis (Vitaceae), a new species from Hubei, China, is described and illustrated. It is morphologically similar to V. flexuosa and V. bryoniifolia, but differs in leaf lobing and pubescence. It can be easily distinguished from the two species based on its glabrous or with very sparse arachnoid tomentum on the abaxial mature leaf surface, and its unlobed to 3–7 lobed leaves. A detailed description, along with photographs for the new species, and a table for morphological comparisons with similar Vitis species, are also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70045/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70045/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70045/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 2 Nov 2021 16:01:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Notes on the systematics of Cuscuta sect. Subulatae (subg. Grammica) with the description of Cuscuta mantiqueirana, a new species from Brazil</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69037/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 27-44</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.69037</p>
					<p>Authors: Mihai Costea, Simone Soares da Silva, Rosangela Simao-Bianchini, Ana Rita G. Simoes, Sasa Stefanovic</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cuscuta mantiqueirana Costea, S.S. Silva &amp; Sim.-Bianch. a new species from montane cloud forests of the Serra da Mantiqueira, Brazil, is described and illustrated. The morphological and phylogenetic analyses revealed that the new species belongs to sect. Subulatae of subg. Grammica. The new species is related to C. odorata var. botryoides, C. rotundiflora and C. globiflora from which it differs in narrower calyx lobes and the presence of four stomatiferous lobes or projections at the distal part of the ovary. A detailed morphological comparison with C. odorata var. botryoides, morphologically the most similar taxon, is provided along with the geographical distribution, ecology and host range of the species. The morphological and phylogenetic relationships of the new species, as well as the diversity of stomatiferous projections, are discussed in the broader context of sect. Subulatae and subg. Grammica. Cuscuta boliviana var. paranensis is considered a synonym of C. odorata var. botryoides.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69037/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69037/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69037/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 11:38:46 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Saxifraga viridiflora (Saxifragaceae), an unusual new species from Guangxi, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73421/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 19-26</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.73421</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin-Jian Zhang, Quan-Sheng Fu, Jun-Tong Chen, Li-Juan Li, Peng-Rui Luo, Jing-Yi Peng, Xian-Han Huang, Hang Sun, Tao Deng</p>
					<p>Abstract: Saxifraga viridiflora, a remarkable new species of the genus Saxifraga sect. Irregulares (Saxifragaceae) from Guangxi, is described and illustrated herein. This new species morphologically differs from all known S. sect. Irregulares taxa by its greenish petals, verruculose sepals, and thick leathery leaf blade abaxially scarlet with white spots.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73421/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73421/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73421/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 11:37:53 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Goniothalamus roseipetalus and G. sukhirinensis (Annonaceae): Two new species from Peninsular Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73210/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 184: 1-17</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.184.73210</p>
					<p>Authors: Charan Leeratiwong, Piya Chalermglin, Richard M. K. Saunders</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new Goniothalamus species (Annonaceae), G. roseipetalus sp. nov. and G. sukhirinensis sp. nov., are described from the southern limits of Peninsular Thailand (Narathiwat and Yala Provinces). Both new species resemble G. macrophyllus, G. scortechinii and G. uvarioides. The addition of these two new species brings the total number of Goniothalamus species in Thailand to 27. Separate identification keys are provided for flowering and fruiting specimens of the Thai species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73210/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73210/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/73210/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 09:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Marine and brackish Luticola D.G.Mann (Bacillariophyta) species from the Java Sea and South China Sea coasts with the description of three new species</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71049/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 115-142</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.71049</p>
					<p>Authors: Mateusz Rybak, Andrzej Witkowski, Lukasz Peszek, John P. Kociolek, Yenny Risjani, Duc Hung Nguyen, Jinpeng Zhang, Yunianta, Van Duy Nguyen, Romain Gastineau, Thi Thuy Duong, Philippe Rosa, Vona Meleder</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, samples were collected from the Java Sea coasts, from the South China Sea in Hainan Island coasts and Quảng Yên region and Rú Chá mangrove near Hue in Central Vietnam. In studied samples a total of eight Luticola species have been observed. Three of the taxa studied are described herein as species new to science – Luticola orientalis sp. nov., L. cribriareolata sp. nov. and L. halongiana sp. nov. Under light microscopy (LM) L. orientalis sp. nov. and L. cribriareolata sp. nov. are similar with rhombic-lanceolate to rhombic/ elliptic-lanceolate to elliptic valve shapes and narrowly rounded apices. Both species can be easily distinguished by stria density (higher density in L. orientalis). Under SEM L. cribriareolata is characterized by cribrate areola occlusions, a character thus far observed only in three established species. The remaining species of the whole genus known thus far are characterized by hymenate areola. Similar morphology Luticola species have been observed from tropical mangrove forests from Madagascar but they all can be easily distinguished based on the lack of grooves in the central area. The third species – L. halongiana sp. nov. has rhombic-elliptic to rhombic-lanceolate valves with broadly rounded to slightly protracted apices in larger specimens. This species has a relatively broad central area. Also unique among brackish-water Luticola is the small, rounded stigma positioned almost midway between the valve center and valve margin. In the habitats from which the new species are described we also identified five established Luticola taxa including, L. belawanensis, L. celebesica, L. inserata, L. seposita and L. tropica. For those species we provide detailed SEM characteristics of valve ultrastructure, as well as the range of environmental conditions and geographic distribution within the study area.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71049/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71049/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71049/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 17:20:05 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Hemiboea chanii (Gesneriaceae), a new species from limestone areas of northern Vietnam</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69180/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 108-114</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.69180</p>
					<p>Authors: Cuong Huu Nguyen, Ly Van Nguyen, Khang Sinh Nguyen, Alexander A. Egorov, Leonid V. Averyanov</p>
					<p>Abstract: Hemiboea chanii, a new species of Gesneriaceae from Ha Giang Province, northern Vietnam, is here described and illustrated. It has many branched stems, diamond-shaped involucre with two cirrose opposite apices, a pink corolla, red spotted inside, and a flowering time in January-February. Among congeners with an externally hairy corolla, this new species is morphologically close to H. crystallina and H. sinovietnamica. Diagnostic discriminative characters in all mentioned species are discussed. The conservation status of this species is considered to be “Critically endangered” (CR) according to the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69180/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69180/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69180/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 10:28:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cymbopleura natellia – a new species from Transbaikal area (Russia, Siberia) described on the basis of molecular and morphological investigation</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72285/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 95-105</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.72285</p>
					<p>Authors: Anton Glushchenko, Evgeniy Gusev, Yevhen Maltsev, John Patrick Kociolek, Irina Kuznetsova, Maxim Kulikovskiy</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new cymbelloid diatom species from the genus Cymbopleura (Krammer) Krammer is described on the basis of molecular and morphological investigations. Cymbopleura natellia Glushchenko, Kulikovskiy &amp; Kociolek, sp. nov. is, on the basis of results with molecular data, close to C. naviculiformis (Auerswald ex Heiberg) Krammer. The two species differ both by molecular distance and morphological features. Morphologically, C. natellia sp. nov. is compared with several other species in the genus. This work is a pioneer investigation of cymbelloid taxa using molecular tool from Transbaikal area.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72285/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72285/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72285/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 10:20:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Allium negianum (Amaryllidaceae): a new species under subg. Rhizirideum from Uttarakhand Himalaya, India</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65433/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 77-93</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.65433</p>
					<p>Authors: Anjula Pandey, K. Madhav Rai, Pavan Kumar Malav, S. Rajkumar</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Allium negianum (Amaryllidaceae), belongs to the genus Allium subg. Rhizirideum, sect. Eduardia is described here from the Uttarakhand Himalayan region of India. This taxon grows in Malari region of Niti valley in Chamoli district and Dharma valley of Pithoragarh district, Uttarakhand, India. It is a narrowly distributed species and morphologically more closer to A. przewalskianum Regel but differentiated by its tunic color of bulb, umbel with lax flowers, peduncle length, perigone colour, size and shape and leaf anatomy. Taxonomic delineation and relationship analysis based on nuclear ribosomal Internal Transcribed Spacers (ITS) region indicated that A. negianum is distinct and related to A. przewalskianum. This study provided a comprehensive description and comparison with A. przewalskianum, an identification key and notes on the distribution of the species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65433/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65433/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65433/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 09:27:59 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Perrottetia taronensis B.M.Barthol. &amp; K.Armstr., sp. nov. (Dipentodontaceae), a new species from northwestern Yunnan Province, China and northern Kachin State, Myanmar and a re-examination of the Asian and Australasian taxa of Perrottetia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71505/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 67-76</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.71505</p>
					<p>Authors: Bruce Bartholomew, Kate E. Armstrong, Rong Li, Peter W. Fritsch</p>
					<p>Abstract: Perrottetia taronensis from the Dulong Jiang valley in northwestern Yunnan Province, China and the Babulongtan mountain range in northern Kachin State, Myanmar is here described as a new species of the Dipentodontaceae. It is the third species of the genus to be recognized for China and the first to be reported for Myanmar. It is similar to P. alpestris s.s. but differs by characters of its leaf margins, inflorescences, and fruit. The three subspecies of P. alpestris recognized by Hou in “Flora Malesiana” are here recognized as three distinct species, i.e., P. alpestris, P. moluccana, and P. philippinensis on the basis of differences in diagnostic characters and distribution. The report in the “Flora of China” of the Taiwan species P. arisanensis from Yunnan is determined to be incorrect due to misidentification of two specimens at KUN.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71505/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71505/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71505/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 17:48:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cirsium taiwanense (Compositae, Cirsium sect. Onotrophe, subsect. Australicirsium), a new species from Taiwan</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70119/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 35-53</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.70119</p>
					<p>Authors: Chih-Yi Chang, Hsy-Yu Tzeng, Yen-Hsueh Tseng</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Cirsium, C. taiwanense Y.H.Tseng &amp; Chih Y.Chang from central-northern Taiwan is reported in this article. This species is similar to C. hosokawae Kitam. in having a densely cobwebby abaxial leaf surface, but differs in its yellow (vs. vivid purplish red) corolla and the angle between the midrib and the lateral veins of the leaf, which is acute as opposed to nearly at a right angle in C. hosokawae. Cirsium taiwanense has 2n = 32 chromosomes, which is different from the other species in the Taiwanese subsect. Australicirsium Kitam. (2n = 34). An identification key to the Cirsium taxa of Taiwan is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70119/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70119/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70119/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:45:23 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Nomenclatural notes and typification of nine names related to Jasminum (Oleaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69852/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 55-65</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.69852</p>
					<p>Authors: Bui Hong Quang, Ritesh Kumar Choudhary, Joongku Lee</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lectotypes are designated here for the following nine validly published names: Jasminum alongense, J. anodontum, J. eberhardtii, J. harmandianum, J. lang, J. laxiflorum, J. pierreanum, J. rufohirtum, and J. sinense. Jasminum lang is reinstated as a distinct species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69852/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69852/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69852/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:16:14 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Euphorbia mbuinzauensis, a new succulent species in Kenya from the Synadenium group in Euphorbia sect. Monadenium (Euphorbiaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70285/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 21-35</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.70285</p>
					<p>Authors: Neng Wei, Fredrick Munyao Mutie, Geoffrey Mwachala, Olwen M. Grace, Guang-Wan Hu, Qing-Feng Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Euphorbia mbuinzauensis, a succulent new species of the Synadenium group in Euphorbiaceae from Makueni County, Kenya, is described and illustrated. Morphologically, it is most similar to E. pseudomollis, but differs mainly by its shrubby habit (up to 4 m), abaxial leaves surfaces with densely stellate hairs, 2–4-forked cymes, smaller bracts (ca. 2.5 × 3.0 mm), smaller cyathia (6 mm wide), crimson glands without narrow smooth margin, smaller fruits (ca. 8 × 7 mm) and ovoid seeds (ca. 1.8 × 2.2 mm). Furthermore, we performed a molecular phylogenetic analysis of the Synadenium group in Euphorbia sect. Monadenium, based on complete nuclear ribosomal DNA (nrDNA) datasets. This phylogenetic inference also supports it to be a distinct species. The new species is assessed as Endangered using the IUCN criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70285/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70285/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70285/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 16:37:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Haplodontium altunense (Bryaceae, Bryopsida), a new moss species from Northwest China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71642/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 9-19</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.71642</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao-Rui Wang, Min Li, John R. Spence, Jian-Cheng Zhao, Sulayman Mamtimin</p>
					<p>Abstract: Haplodontium altunense X.R.Wang &amp; S.Mamtimin, a new moss species of the family Bryaceae from Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, China is described and illustrated. Genetic analysis based on ITS sequences shows that this species is a member of the Bryaceae and in the same clade as Anomobryum. Particularly distinctive features of the new species include: double peristome; the exostome has raised and membranous chomata with united lamellae between two teeth proximally; the endostome is poorly developed and all the endostomial material tightly adherent to the exostome.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71642/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71642/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71642/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 8 Oct 2021 08:00:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Corybas papillatus (Orchidaceae), a new orchid species from peninsular Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71167/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 183: 1-7</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.183.71167</p>
					<p>Authors: Janejaree Inuthai, Sahut Chantanaorrapint, Manop Poopath, Naiyana Tetsana, Wittawat Kiewbang, Somran Suddee</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Corybas papillatus, is described and illustrated from peninsular Thailand. The new species is easily recognized through a combination of the following characters: the purplish flower, the rounded apex of the dorsal sepal, the outer surface of dorsal sepal covered with irregular papillae in the upper half, the lateral sepals adnate laterally at the base to the connate petals, the V-shaped throat, the labellum bearing short hairs, dentate to erose labellum margins, and well-developed conical spurs. A key to the species of Corybas in Thailand is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71167/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71167/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71167/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 8 Oct 2021 08:00:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Leaf epidermal micromorphology defining the clades in Cinnamomum (Lauraceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67289/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 125-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.67289</p>
					<p>Authors: Zeng Gang, Bing Liu, Jens G. Rohwer, David Kay Ferguson, Yong Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, we sampled 48 species of Asian Cinnamomum covering the species groups that were identified in recent phylogenetic studies and conducted leaf micromorphological observations using both light microscopy (LM) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Synapomorphies were determined by means of mapping micromorphological characters on a phylogenetic tree. The results indicate that Cinnamomum exhibits two different types of leaf upper epidermis: Type I has smooth/non-reticulate periclinal walls whereas Type II has reticulate periclinal walls and is unusual in the family Lauraceae. We found that the two types of micromorphological characters are clade-specific, sect. Camphora s.s. possesses Type I leaf upper epidermis, and sect. Cinnamomum s.l. has Type II leaf upper epidermis. Our study also reveals that C. saxatile, a member of sect. Camphora s.l. in the traditional classification, actually has Type II leaf upper epidermis, thus reinforcing the result of a recent molecular phylogeny that has this species in a clade consisting mainly of species of sect. Cinnamomum.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67289/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67289/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67289/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 4 Oct 2021 16:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Begonia pseudoedulis, a new species in Begonia sect. Platycentrum (Begoniaceae) from southern Guangxi of China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69074/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 113-124</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.69074</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin-Xin Feng, Yan Xiao, Zhi-Xian Liu, Ren-Kun Li, Dan Wei, Dai-Ke Tian</p>
					<p>Abstract: Begonia pseudoedulis, a new species in Begonia sect. Platycentrum (Klotzsch) A.DC. (Begoniaceae) from southern Guangxi of China, is here described and illustrated. It morphologically resembles B. edulis H.Lév. and B. dielsiana E.Pritz. ex Diels but differs easily by its hairy petioles and inflorescences, and red hispidulous flower tepals, ovary and capsules. The molecular phylogenetic analysis based on ITS supported that the new species was a monophyletic lineage, separating from both B. dielsiana and B. edulis. Due to its isolated distribution with several small populations, which are possibly disturbed by human activities, the species is considered as “Near Threatened” (NT) according to the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69074/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69074/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69074/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 08:00:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Indigofera wenholdiae (Indigofereae, Fabaceae), a new species from the Western Cape Province, South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72170/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 107-112</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.72170</p>
					<p>Authors: Brian du Preez, Leanne L. Dreyer, Charles H. Stirton, A. Muthama Muasya, Brian D. Schrire</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, Indigofera wenholdiae, a new species of Fabaceae from the Agulhas Plain Region of the Western Cape Province, South Africa, is described. A composite photographic plate is included along with a distribution map, description of habitat and ecology and proposed IUCN conservation status. Indigofera wenholdiae is unique in the I. brachystachya group by having digitately compound (vs. pinnately compound) leaves, white and unscented flowers (vs. pink and sweetly scented flowers) and grows on sandstone hillsides (vs. coastal limestone plains and outcrops).</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72170/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72170/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/72170/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 08:00:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Lectotypification of six names in the genus Elleanthus (Orchidaceae) described from J. J. Linden’s collection</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68782/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 93-106</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.68782</p>
					<p>Authors: Magdalena Dudek, Dariusz L. Szlachetko</p>
					<p>Abstract: The lectotypification of six names of species, originally described as Evelyna Lind. (Orchidaceae), based on collections of Jean Jules Linden from locations that are currently in Venezuela and Colombia, is proposed. We also provide the number and location of duplicates of the type material.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68782/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68782/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68782/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 14:09:11 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Columnea (Gesneriaceae) from the western Andean slopes of Ecuador and Colombia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69016/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 67-82</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.69016</p>
					<p>Authors: John L. Clark, Francisco Tobar, Laura Clavijo, Mathieu Perret, Catherine Helen Graham</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Columnea (Gesneriaceae, tribe Gesnerieae) are described from the western Andean slopes of northern Ecuador and southern Colombia. Columnea angulata J.L. Clark &amp; F. Tobar and Columnea floribunda F. Tobar &amp; J.L. Clark are described from northern Ecuador. Columnea tecta J.L. Clark &amp; Clavijo is described from southern Colombia and northern Ecuador. The three new species are facultative epiphytes with dorsiventral shoots and are readily recognized by bright red tips on the abaxial and adaxial leaf surfaces. The species described here are vegetatively similar to the sympatric species Columnea picta H. Karst. and are readily differentiated by floral features that are illustrated, described and featured with digital images.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69016/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69016/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69016/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:58:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cyclorhiza puana (Apiaceae), a new species from Sichuan, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67009/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 57-66</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.67009</p>
					<p>Authors: Jing Zhou, Jun-Mei Niu, Xin-Yue Wang, Pei Wang, Ming-Jia Guo, Zhen-Wen Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Cyclorhiza puana J. Zhou &amp; Z.W. Liu (Apiaceae) from Sichuan Province of China, is described and illustrated here. Morphological comparisons with congeneric species revealed that it is distinguished by its slender habit, sparse annular scars, 4-pinnatisect leaf blade with ultimate segments linear (2–4×0.5–1 mm), subequal rays, oblong fruits with slightly thickened ribs, obconic stylopodium and slightly concave seed face. A molecular analysis based on nuclear ribosomal DNA internal transcribed spacer (ITS) sequences indicated that C. puana is genetically distinct from the other two species of the genus. A distribution map, as well as an updated key, are provided for the species of Cyclorhiza.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67009/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67009/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67009/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:56:19 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Re-appraisal of Nertera (Rubiaceae) in Taiwan</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70685/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 83-91</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.70685</p>
					<p>Authors: Wei-Chih Chen, Chih-Chiang Wang, Kun-Cheng Chang</p>
					<p>Abstract: A revision of Nertera (Rubiaceae) in Taiwan was carried out by classical taxonomic methods and the presence of two endemic species was confirmed. Only one species, misapplied as N. granadensis, had been reported in the second edition of “Flora of Taiwan”, but there were two additional endemic species in this genus: N. nigricarpa and N. taiwaniana confirmed. Nertera nigricarpa is characterised by the entire leaf, purple-black petals, black fruits and dark-purple seeds with raised striate. Nertera taiwaniana has leaves with undulated margins, yellowish-green petals, red fruits and yellow-white seeds without striate. N. granadensis is excluded from the flora of this Island.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70685/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70685/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70685/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:14:11 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Youngia hangii (Asteraceae, Crepidinae), a new species from Hubei, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71063/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 27-38</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.71063</p>
					<p>Authors: Qun Liu, Gui-Yun Huang, Dai-Gui Zhang, Jian-Wen Zhang, Tao Deng, Zhi-Min Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Youngia hangii T.Deng, D.G.Zhang, Qun Liu &amp; Z.M.Li, sp. nov., a new species of Asteraceae, is described and illustrated. It was collected in Wufeng County, Hubei Province, Eastern Central China. Youngia hangii is morphologically most similar to Y. rubida, but can be easily distinguished from the latter by capitula with 8–10 florets and the hairy leaf surface. Phylogenetic analyses, based on the internal transcribed spacers (ITS) and one chloroplast marker (rps16), showed that Y. hangii and Y. rubida were sister species with good support. The results of both phylogenetic analysis and the morphological data support the specific rank of Y. hangii.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71063/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71063/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71063/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 17:13:05 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Description of four new terrestrial diatom species from Luticola and Microcostatus genera from South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65326/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 1-26</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.65326</p>
					<p>Authors: Mateusz Rybak, Natalia Kochman-Kędziora, Łukasz Peszek</p>
					<p>Abstract: The knowledge about terrestrial diatom assemblages in southern Africa is rather limited, despite a long history of diatom research in this area. Terrestrial habitats are places of characteristic diatom floras, dominated by species resistant to desiccation which are able to thrive in conditions of limited water availability. The presented work expands the knowledge about these unique habitats. During the study on terrestrial moss-inhabiting diatoms from Western Cape Province (South Africa), four taxa with a unique set of valve features have been found and described herein as new species, based on light and scanning electron microscopy. These new species are: Luticola microcephala M. Rybak, Peszek &amp; Kochman-Kędziora, sp. nov., Luticola asymmetrica M. Rybak, Kochman-Kędziora &amp; Peszek, sp. nov., Luticola terrestris Kochman-Kędziora, M. Rybak &amp; Peszek, sp. nov. and Microcostatus meridionalis Peszek, M. Rybak &amp; Kochman-Kędziora, sp. nov. Algal community composition had low species richness (9–15 taxa per sample) and samples were dominated by: Humidophila contenta, Nitzschia brevissima and Eunotia aff. pseudominor. The three new Luticola species formed numerous populations, exceeding 10% of the share, whereas Microcostatus meridionalis reached 5.4%. Basic morphological data of associated diatom flora together with detailed micrographs are also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65326/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65326/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65326/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 15:47:43 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The history and typification of Lilium humboldtii J.H.Krelage (Liliaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70099/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 182: 39-55</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.182.70099</p>
					<p>Authors: James Compton, Mark W. Skinner</p>
					<p>Abstract: The history of the Californian Lilium humboldtii J.H.Krelage, its initial discovery and confusion in literature over its collection, distribution and naming are discussed. Neotypes are designated for the names Lilium humboldtii and Lilium bloomerianum Kellogg. Lectotypes are designated for the names Lilium canadense var. puberulum Torr. and L. bloomerianum var. ocellatum Kellogg.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70099/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70099/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70099/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 10:58:44 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Microlicia deflexa and M. johnwurdackiana (Melastomataceae), two new species from the Brazilian Cerrado</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70949/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 113-128</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.70949</p>
					<p>Authors: Rosana Romero, Rodrigo Valentim</p>
					<p>Abstract: Microlicia deflexa sp. nov. and M. johnwurdackiana sp. nov. are described, illustrated and an updated identification key for the species of Microlicia from Clube Caça e Pesca Itororó de Uberlândia is provided. Microlicia deflexa occurs in Minas Gerais and Goiás States and is characterised by its linear-lanceolate and deflexed sepal on flower and immature fruit, long pedicel and indumentum of glandular trichomes, mixed with spherical, golden glands. Microlicia johnwurdackiana is endemic to Uberlândia and characterised by having indumentum of setose trichomes and spherical, golden glands, magenta petal with greenish abaxial surface at the apex and dimorphic stamens with bicolorous and tetrasporangiate anthers.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70949/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70949/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70949/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:10:52 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Vaccinium motuoense (Ericaceae), a new species from Xizang, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71522/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 105-111</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.71522</p>
					<p>Authors: Yi-Hua Tong, Wang-Lin Zhao, Bing-Mou Wang, En-De Liu, Jie Cai, Yong-Jie Guo</p>
					<p>Abstract: Vaccinium motuoense (Ericaceae), a new species from Motuo County, Xizang Autonomous Region, China is described and illustrated. This new species belongs to Vaccinium sect. Calcicolus and is morphologically most similar to V. dunalianum, but differs in having yellowish-brown tomentose young branches, petioles and inflorescence rachis, leaf blades with 2–3(–4) pairs of secondary veins, usually all basal and with fine veins impressed adaxially and urceolate to spherical corollas.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71522/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71522/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71522/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 12:28:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The genus Deschampsia and the epithet “ alpina”</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69546/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 95-103</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.69546</p>
					<p>Authors: Jorge O. Chiapella, Zhi-Qing Xue, Josef Greimler</p>
					<p>Abstract: The epithet “alpina” has been recurrently used in the genus Deschampsia to name plants located in northern regions of Europe, Asia and North America, as a species (Deschampsia alpina (L.) Roem. &amp; Schult.), but also in infraspecific categories (Deschampsia cespitosa subsp. alpina Tzvel. and Deschampsia cespitosa var. alpina Schur.). The morphological and molecular available evidence suggests the existence of a single species, Deschampsia cespitosa (L.) P. Beauv., in which individuals belonging to the same morphological gradient have received different names in different taxonomic categories throughout its wide distribution range. An evaluation of the available names indicates that all uses of the epithet “alpina” are illegitimate. A new combination is proposed at the infraspecific level as Deschampsia cespitosa subsp. neoalpina Chiapella, Xue &amp; Greimler.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69546/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69546/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69546/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Sep 2021 17:46:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Validation of Hosta alata (Asparagaceae) as a new species and its phylogenetic affinity</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64245/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 79-93</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.64245</p>
					<p>Authors: Tetsukazu Yahara, Shun K. Hirota, Kengo Fuse, Hiroyuki Sato, Shuichiro Tagane, Yoshihisa Suyama</p>
					<p>Abstract: Molecular phylogenetic studies of Hosta pulchella (Asparagaceae) and its relatives, which are native to Japan, have been conducted and resulted in a highly resolved phylogeny. Specifically, the relationship of H. pulchella to H. alata Hatusima, nom. nud. is investigated. These data include genome-wide SNPs obtained through conducting multiplexed ISSR genotyping by sequencing (MIG-seq). Based on these phylogenetic results, morphological observations, distribution, and differences in flowering periods of H. alata collections sympatric with H. pulchella, we find the two species closely related, but distinct. As such, we formally describe Hosta alata sp. nov. from the Oita Prefecture of Kyushu island, southwestern Japan.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64245/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64245/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64245/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Sep 2021 17:46:08 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Proposal to recognise the tribes Adinobotryeae and Glycyrrhizeae (Leguminosae subfamily Papilionoideae) based on chloroplast phylogenomic evidence</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71259/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 65-77</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.71259</p>
					<p>Authors: Lei Duan, Li-Na Han, Yotsawate Sirichamorn, Jun Wen, James A. Compton, Shuang-Wen Deng, Emine Arslan, Kuddisi Ertuğrul, Brian Schrire, Hong-Feng Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Within the legume family, the taxonomic status of subtribe Glycyrrhizinae of tribe Galegeae and of the genus Adinobotrys has been re-assessed. Based on genome skimming data, we conducted phylogenomic analyses of the inverted repeat-lacking clade within subfamily Papilionoideae. The results support the sister relationship between Glycyrrhizeae and Adinobotrys. Glycyrrhizeae is resurrected based on Glycyrrhiza and Glycyrrhizopsis, and a new tribe, Adinobotryeae, is proposed to accommodate Adinobotrys.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71259/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71259/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/71259/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 2 Sep 2021 18:46:50 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Clarifying the nomenclatural history of Tovomitopsis, a Brazilian endemic genus of Clusiaceae</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70745/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 49-64</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.70745</p>
					<p>Authors: Lucas C. Marinho, Pedro Fiaschi, André M. Amorim, Volker Bittrich</p>
					<p>Abstract: Tovomitopsis Planch. &amp; Triana is a Brazilian Atlantic Forest endemic genus composed of two species: T. paniculata (Spreng.) Planch. &amp; Triana and T. saldanhae Engl. An investigation was conducted to clarify the nomenclatural history of Tovomitopsis. We report the results of this investigation, provide an updated description of the genus, and propose lectotypes for T. paniculata and its synonyms: Tovomita foliosa C.Presl and Tovomita paniculata Cambess. We also propose lectotypes for T. saldanhae and for the new synonym Clusia angustifolia Engl.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70745/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70745/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/70745/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Sep 2021 17:46:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Nomenclatural revision of Cryptantha (Boraginaceae s. str.) names linked to South American taxa</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69740/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 29-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.69740</p>
					<p>Authors: Pablo Moroni, Agustina Martínez, Michael G. Simpson</p>
					<p>Abstract: During the preparation of the treatment of the genus Cryptantha Lehmann ex G. Don for South America, numerous names were identified as needing typification to stabilize their nomenclature. As a result, lectotypes are designated for 11 names and second-step lectotypes for 20 names. Furthermore, supporting information about the type material of the basionyms of four Cryptantha names already typified by Johnston (Eritrichium talquinum Phil., Eritrichium dimorphum Phil., Eritrichium carrizalense Phil., and Eritrichium subamplexicaule Phil.) is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69740/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69740/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69740/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:47:53 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Pseudostellaria wuyishanensis, a new species of Caryophyllaceae from Fujian, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67436/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 21-28</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.67436</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao Luo, Qi-Yi Yang, Zhe Zhang, Pan Zhu, Liang Ma, Xin-Yan Chen, Shu-Yi Lin, Shi-Pin Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Pseudostellaria wuyishanensis, a new species from the Wuyishan National Park, Fujian, China, is described and illustrated. Morphologically, Pseudostellaria wuyishanensis resembles P. heterantha. However, the new species can be distinguished by presence of stolons, 1 line of hairs on the stem, smaller leaf blades, shorter pedicels, and ovary with 2 styles.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67436/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67436/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67436/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:44:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Hanguana deflexa (Hanguanaceae), a new forest species from Sarawak, Borneo</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69045/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 9-19</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.69045</p>
					<p>Authors: Michal Hroneš, Jana Leong-Škorničková, Matti A. Niissalo, Martin Dančák</p>
					<p>Abstract: Hanguana deflexa sp. nov. (Hanguanaceae) from Lawas district, Sarawak, Malaysia (northern Borneo) is described and illustrated, bringing the total number of species in Borneo to eight. The new species differs from all other recognized Hanguana species by a combination of flat leaf blade, deflexed infructescences, one-seeded dull red fruits with centrally positioned stigma and globose seed with wedge-shaped ostiole. Revised key for Bornean Hanguana species is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69045/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69045/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69045/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 08:54:53 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Petrocosmea duyunensis (Gesneriaceae), a new species from Guizhou, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68635/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 181: 1-8</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.181.68635</p>
					<p>Authors: Sheng-Hu Tang, Jia-Wen Yang, Cong-Rui Li, Qing Zhou</p>
					<p>Abstract: Plants belonging to the genus Petrocosmea are rare and small herbs difficult to find in the wild. In the present study, a new species, Petrocosmea duyunensis, from Guizhou, China, is described. The species is most similar to P. leiandra and differs from it by a distinctly recurved abaxial corolla lip, free anthers and included pistil. Detailed morphological comparisons are given. One population with about 100 mature individuals was found at the type locality. This new taxon was assessed as “Data Deficient” (DD) according to the IUCN standards.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68635/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68635/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68635/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:30:36 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Impatiens (Balsaminaceae) from southern Western Ghats, Kerala</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66748/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 157-171</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.66748</p>
					<p>Authors: Sindhu Arya, Murugan Govindakurup Govind, Veerankutty Suresh, Walsan Kalarikkal Vishnu, Venugopalan Nair Saradamma Anil Kumar</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Impatiens, Impatiens achudanandanii, I. danii, and I. shailajae, are described from Thiruvananthapuram and Idukki districts of Kerala state (SW-India). Impatiens achudanandanii is similar to I. courtallensis and I. herbicola; I. danii to I. goughii and I. shailajae is to I. minae and I. scapiflora. The newly described taxa are readily distinguished from their allied species by unique character combinations, viz. shape of lateral sepal, lower sepal, dorsal petal, seed and pollen morphology. Detailed descriptions along with illustrations and photographs are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66748/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66748/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66748/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new endemic species of Lepanthes (Orchidaceae, Pleurothallidinae) from the highlands of Ecuador</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62671/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 111-132</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.62671</p>
					<p>Authors: Francisco Tobar Suarez, María Fernanda López, María José Gavilanes, Marco Federico Monteros, Tatiana Santander García, Catherine Helen Graham</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Lepanthes from Ecuador are described and illustrated. These additions to the Ecuadorean flora were recorded in evergreen montane forest and páramo as part of three different research projects conducted during the last five years (2016–2021). Lepanthes oro-lojaensis was discovered in the southwest of El Oro province and is similar to L. jimburae, differing mainly in the much smaller plants, inflorescences and floral parts. Lepanthes microprosartima from the western slopes of Pichincha volcano in northern Ecuador resembles L. obandoi but differs in the coloration of the leaves, the inflorescence that are shorter than the leaves and the smaller floral appendix. Lepanthes caranqui, found in eastern Pichincha and Imbabura, is most similar to L. pachychila but differs from it in its much larger plants and different shape of the petals and the floral appendix. Preliminary assessments of the conservation status of the three taxonomic novelties are provided, using the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62671/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62671/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62671/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Aug 2021 14:27:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic notes on Cyperaceae of Nepal: new records of a genus, six species and other noteworthy species</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67634/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 141-156</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.67634</p>
					<p>Authors: Prabin Bhandari, Satyam Chaudhary, Ajay Neupane, Shi-Liang Zhou, Shu-Ren Zhang</p>
					<p>Abstract: This paper reports on the presence of one generic and six specific new records of Cyperaceous species for the flora of Nepal. Amongst the new discoveries are the genus Machaerina, alongside species: Eleocharis ochrostachys, Fimbristylis acuminata, F. ferruginea, F. nutans, F. thomsonii and Scleria rugosa. The taxonomy and distribution of Actinoscirpus grossus, Fimbristylis salbundia and Fuirena umbellata in Nepal are clarified through notes on nomenclature, description, distribution, specimen examination, identification keys and photographs.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67634/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67634/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67634/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Aug 2021 12:38:40 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Agapetes heana, a new species of A. ser. Longifiles (Ericaceae) from Yunnan, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69667/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 133-139</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.69667</p>
					<p>Authors: Yi-Hua Tong, Ying Bai, Jian-Ming Feng, Ji-Dong Ya</p>
					<p>Abstract: Agapetes heana Y. H. Tong &amp; J. D. Ya (Ericaceae), a new species from Lüchun Xian, Yunnan Province, China is described and illustrated. This new species is assigned to Agapetes sect. Agapetes ser. Longifiles Airy Shaw. It is closest to A. inopinata Airy Shaw and A. oblonga Craib, but differs in having bead-like tubers, leaf blade with a wholly serrulate margin, subulate and much longer calyx lobes, much larger corollas that are carmine, green at the apex and maroon on angles, and longer stamens without spurs on the back.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69667/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69667/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69667/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 9 Aug 2021 12:35:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Nomenclatural revision of Delphinium subg. Consolida (DC.) Huth (Ranunculaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67126/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 81-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.67126</p>
					<p>Authors: Pierre-Emmanuel DuPasquier, Véronique Andro-Durand, Lucas Batory, Wei Wang, Florian Jabbour</p>
					<p>Abstract: Recent molecular phylogenetic studies have indicated that Aconitella is embedded in Consolida, which in turn is embedded in Delphinium. We choose not to split the genus Delphinium (c. 300 species), as it is horticulturally and pharmaceutically important, by conserving a broad Delphinium by transferring the names from Consolida and Aconitella to Delphinium s.lat., and more precisely in the resurrected D. subg. Consolida. Including 58 species of Aconitella and Consolida within Delphinium causes fewer nomenclatural overall changes than do alternative schemes because most of the species of Aconitella and Consolida were once named under the name Delphinium. We present here the list of synonyms for the species once named under Consolida or Aconitella and gather the information relative to the types of these names. Two new combinations are provided, and 21 lectotypes are designated here.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67126/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67126/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67126/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 5 Aug 2021 13:53:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cyphostemma calcarium, a new species of Vitaceae from the Ankarana Special Reserve, Madagascar</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69194/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 73-80</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.69194</p>
					<p>Authors: Romer Narindra Rabarijaona, Valisoa Louisicaël Rafaralahy, Charles Rakotovao, Rindra Manasoa Ranaivoson, Bing Liu, Zhi-Duan Chen, Jun Wen, Li-Min Lu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Cyphostemma calcarium Rabarij &amp; L.M.Lu, sp. nov., is herein described as a new species found on limestone outcrops in northern Madagascar. Its diagnostic morphological characteristics were compared to the species occurring in the Ankarana Special Reserve. We present detailed descriptions, illustrations, distribution map, and a preliminary conservation assessment of the species. An identification key to all known species of Cyphostemma from the Ankarana Special Reserve is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69194/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69194/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/69194/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 16:32:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species and a new series of Elatostema (Urticaceae) from south-western China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65813/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 65-71</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.65813</p>
					<p>Authors: Dan-Hong Yin, Teng-Fei Huang, Zhen Lu, Lin-Dong Duan</p>
					<p>Abstract: The new series Elatostema section Weddellia series Xingyiensia L.D. Duan &amp; D.H. Yin (Urticaceae) is described. In addition, its new species Elatostema xingyiense L.D. Duan &amp; D.H. Yin, endemic to Guizhou Province, is also described and illustrated with photographs. The new series is morphologically similar to series Melanocarpa W.T. Wang and series Sublinearia W.T. Wang. The new species is most similar to E. melanocarpum, E. sublineare, E. obscurinerve, E. langicuspe and E. youyangense in morphology, but can be visibly distinguished by a combination of characters, including leaf vein, male inflorescences, female inflorescences and persistent tepals.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65813/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65813/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65813/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 11:20:57 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphology and molecules support the new monotypic genus Parainvolucrella (Rubiaceae) from Asia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67624/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 53-64</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.67624</p>
					<p>Authors: Yi-Da Xu, Ming-Deng Yuan, Rui-Jiang Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Parainvolucrella R.J. Wang, a new monotypic genus for P. scabra (Wall. ex Kurz) M.D.Yuan &amp; R.J.Wang, new combination, is segregated from the Hedyotis-Oldenlandia complex, based on morphological and molecular evidence. Phylogenetically, the new genus is sister to Scleromitrion, from which it differs by a combination of morphological characters: herbaceous habit, terminal inflorescence with subtended leaves, heterostylous flowers, indehiscent fruits and pollen with double microreticulate tectum. A key to the genera of the Hedyotis-Oldenlandia complex in China is provided for further identification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67624/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67624/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67624/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 11:20:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diversity of leaf anatomy within a single leaflet and between leaflets of four Butia (Arecaceae, Arecoideae) species</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66018/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 31-52</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.66018</p>
					<p>Authors: Larry R. Noblick, Bruno F. Sant’anna-Santos</p>
					<p>Abstract: This paper is an investigation into how the anatomy changes within a leaflet and between the leaflets of a single leaf blade of Butia. Four species of Butia were studied: Butia paraguayensis, B. eriospatha, B. yatay and B. odorata. Changes in the anatomical characters are important because some have been used in keys to help separate the species. Recently, anatomical mid-rib characters were used in a key to separate species of Butia. We found that characters, such as abaxially projected or rounded mid-rib fibrous ring or number and arrangement of accessory bundles, do change within a single leaflet or between the leaflets of a single leaf blade. Growing conditions and leaf developmental maturity are also important factors that influence leaflet anatomy and may cause one to be misled in an identification key based on anatomical characters. We re-emphasize the importance of always sampling from the same part of the leaf, to have a broader sampling, be attentive to the environmental condition and health of the plant from which you are sampling and to consider population differences.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66018/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66018/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66018/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 11:20:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An archipelago within an archipelago: A checklist of liverworts and hornworts of Kepulauan Sunda Kecil (Lesser Sunda Islands), Indonesia and Timor-Leste (East Timor)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65836/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 180: 1-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.180.65836</p>
					<p>Authors: Ainun Nadhifah, Lars Söderström, Anders Hagborg, Eka Aditya Putri Iskandar, Ida Haerida, Matt von Konrat</p>
					<p>Abstract: The first ever liverwort and hornwort checklist is provided for the Kepulauan Sunda Kecil (Lesser Sunda Islands) of Indonesia and Timor-Leste (East Timor). We report 129 accepted taxa, 12 doubtful taxa and three rejected taxa previously reported for the Lesser Sunda Islands. The list is based on over 130 literature references, including monographs, regional studies, and molecular investigations. It is clear that bryophytes from this region have been overlooked historically, and under collected, compared to seed plants, birds, and other organisms, forming a remarkable gap in the flora of Indonesia. Publications dealing with liverworts of Lesser Sunda Islands are few and scattered. We predict that further fieldwork, in addition to collections unveiled from regional herbaria, will uncover a number of new records that remain to be reported, especially considering that regionally widespread species have been recorded elsewhere.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65836/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65836/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65836/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 3 Aug 2021 11:20:11 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Vaccinium exiguum (Ericaceae, Vaccinieae), a new species from the ultramafic summit of Mt. Victoria, Palawan Island, Philippines</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68323/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 145-154</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.68323</p>
					<p>Authors: Maverick N. Tamayo, Rene Alfred Anton Bustamante, Peter W. Fritsch</p>
					<p>Abstract: Vaccinium exiguum from the ultramafic summit of Mt. Victoria, Palawan Island, Philippines is here described as a new species of Ericaceae. It closely resembles V. hamiguitanense but is distinct by having much shorter petioles and leaves, longer and glabrous calyx lobes with serrate lobe margins, a larger corolla with deeper sulcations, and longer stamens with spurs oriented laterally. Vaccinium exiguum represents the third Vaccinium species found on the Island of Palawan and 36th in the Philippines.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68323/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68323/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68323/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 09:13:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Big fruits with tiny tepals: An unusual new species of Lauraceae from southwestern China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62050/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 129-143</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.62050</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi Yang, Wei-Yin Jin, Bing Liu, David Kay Ferguson, Yong Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: We collected an unusual new plant of Phoebe (Lauraceae) from southeastern Yunnan, China, which possesses more or less oblong leaves, paniculate inflorescences with strictly opposite lateral cymes, trimerous flowers with 4-locular stamens, and large fruits with tiny, equal, persistent tepals. Our molecular phylogenetic study based on nrITS, LEAFY and plastid matK sequences suggests that this species belongs to a clade of Phoebe including P. puwenensis, P. megacalyx, and P. macrocarpa. However, this species differs from the latter three species by subglabrous twigs, leaves and inflorescences (vs. pubescent twigs, leaves and inflorescences in the latter three species), larger fruits (5–8 cm long vs. 1–4 cm long in the latter three species), and smaller tepals (1–2.5 mm long vs. 5–15 mm long in the latter two species). As a result, Phoebe jinpingensis sp. nov. is described and illustrated here as new to science.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62050/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62050/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62050/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 08:20:57 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphology of pollen in Ferula genus (Apiaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66312/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 111-128</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.66312</p>
					<p>Authors: Birol Başer, Mehmet Sagıroglu, Gulden Dogan, Hayri Duman</p>
					<p>Abstract: In this study, the pollen morphology of all Ferula species distributed throughout the country of Turkey was studied with light and scanning electron microscopy for the first time. The aim is to identify the pollen morphological characteristics of 23 Ferula species. The pollen is radially symmetrical, isopolar and tricolporate in all examined species. Pollen grains are prolate and perprolate with the polar axis ranging from 22.28 to 40.47 µm and the equatorial axis from 13.70 to 18.73 µm. Their polar shapes are triangular, triangular to subtriangular and circular to subcircular. Several types of exine ornamentations have been observed on pollen through the use of scanning electron microscopy. The dendrogram constructed by using Average Linkage of the examined data revealed two main groups. It was determined that some pollen characteristics are more useful for classification than others. In particular, P, E, the ratio of P/E (pollen shape) and ornamentation in the polar and equatorial views are the most valuable variables for discrimination the Ferula species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66312/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66312/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66312/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 09:37:39 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New circumscriptions add two northern Andean species to Kohleria (Gesneriaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65990/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 99-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.65990</p>
					<p>Authors: John L. Clark, Lou Jost</p>
					<p>Abstract: Recent studies of type specimens and exploratory research expeditions in the northern Andes have resulted in an updated circumscription and recognition for two species of Kohleria (Gesneriaceae) in Ecuador and Colombia. A change in the rank from a variety to species is recognized for Kohleria anisophylla (Fritsch) Wiehler. The combination Kohleria andina (Fritsch) J.L. Clark &amp; Jost, comb. nov. is provided here and a lectotype is designated. The updated circumscriptions of these two species are supported by morphology and geographic distribution. The presence of an epiphytic habit for Kohleria is discussed. Field images based on recent expeditions are provided to support the circumscriptions presented here.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65990/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65990/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65990/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:21:32 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Aphyllorchis yachangensis (Orchidaceae), a new holomycotrophic orchid from China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63994/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 91-97</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.63994</p>
					<p>Authors: Ying Qin, Hailing Chen, Zhenhai Deng, Yan Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Aphyllorchis yachangensis, a new holomycotrophic orchid from Guangxi, southern China is described and illustrated here. This new species is similar to A. caudata but differs from the latter mainly by the sepals acute at the apex, the hypochile with 2 smaller and semicircular wings, the epichile adaxially smooth, acute, the lateral lobes triangular-ovate and the column clavate.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63994/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63994/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63994/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 5 Jul 2021 08:57:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Thismia sitimeriamiae (Thismiaceae), an extraordinary new species from Terengganu, Peninsular Malaysia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68300/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 75-89</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.68300</p>
					<p>Authors: Mat Yunoh Siti-Munirah, Nikong Dome, Chris J. Thorogood</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe an extraordinary new species in the genus Thismia from the Terengganu State of Malaysia in the Malay Peninsula. The new species, which we name Thismia sitimeriamiae, is distinct from all other Thismia species known to science, most notably in its unique mitre configuration formed by the inner tepals and its floral surface morphology characterised by conspicuous orange trichomes. We discuss our findings in the context of underestimated species diversity in the genus Thismia and implications for their conservation. We recommend assigning T. sitimeriamiae the conservation status as Critically Endangered (CR) according to IUCN criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68300/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68300/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/68300/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 09:47:16 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic revision of Sageretia (Rhamnaceae) from China I: identities of S. lucida, S. thea var. cordiformis and S. yunlongensis, with the description of a new species S. ellipsoidea</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64750/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 13-28</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.64750</p>
					<p>Authors: Yi Yang, Hua Peng, Hang Sun</p>
					<p>Abstract: A taxonomic revision of Sageretia lucida, S. thea var. cordiformis and S. yunlongensis in China is presented. Sageretia lucida is revised in terms of morphological characters (habit, branchlet color, phyllotaxis and rachis length), distribution, habitat, and phenology; S. thea var. cordiformis is raised to S. cordiformis; and S. yunlongensis is excluded from the genus Sageretia and reduced to the synonym of Rhamnus nigricans. Furthermore, a new species, S. ellipsoidea, is erected based on the paratype collections of S. lucida. The new species morphologically differs from S. lucida in having reddish brown branchlets, opposite or subopposite phyllotaxis, shorter rachises, and flowering in spring or early summer. S. ellipsoidea is factually closest to S. hamosa as they share similar woody-vine habit and larger fruit size, and fruiting in winter, whereas the former can be easily recognized based on its smaller leaf blades, fewer lateral veins, shorter rachises, and ellipsoidal or elliptic-ovoid fruits.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64750/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64750/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64750/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:19:06 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Begonia catbensis (sect. Coelocentrum, Begoniaceae), a new species from northern Vietnam</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65812/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.65812</p>
					<p>Authors: Li-Na Dong, Khang Sinh Nguyen, Yu-Min Shui, Hieu Quang Nguyen, Wei‑Bin Xu, Xuan Khu Nguyen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Begonia catbensis, a new species in Begonia sect. Coelocentrum is described and illustrated. The new species was discovered in lowland limestone hills at Cat Ba National Park and can be easily distinguished from all its congeners by having dendritic hairs on the petiole, adaxial veins and stipules, fimbriate bracts and bracteoles, dense conical bullae on the upper surface of the leaf blade, two tepals in the pistillate flowers and a glabrescent ovary with verrucose wings. Based on IUCN Criteria, the species is currently assessed as “Endangered” (D).</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65812/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65812/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65812/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 09:54:29 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomy of Vincetoxicum s.str. (Asclepiadoideae, Apocynaceae) from southern Asia including three new species and resurrected names</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62514/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 35-73</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.62514</p>
					<p>Authors: Sayed Afzal Shah, Amir Sultan, Jun Wen, Zahid Ullah, Surat Un Nisa, Zhumei Ren, Muhammad Maqsood Alam, Javed Iqbal, Abdul Samad Mumtaz</p>
					<p>Abstract: This paper presents a taxonomic study of genus Vincetoxicum s.str. from southern Asia. Eleven regional endemic species are recognized on the basis of herbarium studies and fieldwork. Three new species are described: V. lenifolium sp. nov. (endemic to Pakistan), V. stewartianum sp. nov. (endemic to India), and V. subcanescens sp. nov. (endemic to Pakistan, Kashmir and Tibet). Three species names, V. cabulicum, V. glaucum and V. kenouriense, previously treated as synonyms of V. glaucum, V. canescens and V. hirundinaria, respectively, are resurrected. A neotype is designated for the Afghani endemic V. cabulicum. A lectotype is chosen from the syntypes of V. glaucum. We resolve the long-standing taxonomic problems in three species complexes: V. arnottianum, V. luridum, V. sakesarense, and V. stocksii; V. glaucum, V. canescens and V. cabulicum; and V. hirundinaria and V. kenouriense. Geo-taxonomic distinctions of southern Asian taxa are highlighted by excluding from henceforth the long misrecognized western Eurasian taxa V. canescens and V. hirundinaria. Furthermore, a detailed account of the genus including illustrations of whole plants, leaves and corona, distribution maps, a taxonomic key, morphological descriptions, synonymy, notes, and information on phenology, distribution and habitats is provided. Finally, provisional conservation assessments are provided, which indicate that V. cardiostephanum and V. sakesarense are critically endangered.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62514/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62514/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62514/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 09:54:05 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the recognition of the long neglected Vitis adenoclada Hand.-Mazz. (Vitaceae) from southern China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65519/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 179: 29-33</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.179.65519</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun Wen, Zhi-Yao Ma</p>
					<p>Abstract: This study reports the recognition of Vitis adenoclada Hand.-Mazz. from southern China. The species was not recognized in the Flora Reipublicae Ropularis Sinicicae and Flora of China treatments. Recent field studies and examination of herbarium collections including the type material suggest that Vitis adenoclada is morphologically similar to V. heyneana, in their densely arachnoid tomentose abaxial leaves, yet it can be easily distinguished from the latter by its red-purple glandular hairs on the young branches (vs. glandular hairs absent in V. heyneana) and inflorescences usually subtended by a tendril at the base (vs. only occasionally with a tendril in V. heyneana). Vitis adenoclada may be a species of hybrid origin, with the highly tomentose Vitis heyneana as one of the parental species, and likely the glandular-hair bearing V. davidii as the other parental species. Vitis adenoclada is recorded from southern China in Guangdong, Guangxi, Guizhou, Hunan and Zhejiang provinces.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65519/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65519/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65519/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 09:37:35 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Begonia shenzhenensis, a new species of Begoniaceae from Guangdong, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66462/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 171-177</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.66462</p>
					<p>Authors: Dai-Ke Tian, Bin Chen, Yan Xiao, Min-Min Zheng, Bin-Jie Ge</p>
					<p>Abstract: Begonia shenzhenensis D.K.Tian &amp; X.Yun Wang, sp. nov., a new species in Begonia sect. Platycentrum of Begoniaceae from Shenzhen of Guangdong province, China, is described and illustrated. Morphologically, it is primarily similar to B. coelocentroides in the same section but differs by its denser hairs on leaf, petiole, and pedicel, abtuse anther apex, hairy ovary, and narrower adaxial fruit wing. Based on only one small population found to date, its conservation status is assigned to Critical Endangered according to the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66462/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66462/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/66462/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 4 Jun 2021 10:13:07 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Smelowskia sunhangii (Brassicaceae), a new species from China, with a re-evaluation of the S. tibetica complex</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62922/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 179-191</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.62922</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin-jian Zhang, Jun-Tong Chen, Ihsan A. Al-Shehbaz, Qun Liu, Li-Juan Li, Peng-Ju Liu, Xian-Han Huang, Tao Deng</p>
					<p>Abstract: Smelowskia sunhangii, from Qinghai and Tibet (China), is described and illustrated. Morphological and molecular data indicate that S. sunhangii is closely related to Smelowskia tibetica, from which it is easily distinguished by the densely hirsute (vs. glabrous or sparsely pubescent), elliptic to ovate-lanceolate (vs. suborbicular, oblong, or lanceolate) fruits with undulate (vs. straight) margins. A re-evaluation of the widely distributed S. tibetica and related taxa is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62922/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62922/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62922/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 4 Jun 2021 09:27:37 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An unknown hotspot of plant diversity in the heart of the Central Apennine: flora and vegetation outline of Mt. Pozzoni-St. Rufo valley (Cittareale, Rieti)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62947/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 111-146</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.62947</p>
					<p>Authors: Edda Lattanzi, Eva Del Vico, Roberto Tranquilli, Emmanuele Farris, Michela Marignani, Leonardo Rosati</p>
					<p>Abstract: Surprisingly enough, Italy still has some botanically unexplored areas; among these there are some territories between Lazio, Umbria and Abruzzo not included in any protected area. The study area, ranging for 340 ha, includes the mountainous area of Mt. Pozzoni-Mt. Prato-St. Rufo valley, which forms the upper part of the river Velino basin, located in the territory of the municipality of Cittareale (Rieti, Lazio), at an elevation from 1150 to 1903 m a.s.l. The substrate is mainly made of marly limestone of the Meso-Cenozoic Umbria-Marche sedimentary succession. The climate is Temperate and comprises vegetation belts from the montane to sub-alpine. Land cover is dominated by pastures and deciduous forests, with only a few hay meadows. 794 entities have been detected: 16% are considered rare or very rare for the regional territory with several floristic novelties for the regional flora, 6% of the total was found to be endemic to Italy and only eight taxa were aliens. Four taxa are new for the regional flora of Lazio: Arum cylindraceum, Alopecurus pratensis subsp. pratensis, Hieracium bupleuroides and Trinia glauca subsp. glauca. Forest vegetation is represented by beech forests, while dry grasslands are the most widespread vegetation type. The greatest phytocoenotic diversity was found within the secondary pastures. Particularly interesting is the plant community with Iris marsica, which suggests that limestone mountain ledges can represent a primary habitat for this endemic species of the Central Apennine. The presence of several habitats listed in the EU Habitat Directive indicates how the lack of detailed territorial knowledge can lead to the non-designation of conservation sites in areas of high naturalistic value. These findings showed that botanical explorations in territories which are still not known could contribute significantly to the identification of areas of high interest in conserving plant diversity.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62947/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62947/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/62947/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 11:40:09 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Otoba (Myristicaceae) from Colombia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64564/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 147-170</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.64564</p>
					<p>Authors: Daniel Santamaría-Aguilar, Laura P. Lagomarsino</p>
					<p>Abstract: Otoba is the third largest genus of Myristicaceae in the Neotropics with 12 species, nine of them native to Colombia. Two new species from the department of Antioquia, O. scottmorii sp. nov. and O. squamosa sp. nov., are described and illustrated. Otoba scottmorii occurs in humid, lowland forests, while O. squamosa occurs in premontane forest. Previously, Otoba scottmorii was confused with O. acuminata (which here is considered restricted to Costa Rica and Panama), while O. squamosa was confused with O. gordoniifolia. The similarities and differences between these and other species are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64564/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64564/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64564/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:12:45 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Finding missing diversity from synonyms of Haplopteris (Pteridaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67622/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 81-94</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.67622</p>
					<p>Authors: Zuo-Ying Wei, Zeng-Qiang Xia, Xian-Chun Zhang, Jian-Guo Cao, Yue-Hong Yan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Although taxonomists target the remote wild regions to discover new species, taxa lacking a comprehensive and modern systematic treatment may be the new hotspot for biodiversity discovery. The development of molecular systematics integrated with microscopic observation techniques has greatly improved the ability of taxonomists to identify species correctly. Vittaria centrochinensis Ching ex J.F. Cheng, regarded as a synonym of Haplopteris fudzinoi (Makino) E.H.Crane, remained hidden from the eyes of fern taxonomists for more than 20 years. Herein, we collected several population samples of V. centrochinensis by performing molecular phylogenetic analysis of five cpDNA regions (rbcL, atpA, matK, ndhF, and trnL-trnF) and through micromophological observation of specimens which differs from H. fudzinoi by lamina width and exospores. Considering the differences in morphology, geographical range, and genetic distance between these two species, we formally recognized V. centrochinensis as an authentic species and proposed a new combination Haplopteris centrochinensis (Ching ex J.F.Cheng) Y.H.Yan, Z.Y.Wei &amp; X.C.Zhang, comb. nov. Our findings demonstrate that several taxa in synonyms are missing, and nowadays taxonomy should also include re-evaluation of the past taxonomy.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67622/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67622/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/67622/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 12:46:13 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Typifications of some species names in Anthurium section Pachyneurium (Araceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65087/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 95-109</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.65087</p>
					<p>Authors: Mel de Castro Camelo, Lívia Godinho Temponi, Simon Joseph Mayo, Marcus Alberto Nadruz Coelho, José Fernando A. Baumgratz</p>
					<p>Abstract: During a taxonomic study of Anthurium sect. Pachyneurium, it was found that the names of four species required typification. Verification of the protologues and cited collections is discussed and typifications are proposed as follows: the illustration Schott Icones Aroideae No. 465 is designated as the neotype of A. affine Schott. A lectotype is designated for A. bonplandii G.S.Bunting since the holotype, cited in the protologue at MY, was not found there. An epitype is selected for A. solitarium Schott because the lectotype illustration of J.M.C. Vellozo (Flora Fluminensis t. 123) lacks sufficient detail to determine it unambiguously to species in A. sect. Pachyneurium. A lectotype is selected for A. glaziovii Hook.f., a synonym of A. solitarium.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65087/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65087/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/65087/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 10:32:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Artabotrys pachypetalus (Annonaceae), a new species from China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64485/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 71-80</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.64485</p>
					<p>Authors: Bine Xue, Gang-Tao Wang, Xin-Xin Zhou, Yi Huang, Yi Tong, Yongquan Li, Junhao Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Artabotrys pachypetalus sp. nov. is described from Guangdong, Guangxi, Guizhou, Hunan and Jiangxi in China. A detailed description, distribution data, along with a color plate and a line drawing are provided. In China, specimens representing this species were formerly misidentified as A. multiflorus or A. hongkongensis (= A. blumei). Artabotrys blumei typically has a single flower per inflorescence, whereas both Artabotrys pachypetalus and A. multiflorus have multiple flowers per inflorescence. In addition, A. pachypetalus is readily distinguished from A. multiflorus in having thicker and shorter petals, and connivent and somewhat trigonal or terete inner petal blades. Artabotrys pachypetalus is most similar to A. punctulatus because both have multi-flowered inflorescences and similar petal length, but A. pachypetalus differs in having cream petals in vivo, connivent inner petal blades, and a short, raised rim above the inner petal claw. Artabotrys multiflorus should be excluded from the flora of China because none of the Chinese specimens of Artabotrys collected so far fall within the variation of A. multiflorus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64485/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64485/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64485/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 09:28:37 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Centric diatom diversity in the lower part of the Southern Bug river (Ukraine): the transitional zone at Mykolaiv city</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64426/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 31-69</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.64426</p>
					<p>Authors: Olena P. Bilous, Sergey I. Genkal, Jonas Zimmermann, Wolf-Henning Kusber, Regine Jahn</p>
					<p>Abstract: The diversity of centric diatoms is documented for the transitional zone of the lower part of the Southern Bug River (Ukraine) just before entering the Dnipro-Bug Estuary and compared to earlier results from the upstream sampling sites of the same river system. Benthic samples of the following sites were investigated: north of Mykolaiv City (approximately 5 km), in Mykolaiv City (near Varvarivskyi Bridge), and 5 km south of the city. Twenty-four centric diatom taxa belonging to 11 genera were identified, analysed, and documented by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and light microscopy (LM). Among them, Aulacoseira nivalis is the first report for Ukraine, A. islandica and is the first confirmed record for the studied area since the 1930s. The maximum number of centric diatom taxa found in one station was 21, the minimum 10. Melosira subglobosa was the most common (documented in 57–80% of sites with centric diatoms) and abundant species 7.3–15.7% in relative abundance to all diatom taxa. The discovered diversity of taxa and its comparison with previous results is discussed with regard to the relevance of estuary zones in the research of diatoms.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64426/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64426/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64426/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:19 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Hybridization of Oxalis corniculata and O. dillenii in their non-native range</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/61031/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 17-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.61031</p>
					<p>Authors: Quentin Groom, Sofie Meeus, Steven B. Janssens, Leen Leus, Ivan Hoste</p>
					<p>Abstract: Many species have been introduced beyond their native ranges and many have become global weeds. Human mediated dispersal has removed the geographic isolation of these species, reversing millions of years of independent evolution. Examples are the Oxalis species in section Corniculatae where several species have become invasive. Here we characterize and formally describe a hybrid between O. dillenii and O. corniculata, which occurs spontaneously in Belgium and Japan. Oxalis corniculata is probably native to Japan, but both species are alien to Belgium and O. dillenii is native to North America. We formally name this hybrid as Oxalis × vanaelstii. Although this hybrid is sterile, it is nevertheless vigorous and perennial. Both parent species grow as weeds in gardens; therefore, it is likely to be more common than currently appreciated in countries where these species co-occur.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/61031/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/61031/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/61031/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 10:21:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Athenaea Sendtn. (Solanaceae) from the Atlantic forests of south-eastern Brazil</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64609/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 178: 1-15</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.178.64609</p>
					<p>Authors: Izabella Martins da Costa Rodrigues, Sandra Knapp, João Renato Stehmann</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Athenaea Sendtn. (Solanaceae) from the Brazilian Atlantic Forest are described and illustrated. Athenaea altoserranae I.M.C. Rodrigues &amp; Stehmann, sp. nov. from the Serra do Mar range, in São Paulo State and Athenaea hunzikeriana I.M.C. Rodrigues &amp; Stehmann, sp. nov. from a restricted area in the north-eastern region of Minas Gerais State and the southern part of Bahia State. Both species have brown to purple-brown or purple mature fruits, a character not found in other species of Athenaea. Descriptions, illustrations, complete specimen citations and maps of both species are provided. A dichotomous key to all species of Athenaea is also presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64609/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64609/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64609/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:40:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Lagenophora (Asteraceae, Astereae) in New Caledonia</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63116/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 125-138</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.63116</p>
					<p>Authors: Guillaume Lannuzel, Gildas Gâteblé, Anthony R. Bean, Jian Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Lagenophora Cass. is taxonomically revised for New Caledonia with two species recognised. Lagenophora sinuosa Lannuzel, Gâteblé &amp; Jian Wang ter, sp. nov. is endemic to New Caledonia and the other, L. sublyrata (Cass.) A.R.Bean &amp; Jian Wang ter occurs there and in many other countries from the region. Both are fully described and illustrated. An identification key is provided, as are notes on the distribution (including maps), habitat, phenology and conservation status. The generic placement of the new species is also discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63116/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63116/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63116/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:48:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On a noteworthy habitat type in the savannahs of Central Cuba and a remarkable new species of Elytraria (Acanthaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64764/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 117-124</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.64764</p>
					<p>Authors: Werner Greuter, Rankin Rodríguez</p>
					<p>Abstract: A peculiar habitat type found in the savannahs of Central Cuba, Villa Clara Province and characterised by the presence of a surface gravel layer of “perdigones”, an assemblage of small ferralitic concretions, upon the “mocarrero” soil prevailing in the area, is described. On sterile gravel patches, only one species grows: Elytraria serpens, a new species described and named here. It is noteworthy for possessing long and wide creeping, stoloniform subterranean peduncles with apical gemmae developing into rooting leaf rosettes enabling vegetative propagation. The new species is close to E. shaferi and considered to derive from the latter by adaptive evolution, enabling it to survive in its hostile habitat, sheltered from the competition of other plant species. Small soil insects, for example, ants, are believed to act as pollinators.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64764/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64764/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64764/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:32:59 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic revision of Martinella Baill. (Bignonieae, Bignoniaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64465/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 77-116</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.64465</p>
					<p>Authors: Eric Y. Kataoka, Lúcia G. Lohmann</p>
					<p>Abstract: Martinella Baill. is a genus of Neotropical lianas in tribe Bignonieae (Bignoniaceae). The genus is monophyletic and well supported by morphological and molecular characters. Members of Martinella are characterized by a continuous interpetiolar ridge surrounding the stem, bilobed or 4–5-parted calyces, and minute triangular prophylls of the axillary buds. Generic circumscription remained unchanged since the description of the genus, although unclear species limits remained. Based on extensive fieldwork, herbarium work, and a molecular phylogenetic hypothesis for the genus, we here recognize five species of Martinella. Of these, three were recognized in earlier treatments for the genus, while two represent new species described here, Martinella lanuginosa Kataoka &amp; L.G.Lohmann, sp. nov. and Martinella tomentosa Kataoka &amp; L.G.Lohmann, sp. nov. Martinella iquitoensis A.Samp. is treated as a synonym of M. insculpta Sprague &amp; Sandwith. In addition, one second-step lectotype is designated for Bignonia martini DC., and neotypes are designated for Doxantha longisiliqua Miers and Martinella gollmeri K.Schum. This work provides a full taxonomic treatment for Martinella, including a complete list of synonyms, morphological descriptions, illustrations, photographs, distribution maps, conservation status, and comments for all five species recognized.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64465/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64465/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/64465/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Monograph</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:44:07 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Chayamaritia vietnamensis (Gesneriaceae), a new species from Son La Province, northern Vietnam</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63401/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 43-53</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.63401</p>
					<p>Authors: Zi-Bing Xin, Long-Fei Fu, Stephen Maciejewski, Zhang-Jie Huang, Truong Van Do, Fang Wen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Chayamaritia vietnamensis, a new species from Son La Province, northern Vietnam, is described and illustrated. The phylogenetic study revealed that the new species is most closely related to C. banksiae and C. smitinandii. The morphological comparison suggests it as the third new species of Chayamaritia and distinguished from C. banksiae and C. smitinandii by a combination of morphological characters of leaf blades, bracts, calyx and corolla, especially its peltate leaf blades. This species is provisionally assessed as endangered (EN B1ab(iii), B2ab(iii)) using IUCN Categories and Criteria. Information on ecology, phenology and an identification key for the known Chayamaritia species are also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63401/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63401/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63401/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:38:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Primulina papillosa (Gesneriaceae), a new species from limestone areas of Guangxi, China</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63878/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 55-61</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.63878</p>
					<p>Authors: Zi-Bing Xin, Wei-Chuen Chou, Stephen Maciejewski, Long-Fei Fu, Fang Wen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Primulina papillosa Z.B. Xin, W.C. Chou &amp; F. Wen, a new species from limestone areas of Guangxi, China, is described and illustrated here. It morphologically resembles P. linearifolia (W.T. Wang) Yin Z. Wang and P. pseudolinearifolia W.B. Xu &amp; K.F. Chung, but can be easily distinguished by some combined characters, especially its leaf blades densely papillose-hispid. We found only one population at the type locality with no more than 200 individuals, so that this new species is provisionally assessed as Critically Endangered (CR) using IUCN Criteria.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63878/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63878/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/63878/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:03:39 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic Identity of Carpinus dayongina Franchet (Betulaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/57725/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>PhytoKeys 177: 63-75</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/phytokeys.177.57725</p>
					<p>Authors: Qianqian He, Runan Zhao, Anguo He, Zunling Zhu, Yihua Tong</p>
					<p>Abstract: Carpinus polyneura and C. dayongina are recognised as separate species in Flora of China. In this study, the results of an examination of literature, morphological comparison and phenetic clustering of nuclear ITS sequences suggest that C. dayongina is conspecific with C. polyneura. Thus, we propose reducing C. dayongina to a synonym of C. polyneura.</p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/57725/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/57725/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://phytokeys.pensoft.net/article/57725/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 09:37:40 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
	