
<rss version="0.91">
    <channel>
        <title>Latest Articles from ZooKeys</title>
        <description>Latest 100 Articles from ZooKeys</description>
        <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:59:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Pensoft FeedCreator</generator>
        <image>
            <url>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/i/logo.jpg</url>
            <title>Latest Articles from ZooKeys</title>
            <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Feed provided by https://zookeys.pensoft.net/. Click to visit.]]></description>
        </image>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Gems of the southern Japanese seas – four new species of Edwardsianthus (Anthozoa, Actiniaria, Edwardsiidae) with redescriptions of two species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69025/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 151-182</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.69025</p>
					<p>Authors: Takato Izumi, Takuma Fujii</p>
					<p>Abstract: Edwardsianthus England, 1987 is a genus of Edwardsiidae, a family of burrowing and worm-like sea anemones characterized by lacking four mesenteries in the first cycle and containing only one type of nematocysts in nemathybomes. Until now, this genus has accommodated only two species since its establishment and has been recorded only from Indo-West Pacific regions. In this study, six species are reported from Japan: two are previously known species, E. pudicus (Klunzinger, 1877) and E. gilbertensis (Carlgren, 1931); four are new species, E. carbunculus sp. nov., E. sapphirus sp. nov., E. smaragdus sp. nov., and E. amethystus sp. nov. Based on these results, the diagnostic features of the genus are revised.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69025/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69025/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69025/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 02:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿The re-description of Synoecnema hirsutum Timm, 1959 (Synoecneminae, Ungellidae, Drilonematoidea) from a pheretimoid earthworm in Vietnam with the analysis of its phylogenetic relationships</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75932/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 135-150</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.75932</p>
					<p>Authors: Elena S. Ivanova, Boris D. Efeykin, Sergei E. Spiridonov</p>
					<p>Abstract: Synoecnema hirsutum Timm, 1959 (Ungellidae, Drilonematoidea), found in the body cavity of the pheretimoid earthworm at the border of Laos and Vietnam, was re-described and illustrated. The mitochondrial genome of S. hirsutum obtained with Illumina HiSeq sequencing is the first annotated mitochondrial genome as a representative of the superfamily Drilonematoidea. The phylogeny inferred from the analysis of 12 mitochondrial genes has shown some similarity of S. hirsutum with a cephalobid Acrobeloides varius.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75932/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75932/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75932/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:57:30 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Discovery of the genus Platycotylus Olliff, 1883 (Coleoptera, Tenebrionidae) in Japan: Description of a new and remarkable species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75846/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 125-133</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.75846</p>
					<p>Authors: Takahiro Yoshida, Kiyoshi Ando</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Platycotylus Olliff, 1883 (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae) is recorded from Japan (Nakanoshima Island, Tokara Islands) for the first time, through the discovery of a new and remarkable species, Platycotylus merkli sp. nov., which is described herein. The male of this new species can be distinguished from all known males of other congeneric species by its long and asymmetrical epistomal horn. Although this new species is most similar to Platycotylus parvicollis (Pic, 1923), for which a male has not been examined, it can be distinguished from this species by its simple sparse pronotal punctation, smaller eyes, and acutely produced temples.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75846/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75846/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75846/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:51:50 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿New relictual genera in Cyrtoquediini and Indoquediini (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylininae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73103/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 109-124</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.73103</p>
					<p>Authors: Adam J. Brunke</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sundaquedius gen. nov. (Cyrtoquediini) and Fluviphirus gen. nov. (Indoquediini) are described from southeast Asia and western North America, respectively, resulting in the new combinations Sundaquedius nigropolitus (Cameron) and Fluviphirus elevatus (Hatch). Sundaquedius abbreviatus sp. nov. is described from Vietnam. The phylogenetic positions of these genera within Staphylininae are supported by morphology and recently published phylogenomic evidence. New keys to the world genera of Cyrtoquediini and Indoquediini are provided. A new country record for Alesiella lineipennis (Cameron) is provided for Thailand, based on the first available specimen in more than 100 years.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73103/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73103/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73103/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:48:31 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First record of the genus Discorhabdella (Porifera, Demospongiae, Poecilosclerida, Crambeidae) from Sagami Bay, Japan with description of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/37278/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 67-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.37278</p>
					<p>Authors: Yuji Ise, Jean Vacelet, Takato Izumi, Sau Pinn Woo, Shau Hwai Tan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Discorhabdella are described from Sagami Bay, Japan. Discorhabdella has been suggested to have an ancient Tethyan origin according to discovery of their unique pseudoastrose acanthostyles from late Eocene to Oligocene deposits. This is the first record of the genus from the northwest Pacific and first record of the family Crambeidae from Japan. Discorhabdella hispida sp. nov. is distinctive within the genus by possession of special sigmoid microscleres and C-shaped isochelae with short alae. Discorhabdella misakiensis sp. nov. is characterized by short choanosomal subtylostyles, and their length overlapped with that of the ectosomal subtylostyles. Only one other species, Discorhabdella tuberosocapitata (Topsent, 1890), has the same spicule composition. However, all spicule types are larger in D. tuberosocapitata than those of D. misakiensis sp. nov., and the shape of the isochelae is different: the alae are more widely opened in D. tuberosocapitata. An identification key to species of the genus Discorhabdella is also provided. The discovery of two new species from warm temperate northwest Pacific extends the geographical distribution of the genus Discorhabdella.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/37278/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/37278/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/37278/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:46:29 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Two new Cypridopsinae Kaufmann, 1900 (Crustacea, Ostracoda) from southern Africa</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76123/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 83-107</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.76123</p>
					<p>Authors: Agata Szwarc, Koen Martens, Tadeusz Namiotko</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new Cypridopsinae ostracods, Potamocypris meissneri sp. nov. and Sarscypridopsis harundineti sp. nov. are described. Both were found only as asexual (all-female) populations in temporary waters of southern Africa. Potamocypris meissneri was collected from a small pan in the North-West Province of South Africa. It is approximately 0.5 mm long and belongs to the species group with long swimming setae on the second antennae. However, the species has a somewhat isolated position in the genus owing to the conspicuously reticulated carapace, which is furthermore densely covered by prominent conuli with normal pores carrying long sensilla, as well as to the wide anterior and posterior flanges on the left valve. To allow identification of the new species in relation to its closest congeners, a key to the species of the genus Potamocypris Brady, 1870 from southern Africa is provided. The genus Sarscypridopsis McKenzie, 1977 mostly has an Afrotropical distribution with only few species occurring in other regions. Sarscypridopsis harundineti was collected from floodplains of the outskirts of the Okavango Delta in Botswana. It is approximately 0.4 mm long and can be distinguished from congeners mainly by the smaller and more oval-shaped valves. We conclude that southern African Cypridopsinae urgently need integrated taxonomic revision, by means of both morphological characters and DNA-sequence data.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76123/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76123/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76123/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 9 Dec 2021 11:34:51 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Rediscovering the dancing semislug genus Cryptosemelus Collinge, 1902 (Eupulmonata, Ariophantidae) from Thailand with description of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75576/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 43-65</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.75576</p>
					<p>Authors: Arthit Pholyotha, Chirasak Sutcharit, Somsak Panha</p>
					<p>Abstract: Knowledge of Thai semislugs remains scarce, especially the dancing semislug genus Cryptosemelus. Prior to the present study, only a single species has been recognized with little available information. To address this knowledge gap, we surveyed for semislugs in western and southern Thailand, which yielded three species belonging to the genus Cryptosemelus. The little-known type species C. gracilis is redescribed herein, including a comparison with the type specimens. Two additional species, C. betarmon sp. nov. and C. tigrinus sp. nov., are described as new to science. All three species are characterized by differences in their genital anatomy, especially with respect to anatomical details of the penis, epiphallus, and spermatophore. In addition, C. tigrinus sp. nov. differs from C. gracilis and C. betarmon sp. nov. in the mantle color pattern.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75576/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75576/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75576/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Dec 2021 11:34:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Taxonomic and genetic assessment of captive White-Handed Gibbons (Hylobates lar) in Peninsular Malaysia with implications towards conservation translocation and reintroduction programmes</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73262/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 25-41</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.73262</p>
					<p>Authors: Millawati Gani, Jeffrine J. Rovie-Ryan, Frankie Thomas Sitam, Noor Azleen Mohd Kulaimi, Chew Cheah Zheng, Aida Nur Atiqah, Nur Maisarah Abd Rahim, Ahmad Azhar Mohammed</p>
					<p>Abstract: Conservation translocation and reintroduction for the purpose of repopulating and reinforcing extirpated or depleted populations has been recognised as an important conservation tool, particularly for gibbon conservation in the immediate future. Feasibility assessments involving multiple factors, including taxonomic and genetic assessment of rescued and captive gibbons, are imperative prior to translocation and reintroduction programmes. In this study, we attempt to determine the subspecies and origin of captive Hylobates lar, White-handed gibbons, from Peninsular Malaysia to assist in future translocation and reintroduction programmes. A total of 12 captive and rescued H. lar samples were analysed using the control region segment of mitochondrial DNA. Sequence analyses and phylogenetic trees constructed using neighbour-joining, maximum likelihood, Bayesian inference, and network methods congruently differentiate all 12 captive individuals used in this study from other H. lar subspecies suggesting that these individuals belong to the H. lar lar subspecies. In addition, two populations of H. l. lar were observed: (1) a southern population consisting of all 12 individuals from Peninsular Malaysia, and (2) a possible northern population represented by three individuals (from previous studies), which might have originated from the region between the Isthmus of Kra, Surat Thani-Krabi depression, and Kangar-Pattani. Our findings suggest that the complete control region segment can be used to determine the subspecies and origin of captive H. lar.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73262/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73262/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73262/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Dec 2021 11:32:31 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Designation of the neotype of Triatoma dimidiata (Latreille, 1811) (Hemiptera, Reduviidae, Triatominae), with full integrated redescription including mitogenome and nuclear ITS-2 sequences</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72835/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 9-24</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.72835</p>
					<p>Authors: Silvia Andrade Justi, Carolina Dale</p>
					<p>Abstract: The taxonomic status of Triatoma dimidiata (Latreille, 1811) is, by far, the most discussed within Triatominae. Molecular studies have recovered at least three independently evolving lineages in T. dimidiata across its range. The original description of T. dimidiata (as Reduvius dimidiatus) included few taxonomic characters, and no types were assigned. To define and describe the cryptic diversity within T. dimidiata sensu lato (s.l.), a neotype must be designated. For this purpose, all 199 specimens identified as T. dimidiata from the collections of the Smithsonian Institution – National Museum of Natural History and the American Museum of Natural History, ranging from Peru to Mexico, were studied. Only one specimen (from Tumbes, Peru) matched the combination of characters as listed in the original description, and it is herein formally designated as the neotype for T. dimidiata. The neotype is morphologically described and DNA sequences of its whole mitochondrial genome and the nuclear second internal transcribed spacer region (ITS2), commonly used in triatomine molecular systematics studies, are presented and compared to other publicly available sequences of T. dimidiata s.l. in GenBank. Our results suggest that T. dimidiata sensu stricto (s.s.) is somewhat rare and, therefore, unlikely to serve as a major vector of Chagas disease.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72835/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72835/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72835/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Dec 2021 11:30:39 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿ Neothelaxes pileata, a new species from China (Hemiptera, Sternorrhyncha, Aphididae, Thelaxinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72802/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1076: 1-8</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1076.72802</p>
					<p>Authors: Li-Yun Jiang, Xiao-Lu Zhang, Jing Chen, Yi-Fang Zhao, Ge-Xia Qiao</p>
					<p>Abstract: Neothelaxes pileata Qiao sp. nov., found on Pilea martinii (Urticaceae) in China, is described and illustrated. Neothelaxes Chakrabarti &amp; Quednau is also a new generic record for China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72802/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72802/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72802/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Dec 2021 11:30:05 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿A contribution to the knowledge of cave-adapted ground beetles from Guiyang, central Guizhou Province, southwestern China (Coleoptera, Carabidae, Trechini)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73318/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1075: 175-198</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1075.73318</p>
					<p>Authors: Mingyi Tian, Guangyuan Cheng, Sunbin Huang</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new genus and two new species of cavernicolous trechines are reported from central Guizhou Province, southwestern China. Haixiaphaenops gen. nov. is established to place a new species discovered in two limestone caves in northern Qingzhen Shi: H. jinxiaohongae sp. nov. (Dawan Dong cave and Changtu Dong and Dawan Dong caves). This new genus is allied to Zhijinaphaenops Uéno &amp; Ran, 2002. Zhijinaphaenops zhaofeii sp. nov. is described from Zhangkou Dong cave in northern Jiuzhuang Zhen of Xifeng County. In addition, two new localities of the species Zhijinaphaenops jingliae Deuve &amp; Tian, 2015, and two new localities of Sinaphaenops chengguangyuani Ma et al. 2020 are provided. A distribution map for all cavernicolous trechine beetles known in Guiyang is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73318/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73318/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73318/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Review Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 7 Dec 2021 11:14:34 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿A review of the genus Hesperosoma Scheerpeltz (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae, Staphylininae) of China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75799/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1075: 137-174</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1075.75799</p>
					<p>Authors: Yu-Jie Cai, Liang Tang, Harald Schillhammer</p>
					<p>Abstract: A review of 16 species of Hesperosoma Scheerpeltz from China is presented. Five new species are described: H. (s.str.) chenchangchini sp. nov. from Yunnan, H. (s.str.) languidum sp. nov. from Yunnan, H. (s.str.) motuoense sp. nov. from Xizang, H. (Paramichrotus) parvioculatum sp. nov. from Hubei, Hunan and H. (s.str.) xizangense sp. nov. from Xizang. Two species are new to China: H. (Paramichrotus) brunkei Schillhammer, 2015 from Yunnan and H. (s.str.) kleebergi Schillhammer, 2009 from Xizang. Females of H. (Paramichrotus) alexpuchneri Schillhammer, 2009, H. (Paramichrotus) guizhouense Schillhammer, 2018 and H. (s.str.) flavoterminale Schillhammer, 2004 are described for the first time. Habitus and diagnostic characters of all species are photographed and a key to Chinese species of Hesperosoma is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75799/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75799/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75799/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 7 Dec 2021 11:13:26 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Addendum to a minimalist revision of Costa Rican Braconidae: 28 new species and 23 host records</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72197/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1075: 77-136</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1075.72197</p>
					<p>Authors: Michael J. Sharkey, Austin Baker, Kathryn McCluskey, Alex Smith, Suresh Naik, Sujeevan Ratnasingham, Ramya Manjunath, Kate Perez, Jayme Sones, Michelle D'Souza, Brianne St. Jacques, Paul Hebert, Winnie Hallwachs, Daniel Janzen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Twenty-nine species are treated, most of which have host caterpillar and food plant records, and all but one are new to science. The first host record for the agathidine genus Amputoearinus is given. Gnathopleura josequesadai Sharkey, sp. nov. is reported as a hyperparasitoid of fly larvae, the first such record for the genus. The following new species are diagnosed primarily using COI barcode data; Sharkey is the authority for all: Agathidinae: Aerophilus davidwagneri, Aerophilus fundacionbandorum, Aerophilus nicklaphami, Lytopylus davidstopaki, Lytopylus davidschindeli; Alysiinae: Gnathopleura josequesadai; Braconinae: Bracon andreamezae, Bracon franklinpaniaguai, Bracon rafagutierrezi, Bracon guillermoblancoi, Bracon oscarmasisi, Bracon pauldimaurai, Bracon shebadimaurae, Sacirema karendimaurae; Cheloninae: Chelonus minorzunigai; Homolobinae: Homolobus stevestroudi; Macrocentrinae: Macrocentrus michaelstroudi; Orgilinae: Stantonia gilbertfuentesi; Rhysipolinae: Rhysipolis stevearonsoni; Rogadinae: Aleiodes kaydodgeae, Aleiodes kerrydresslerae, Aleiodes josesolanoi, Aleiodes juniorporrasi, Aleiodes rocioecheverri, Aleiodes ronaldzunigai, Choreborogas jesseausubeli, Triraphis doncombi, and Yelicones mayrabonillae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72197/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72197/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72197/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 7 Dec 2021 11:11:38 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Bringing order to a complex system: phenotypic and genotypic evidence contribute to the taxonomy of Tityus (Scorpiones, Buthidae) and support the description of a new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67459/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1075: 33-75</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1075.67459</p>
					<p>Authors: Jairo A. Moreno-González, Ricardo Pinto-da-Rocha, Jonas E. Gallão</p>
					<p>Abstract: We present a molecular phylogenetic analysis including a survey for overlooked phenotypic characters. Based on both analysis and characters a new cave-dwelling species is described: Tityus (Tityus) spelaeus sp. nov. from the Russão II cave, Posse, state of Goiás, Central Brazil. Characters such as the glandular regions of the female pectinal basal piece and basal middle lamellae of pectines, and the distribution of the ventral setae of telotarsi I–IV proved to be useful to constructing the taxonomy of species and species groups of Tityus. The new species is a member of the Tityus trivittatus species-group of Tityus (Tityus) and can be readily recognized by the immaculate coloration pattern and the more developed glandular region on the female pectinal basal piece. In addition, we provide a discussion of the phylogenetic relationships observed within Tityus, on the relevance of the new phenotypic characters to the modern taxonomy of the genus Tityus, and to the records of Brazilian cave scorpions.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67459/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67459/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67459/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 7 Dec 2021 11:09:32 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Taxonomic revision of Romaleosyrphus Bigot (Diptera, Syrphidae), including descriptions of seven new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/55862/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1075: 1-32</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1075.55862</p>
					<p>Authors: Kevin M. Moran, Jeffrey H. Skevington</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Romaleosyrphus Bigot is reviewed, including the description of seven new species (R. argosi Moran, sp. nov., R. bigoti Moran, sp. nov., R. drysus Moran, sp. nov., R. nephelaeus Moran &amp; Thompson, sp. nov., R. soletluna Moran &amp; Thompson, sp. nov., R. vockerothi Moran &amp; Thompson, sp. nov. and R. woodi Moran, sp. nov.). Romaleosyrphus arctophiloides (Giglio-Tos), comb. nov. is transferred to Romaleosyrphus. Romaleosyrphus stat. rev. is redefined to represent the monophyletic unit of species within Criorhinina which possess holoptic males, a proximal ventral half of vein C with setae, a broad intersection of vein R1 with vein C, the distal part of R4+5 beyond M1 longer than cross-vein h and appressed pile on the abdomen. Descriptions, habitus and genitalia photographs, distributions, and an illustrated key for all nine Romaleosyrphus are presented. DNA barcode data are provided for eight of the species with a cytochrome c oxidase subunit I gene tree presented and discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/55862/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/55862/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/55862/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 7 Dec 2021 11:08:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Corrieopone nouragues gen. nov., sp. nov., a new Ponerinae from French Guiana (Hymenoptera, Formicidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75551/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 83-173</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.75551</p>
					<p>Authors: Flavia A. Esteves, Brian L. Fisher</p>
					<p>Abstract: This study describes the worker and queen castes of the Neotropical ponerine Corrieopone nouragues gen. nov., sp. nov., an ant from the tropical rainforest in French Guiana. Worker morphology of the taxon is compared with those of other Ponerinae and the similarities between them are discussed, refining the definition of character states for some diagnostic characters at the generic level, providing an identification key to the Neotropical genera, and making some adjustments to the taxonomic framework within the subfamily. Descriptions, diagnosis, character discussion, identiﬁcation key, and glossary are illustrated with more than 300 images and line drawings. Open science is supported by providing access to measurement data for specimens of the new genus, a matrix of character states for all ponerine taxa evaluated in this study, and specimen data for all examined material. The new or revived combinations presented here are Pachycondyla procidua Emery, comb. rev., Neoponera curiosa (Mackay and Mackay), comb. nov., Leptogenys butteli (Forel), comb. nov., and Bothroponera escherichi (Forel), comb. nov. In addition, Leptogenys butteli is synonymized with Leptogenys myops (Emery), syn. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75551/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75551/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75551/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Dec 2021 17:46:43 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Revision of the xyleborine ambrosia beetle genus Microperus Wood, 1980 (Curculionidae, Scolytinae, Xyleborini) of Thailand with four new species and four newly recorded species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76235/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 191-214</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.76235</p>
					<p>Authors: Wisut Sittichaya, Sarah M. Smith, Roger A. Beaver, Narit Thaochan</p>
					<p>Abstract: Microperus Wood, 1980 ambrosia beetles in Thailand are reviewed. Four species, M. bidentatus sp. nov., M. bucolicus sp. nov., M. globodeclivis sp. nov., and M. serratus sp. nov. are described. Four new combinations are given: Microperus armaticeps (Schedl, 1942) comb. nov., Microperus exsculptus (Eggers, 1927) comb. nov., Microperus pedellus (Schedl, 1969) comb. nov., and Microperus spicatulus (Browne, 1986) comb. nov., stat. res., all from Xyleborus. Two new synonyms are proposed: Microperus cruralis (Schedl, 1975) (= Xyleborus myllus Browne, 1986 syn. nov.), Microperus exsculptus (Eggers, 1927) (= Xyleborus dentipennis Browne, 1983 syn. nov.). Four species are reported from Thailand for the first time: Microperus chrysophylli (Eggers, 1930), Microperus exsculptus, Microperus nanus (Browne, 1949) and Microperus quercicola (Eggers, 1926). With the inclusion of the Microperus species described and recorded herein, the diversity of Microperus is increased to 35 species, of which 18 are recorded in Thailand. An updated key to the Microperus of the Indochinese Peninsula and China is provided. The taxonomy, diagnostic characters, and distribution of species are briefly discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76235/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76235/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76235/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Dec 2021 12:26:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Four new species of the spider genus Synagelides Strand, 1906 from South China (Araneae, Salticidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72823/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 175-189</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.72823</p>
					<p>Authors: Bing Li, Cheng Wang, Xian-Jin Peng</p>
					<p>Abstract: Four new species of the jumping spider genus Synagelides Strand, 1906 from Guizhou and Yunnan, China are described: Synagelides angustus sp. nov. (♀), S. latus sp. nov. (♂♀), S. subagoriformis sp. nov. (♂♀), and S. triangulus sp. nov. (♀). Photographs of the habitus and copulatory organs and a distributional map are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72823/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72823/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72823/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Dec 2021 12:25:51 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿The genus Dryadaula Meyrick (Lepidoptera, Tineoidea, Dryadaulidae) in China, with descriptions of four new species and a world checklist</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73067/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 61-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.73067</p>
					<p>Authors: Lin-Lin Yang, Hou-Hun Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Four new species of the genus Dryadaula Meyrick, 1893 from China are described: Dryadaula auriformis sp. nov., D. flavostriata sp. nov., D. hirtiglobosa sp. nov. and D. securiformis sp. nov. Photographs of adults and genitalia of the new species are provided. DNA barcodes of D. auriformis sp. nov., D. hirtiglobosa sp. nov. and D. securiformis sp. nov. are given. A key to the species in China and a detailed checklist for the genus with all 49 known species in the world are presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73067/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73067/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73067/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2021 17:21:37 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Four new species of the genus Luzonomyza Malloch (Diptera, Lauxaniidae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68392/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 43-59</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.68392</p>
					<p>Authors: Wenliang Li, Xulong Chen, Keli Feng, Shengjuan Zhao, Ding Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Four species of the genus Luzonomyza Malloch, 1929 from southwest China are described as new to science: Luzonomyza vittifacies Li &amp; Yang, sp. nov., L. serrata Li &amp; Yang, sp. nov., L. honghensis Li &amp; Yang, sp. nov., and L. brevis Li &amp; Yang, sp. nov. A key to Luzonomyza species is also presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68392/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68392/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68392/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2021 17:20:14 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Coleção de Vetores de Tripanosomatídeos (Fiocruz/COLVET) held at the institution Fiocruz Minas in Brazil: diversity of Triatominae (Hemiptera, Reduviidae) and relevance for research, education, and entomological surveillance</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69700/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 17-42</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.69700</p>
					<p>Authors: Raíssa N. Brito, Rita C. M. Souza, Liléia Diotaitui, Valeria S. Lima, Raquel A. Ferreira</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Coleção de Vetores de Tripanosomatídeos (Fiocruz/COLVET), Minas Gerais, Brazil, stands out as one of the most important collections of blood-sucking triatomines, the vectors of Trypanosoma cruzi that causes Chagas disease. The aim is to describe the collection and the services it provides to support scientific research, educational activities, and entomological surveillance between 2013–2019.The data associated with the specimens held in Fiocruz/COLVET is available from the Sistema de Informação sobre a Biodiversidade Brasileira (SiBBr). These specimen metadata were analyzed and either tabulated or plotted on graph and maps. The records of services provided by the collection between 2013–2019 were also categorized and analyzed. There are 12,568 triatomine specimens deposited in the collection that belong to 77 species and 11 genera, from 15 American countries. Of the ~ 65 species of triatomines found in Brazil, 38 (57.6%) are present in the collection, including specimens from all biomes and all but three Brazilian states. The occurrence of Triatoma costalimai, Triatoma lenti, Rhodnius nasutus, and Panstrongylus lenti apparently collected beyond their known distribution ranges are reported and discussed. The collection provided 168 services, supporting educational activities (41.7%), scientific research (35.7%), and regional/national entomological surveillance of triatomines (22.6%). Between the years 2014 and 2020, the number of biological specimens deposited in the Fiocruz/COLVET repository increased from 4,778 to 12,568 triatomine specimens. In addition to its great value to biodiversity conservation, the collection is of great importance because of its support of research and educational activities, and contributions to entomological surveillance, and, therefore, to public health.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69700/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69700/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69700/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Data Paper</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2021 17:18:56 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿A new species of Esola Edwards, 1891 (Crustacea, Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Laophontidae) from the Caribbean coast of Colombia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73030/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1074: 1-15</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1074.73030</p>
					<p>Authors: Juan Manuel Fuentes-Reinés, Eduardo Suarez-Morales, Marcelo Silva-Briano</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the harpacticoid copepod genus Esola is described from specimens collected in Rodadero Beach, on Gaira Bay, on the Caribbean coast of Colombia. The species, E. wellsi sp. nov., is described, illustrated, and com­pared with its congeners. Esola wellsi sp. nov. differs from its known congeners in details of the armature of legs 1–4. It most closely resembles E. bulbifera (Norman, 1911) in the armature formula of P1–P5 but differs from the latter in several respects, including the female antennule segmentation (7-segmented in E. bulbifera but distinctly 6-segmented in E. wellsi sp. nov.) and in the shape and size of the male P3ENP2 apophysis, among other characters. This is the second species of the genus known from the Caribbean and the second record of Esola in the Northwestern Tropical Atlantic. The genus now contains eight species. A key to the known species of the genus is also included.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73030/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73030/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73030/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2021 17:17:50 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Corrigenda: A parasitic insect on a parasitic plant: a new species of the genus Formicoccus Takahashi (Hemiptera, Coccomorpha, Pseudococcidae) from Ishigaki Island, Japan. ZooKeys 1060: 171–182. https://doi.org/10.3897/zookeys.1060.71652</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76830/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 201-204</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.76830</p>
					<p>Authors: Hirotaka Tanaka, Kenji Suetsugu, Satoshi Kamitani</p>
					<p>Abstract: </p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76830/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76830/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/76830/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Corrigenda</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 17:14:31 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>﻿Two new species and new records of Otocepheidae (Acari, Oribatida) from Yunnan, Southwest China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75583/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 177-199</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.75583</p>
					<p>Authors: Lihao Zheng, Jun Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: This work includes taxonomic data on four species of oribatid mites of the family Otocepheidae from Yunnan, China. Two new species of the genera Basiceramerus and Eurostocepheus are described, respectively. Basiceramerus ovatus sp. nov. differs from B. bangladeshensis Corpuz-Raros &amp; Gruèzo, 2008 by the wavy marginalis passing the base of the adanal setae, prodorsal condyles well separated from median ones, a ventral ridge present, and the anal plate foveolate; it differs from B. igorotus Corpuz-Raros &amp; Gruèzo, 2011 from Vietnam by the wavy marginalis passing the base of the adanal setae, a connected tutorium and lamelliform expansion, a ventral ridge present, a smooth genital plate, and seta an2 located close to the median margin of the anal opening; it differs from B. igorotus from the Philippines by the lamellar setae inserted behind the tip of the lamella, separated prodorsal condyles, lyrifissure im posterior to gla, genital plate smooth, anal plate foveolate, and the wavy marginalis passing the base of the adanal setae. Eurostocepheus (Eurostocepheus) sinutus sp. nov. differs from other known species of this genus by having a ventral groove between the genital aperture and the ventral ridge, eight pairs of notogastral setae, and distinctly shorter and thinner notogastral setae p1, p2, p3, h3. Eurostocepheus (Eurostocepheus) aquilinus Aoki, 1965 and E. (E.) mahunkai Mondal &amp; Kundu, 1999 are reported for the first time from China.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75583/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75583/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75583/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:25:41 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A review of the Larainae of Australia with description of seven new species and the new genus Australara (Coleoptera, Byrrhoidea, Elmidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71843/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 55-117</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.71843</p>
					<p>Authors: Cheryl B. Barr, William D. Shepard</p>
					<p>Abstract: The three genera and four species of Larainae (Elmidae) previously described from Australia are reviewed, and one new genus and seven new species are described: Australara glaisteri gen. et sp. nov., Ovolara lawrencei sp. nov., Ovolara monteithi sp. nov., Stetholus carinatus sp. nov., Stetholus longipennis sp. nov., Stetholus metatibialis sp. nov., and Stetholus woronora sp. nov. A lectotype is designated for Hydora laticeps (Carter &amp; Zeck), and the first new collection records of the species are reported since its description in 1932. The occurrence in Australia of Potamophilinus papuanus Satô, described from Papua New Guinea, is reported. A key to the species, photographic images of the external morphology and male genitalia, distribution maps, and habitat and behavioral information, when known, are provided for all twelve species of Australian Larainae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71843/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71843/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71843/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 22:54:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new Diancta species of the family Diplommatinidae (Cyclophoroidea) from Vanua Levu Island, Fiji</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73241/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.73241</p>
					<p>Authors: Estée Bochud, David Haberthür, Ruslan Hlushchuk, Eike Neubert</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of Diancta of the staircase snail family Diplommatinidae is described from Mt. Savusavu, Vanua Levu Island, Fiji. Due to its left coiling shell and a constriction before the last whorl, it is placed in the genus Diancta. Micro-CT imaging reveals two apertural teeth and an inner lamella that is situated at the zone of constriction. The shell abruptly changes coiling direction by 45 degrees before the last whorl. Up to now, this coiling modus had not yet been documented for any species of Diplommatinidae from the Fiji Islands.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73241/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73241/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73241/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 17:50:45 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Songs and morphology in three species of the Chorthippus biguttulus group (Orthoptera, Acrididae, Gomphocerinae) in Russia and adjacent countries</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75539/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 21-53</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.75539</p>
					<p>Authors: Tatiana Tarasova, Dmitry Tishechkin, Varvara Vedenina</p>
					<p>Abstract: Songs and morphology are compared between Chorthippus miramae (Vorontsovsky, 1928) that was previously named as C. porphyropterus and two other closely related species, C. brunneus (Thunberg, 1815) and C. maritimus Mistshenko, 1951. We compare them because the calling song of C. miramae was previously shown to have song elements similar to those of other two species. One morphological character, the length of stridulatory file, appeared to be the best character to distinguish between all three species. For C. maritimus and C. miramae, we present the morphological descriptions since they are absent in the literature. We also establish the synonymy C. maritimus = C. bornhalmi Harz, 1971, syn. n. = C. biguttulus eximius Mistshenko, 1951, syn. n. In the song analysis, we analyse not only the sound but also the leg-movement pattern, which is very helpful to find a homology between various song elements. We show that the calling song of C. miramae usually contains two elements, one element being similar to the C. brunneus calling song, and another – to the C. maritimus calling song. Despite some similarities, the calling song elements in C. miramae have some peculiarities. The courtship song of C. miramae is similar to the C. brunneus song, whereas the rivalry songs of C. miramae comprise both the maritimus-like elements and the unique ones. C. miramae generally demonstrates a richer song repertoire than the other two species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75539/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75539/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75539/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 13:03:17 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An annotated checklist of the amphibians and reptiles of North Padre Island, Texas, USA, with comparisons to adjacent barrier island and mainland herpetofauna</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/57241/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 119-175</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.57241</p>
					<p>Authors: Mike Duran</p>
					<p>Abstract: Padre Island is the world’s longest barrier island and includes the longest stretch of undeveloped barrier island in the world. Largely due to harsh environmental conditions and difficult access, only cursory and incomplete checklists and subjective estimates of abundance have been produced. The results of an inventory of amphibians and reptiles of North Padre Island conducted 2002–2020, including the results of extensive field surveys conducted 2002–2003, are reported herein. Natural history museum and iNaturalist records are summarized and compared among North and South Padre and Mustang islands and the mainland portion of the seven counties in which the islands occur. The conservation status of rare species and extirpation of others is noted. The morphology and taxonomic status of some unique occurrences are discussed. Eleven species of amphibians and 39 species of reptiles presently occur or have occurred naturally or as introduced or accidental species on North Padre Island. Twelve species of amphibians and 50 species of reptiles occur or have occurred on North Padre, South Padre, and Mustang islands. Thirty-one species of amphibians and 93 species of reptiles have been reported from the seven counties in which the islands occur.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/57241/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/57241/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/57241/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:18:02 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of cricket genus Anaxiphomorpha Gorochov, 1987 (Orthoptera, Trigonidiidae, Trigonidiinae) in China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75598/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1073: 13-20</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1073.75598</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi Xin He, Li Bin Ma</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species, Anaxiphomorpha nonggangensis sp. nov. and Anaxiphomorpha manereserratus sp. nov., are reported from Guangxi Province, China. Descriptions and illustrations for the new species and a key to all known species of Anaxiphomorpha are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75598/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75598/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75598/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 11:37:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomy of the Proisotoma complex. VI. Rediscovery of the genus Bagnallella Salmon, 1951 and epitoky in Bagnallella davidi (Barra, 2001), comb. nov. from South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 185-204</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.71307</p>
					<p>Authors: Mikhail Potapov, Louis Deharveng, Charlene Janion-Scheepers</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Bagnallella Salmon is restored and given a diagnosis. It takes an intermediate position between Proisotoma Börner and Cryptopygus Willem complexes and is characterized by the separation of the two last abdominal segments (like in Proisotoma) and 3 and 5 s-chaetae on the fourth and fifth abdominal segments (like in Cryptopygus and its allies). A list of and key to species belonging to Bagnallella is given. Bagnallella biseta comb. nov., B. dubia comb. nov., B. sedecimoculata comb. nov., and B. tenella comb. nov. are commented and redescribed. Morphology of Bagnallella davidi (Barra), comb. nov. is described from the specimens from South Africa. So far B. davidi appears to be a complex of forms differing in size of the furca and macrochaetae. Two types of strongly modified males were found and described. Antennae, ventral side of abdomen, posterior edge of abdominal tergites, and mandibles are affected with epitoky. The nature of the discovered strong polymorphism is unclear.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 16:04:11 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On two new species of deep-sea carrier crabs (Crustacea, Brachyura, Homolodromiidae, Dicranodromia) from Taiwan and the Philippines, with notes on other Indo-West Pacific species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 129-165</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.72978</p>
					<p>Authors: Peter K. L. Ng, Chien-Hui Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The systematics of four species of the homolodromiid genus Dicranodromia A. Milne-Edwards, 1880, from East Asia and the Philippines is reappraised: D. danielae Ng &amp; McLay, 2005, D. doederleini Ortmann, 1892, D. karubar Guinot, 1993, and D. martini Guinot, 1995; and key characters such as the epistome, gonopods, and spermatheca are figured in detail. Two new species, D. erinaceus sp. nov. and D. robusta sp. nov., are described from Taiwan and the Philippines, respectively. Dicranodromia erinaceus sp. nov. resembles D. spinulata Guinot, 1995, and D. delli Ahyong, 2008 (from New Caledonia and New Zealand) but can be separated by its distinctly spinulated carapace surfaces and proportionately shorter fifth ambulatory legs. Dicranodromia robusta sp. nov. is superficially similar to D. baffini (Alcock &amp; Anderson, 1899) and D. karubar Guinot, 1993, but can easily be separated by possessing a broad dorsoventrally flattened infraorbital tooth. A genetic study of the species using the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase I gene confirms that the taxa are distinct, with D. erinaceus sp. nov. coming out in a well-supported clade from congeners. The megalopa of D. doederleini is also reported for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 14:23:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Transcriptional identification of genes light-interacting in the extraretinal photoreceptors of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 107-127</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.73075</p>
					<p>Authors: Gabina Calderón-Rosete, Juan Antonio González-Barrios, Celia Piña-Leyva, Hayde Nallely Moreno-Sandoval, Manuel Lara-Lozano, Leonardo Rodríguez-Sosa</p>
					<p>Abstract: Crayfish serve as a model for studying the effect of environmental lighting on locomotor activity and neuroendocrine functions. The effects of light on this organism are mediated differentially by retinal and extraretinal photoreceptors located in the cerebroid ganglion and the pleonal nerve cord. However, some molecular aspects of the phototransduction cascade in the pleonal extraretinal photoreceptors remain unknown. In this study, transcriptome data from the pleonal nerve cord of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii (Girard,1852) were analyzed to identify transcripts that potentially interact with phototransduction process. The Illumina MiSeq System and the pipeline Phylogenetically Informed Annotation (PIA) were employed, which places uncharacterized genes into pre-calculated phylogenies of gene families. Here, for the first time 62 transcripts identified from the pleonal nerve cord that are related to light-interacting pathways are reported; they can be classified into the following 11 sets: 1) retinoid pathway in vertebrates and invertebrates, 2) photoreceptor specification, 3) rhabdomeric phototransduction, 4) opsins 5) ciliary phototransduction, 6) melanin synthesis, 7) pterin synthesis, 8) ommochrome synthesis, 9) heme synthesis, 10) diurnal clock, and 11) crystallins. Moreover, this analysis comparing the sequences located on the pleonal nerve cord to eyestalk sequences reported in other studies reveals 94–100% similarity between the 55 common proteins identified. These results show that both retinal and pleonal non-visual photoreceptors in the crayfish equally expressed the transcripts involved in light detection. Moreover, they suggest that the genes related to ocular and extraocular light perception in the crayfish P. clarkii use biosynthesis pathways and phototransduction cascades commons.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:58:55 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Tylototriton (Urodela, Salamandridae) from western Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 83-105</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.75320</p>
					<p>Authors: Porrawee Pomchote, Parada Peerachidacho, Axel Hernandez, Pitak Sapewisut, Wichase Khonsue, Panupong Thammachoti, Kanto Nishikawa</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe a new species of the newt genus Tylototriton from Umphang Wildlife Sanctuary, Tak Province, western Thailand based on molecular and morphological evidence and named here as Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. The new species is assigned to the subgenus Tylototriton and differs from other species in having dark-brown to blackish-brown body and limbs, truncate snout, prominent antero-medial ends of the expansion of the dentary bones, laterally protruding quadrate regions, indistinct and small rib nodules, a well-segmented vertebral ridge, and rough dorsolateral bony ridges, which are steeper anterior, and curved medially at the posterior ends. The molecular data show that Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. differs from T. uyenoi sensu stricto by a 5% genetic sequence divergence of the mitochondrial NADH dehydrogenase subunit 2 region gene. The new species and T. uyenoi are both endemic to Thailand, distributed along the Northwest Thai (Dawna) Uplands of Indochina. To clarify the species boundary between Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. and T. uyenoi, additional field research is needed in adjacent areas. Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. is restricted to evergreen hill forests in Umphang Wildlife Sanctuary. We suggest that the new species should be classified as Endangered (EN) in the IUCN Red List.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:58:15 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Nine new species of the spider family Araneidae (Arachnida, Araneae) from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 49-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.73345</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiaoqi Mi, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Nine new species of the orb-weaver spider family Araneidae Clerck, 1757 from Menglun Town, Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China are described: Acusilas tongi sp. nov. (♂♀), Chorizopes yui sp. nov. (♂♀), Chorizopesoides guoi sp. nov. (♂♀), Deione cheni sp. nov. (♀), D. yangi sp. nov. (♂♀), Hypsosinga pulla sp. nov. (♂♀), Mangora baii sp. nov. (♂♀), M. cephala sp. nov. (♂♀) and Milonia gemella sp. nov. (♂♀). The genus Milonia Thorell, 1890 is recorded from China for the first time. The previous description of Chorizopesoides wulingensis (Yin, Wang &amp; Xie, 1994) from Libo County, Guizhou by Mi and Wang (2018) refers to Chorizopesoides annasestakovae sp. nov. (♂♀). Diagnostic photos of the habitus and copulatory organs of the new species are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:55:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic study on fourteen symphytognathid species from Asia (Araneae, Symphytognathidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 1-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.67935</p>
					<p>Authors: Ya Li, Shuqiang Li, Yucheng Lin</p>
					<p>Abstract: Fourteen symphytognathid species belonging to three genera are examined, including the descriptions of eight new species and two new genera from China, Vietnam, Thailand and Myanmar: Patu Marples, 1951: P. catba S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂, Vietnam), P. dakou S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China), P. damtao S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂, Vietnam), P. jiangzhou S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♀, China), P. jidanweishi Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♂♀, China), P. nagarat S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, Thailand), P. nigeri Lin &amp; S. Li, 2009 (♀, China), P. putao S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♀, Myanmar), P. qiqi Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♀, China) and P. xiaoxiao Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♂♀, China); Kirinua S. Li &amp; Lin, gen. nov.: K. maguai S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China) and K. yangshuo S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China); Swilda S. Li &amp; Lin, gen. nov.: S. longtou (Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009), comb. nov. (♂♀, China) is transferred from Crassignatha Wunderlich, 1995 and S. spinathoraxi (Lin &amp; S. Li, 2009), comb. nov. (♂♀, China) is transferred from Patu. Diagnoses, descriptions and illustrations are provided for new taxa, as well as a distribution map. The males of P. xiaoxiao and S. longtou are described for the first time. Type specimens of P. jidanweishi, P. nigeri, P. qiqi, P. xiaoxiao, S. longtou and S. spinathoraxi are re-examined and photographed. All Asian Patu species are revised and two species, P. kishidai Shinkai, 2009 and P. bispina Lin, Pham &amp; S. Li, 2009, are transferred to Crassignatha and proposed as new combinations: Crassignatha kishidai comb. nov. and C. bispina comb. nov. In addition, DNA barcodes and genetic distances of ten species treated in this paper were obtained to confirm identification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:54:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New genetic data reveals a new species of Zospeum in Bosnia (Gastropoda, Ellobioidea, Carychiinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 175-193</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.66417</p>
					<p>Authors: Thomas Inäbnit, Adrienne Jochum, Raijko Slapnik, Eike Neubert</p>
					<p>Abstract: Recent integrative investigations of the terrestrial ellobiid genus, Zospeum, have revealed significant findings concerning its Alpine-Dinaric evolution and taxonomy. Due to the expected discrepancy between the useful, but limited, 1970s’ classification system based on shell data and the results of recent genetic analyses in the latest investigation, a revision of the entire radiation was undertaken, and a new classification system was devised by the present authors in an earlier paper. Concurrent to this work, molecular sequences from two Austrian caves were published independently of our revision by another research group. By incorporating these genetic data within our phylogenetic framework here, we show that the Austrian individuals are genetically most similar to Zospeum amoenum and consequently, classify them within that species. We additionally reveal two new genetic lineages from the largely under-sampled southern extension of Zospeum’s known distributional range. The first lineage, deriving from the region of Dubrovnik, Croatia, is a potential candidate for genetically clarifying Zospeum troglobalcanicum. The second lineage derives from the municipality of Tomislavgrad, Bosnia-Herzegovina and is herein, described a new species: Zospeum simplex Inäbnit, Jochum &amp; Neubert, sp. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:51:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Hexatoma (Eriocera) Macquart (Diptera, Limoniidae) from Xizang, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 155-173</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.66750</p>
					<p>Authors: Bing Zhang, Qicheng Yang, Yan Li, Ding Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: One new species of the subgenus Eriocera Macquart,1838, Hexatoma (Eriocera) xizangensis sp. nov. is described and illustrated from Xizang, China. The following four species are re-described and reported from Xizang for the first time: H. (E.) latigrisea Alexander, 1971, H. (E.) nepalensis (Westwood, 1836), H. (E.) paragnava Alexander, 1973 and H. (E.) perhirsuta Alexander, 1973. A key to the species of Eriocera from Xizang is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:03:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Contribution to the knowledge of the genus Takobia Novikova &amp; Kluge, 1987 (Ephemeroptera, Baetidae) in Central Asia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 127-154</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.71582</p>
					<p>Authors: Pavel Sroka, Zohar Yanai, Dmitry Palatov, Jean-Luc Gattolliat</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on the original type material, the nymphal stage of the mayfly Takobia maxillare is redescribed; in parallel, a lectotype is designated. Takobia maxillare is the type species of the genus Takobia, and an accurate and complete knowledge of its morphology is crucial to the delimitation of this problematic genus and clarification of its phylogenetic affinities. Ambiguous characters, previously reported for this species in the literature are clarified. Furthermore, two new species in the same genus are described, namely Takobia sinusopalpata sp. nov. and Takobia shughnonica sp. nov. based on the morphology of nymphs from Central Asia, supplemented with COI sequences. Implications for the systematics of Takobia and related taxa are discussed and the need for an extensive phylogenetic study of this group is stressed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 07:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Helen’s twins in the Balkans: discovery of two new Paraptychoptera Tonnoir, 1919 species closely related to P. helena Peus, 1958, with systematic revision of the “lacustris” group (Diptera, Ptychopteridae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 63-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.58598</p>
					<p>Authors: Lujza Keresztes, Jürgen Kappert, Mária Henning, Edina Török</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ptychoptera castor Keresztes &amp; Kappert, sp. nov. and P. pollux Keresztes &amp; Török, sp. nov. both belong to the subgenus Ptychoptera (Paraptychoptera) Tonnoir (1919) and are described from boggy headwaters in the south Balkan area. These new species are closely related to the range-restricted P. helena Peus, 1958, which is known only from Oiti village, Mount Oeta, Phthioitis region, Greece and, together with P. lacustris, forms a morphologically well-defined unit in the subgenus Paraptychoptera. Based on cladistic analyses of 53 different morphological characters using the male antenna, wing, and genital structures, a general revision of the “lacustris” group is proposed with a dichotomous key of Paraptychoptera species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:20:26 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Another Laurasian connection in the Early Eocene of India: Myrmecarchaea spiders (Araneae, Archaeidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 49-61</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72515</p>
					<p>Authors: Hannah M. Wood, Hukam Singh, David A. Grimaldi</p>
					<p>Abstract: The first fossil Archaeidae in Cambay amber from India, of Eocene age, is documented. The inclusion is a spider exuvium and is placed as Myrmecarchaea based on the presence of elongated legs, a slightly elongated pedicel with lateral spurs, and a diastema between coxae III and IV that is similar to M. antecessor from Oise amber. The previous occurrences of the genus are from Baltic and Oise amber, both of Eocene age. Because most spiders, including Archaeidae, only molt as juveniles, the exuvium does not have adult features nor have distinct species-specific features, and a new taxon is not erected. This new record further extends the distribution of the family and genus to India 50–52 million years ago. Myrmecarchaea in Indian Cambay amber provides additional evidence that India in the Early Eocene had affinities with the Palearctic mainland rather than showing Gondwanan insularity.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and molecular identification of arrhenotokous strain of Diglyphus wani (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) found in China as a control agent against agromyzid leafminers</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 109-126</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72433</p>
					<p>Authors: Su-Jie Du, Zoya Yefremova, Fu-Yu Ye, Chao-Dong Zhu, Jian-Yang Guo, Wan-Xue Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diglyphus species are ecologically and economically important on agromyzid leafminers. In 2018, a thelytokous species, Diglyphus wani Liu, Zhu &amp; Yefremova, was firstly reported and described. Subsequently, the arrhenotokous D. wani were discovered in Yunnan and Guizhou Provinces of China. We compared the morphological characteristics of thelytokous and arrhenotokous strains. However, the females of two strains had a strongly similar morphology and showed subtle differences in fore- and hind-wings. The difference was that forewing of arrhenotokous female was with denser setae overall, showing that costal cell with 2 ~ 4 rows of setae on dorsal surface and the setae of basal cell with 15 ~ 21 hairs and forewing of thelytokous female was with two rows of setae on dorsal surface and basal cell with 10 ~ 15 hairs generally. The setation beneath the marginal vein of the hind-wing of arrhenotokous female is denser than the same area of thelytokous female. To explore the genetic divergence between thelytokous and arrhenotokous strains of D. wani, the mitochondrial and nuclear gene were applied and sequenced. The polygenic analyses revealed that two strains can be distinguished by COI, ITS1 and ITS2. The mean sequence divergence between the two strains was 0.052, 0.010 and 0.007, respectively. Nevertheless, the 28S gene was unfeasible due to its containing a sharing haplotype between different strains. The two strains of D. wani are dominant parasitoids against agromyzid leafminers and such effective discernible foundation provides future in-depth studies on biological characteristics, along with insight into field application of two strains of D. wani.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 10:59:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Out of Xanthopygus (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae): escape from polyphyly</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 83-107</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.75947</p>
					<p>Authors: Stylianos Chatzimanolis</p>
					<p>Abstract: Xanthopygus as currently defined is the largest genus in the subtribe Xanthopygina (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylininae) with 40 described species. However, the genus is poorly defined, morphologically heterogeneous and previous studies have questioned whether it is a natural group. A morphological (51 characters) Bayesian phylogenetic analysis was performed to test whether Xanthopygus is a monophyletic group. The analysis indicated that Xanthopygus was polyphyletic, and therefore species were split into four different genera. Xanthopygus nigricornis Scheerpeltz was transferred to Oligotergus as Oligotergus nigricornis comb. nov. and Xanthopygus skalitzkyi (Bernhauer) was transferred to Styngetus as Styngetus skalitzkyi comb. nov. A new genus, Photinopygus gen. nov. was erected to accommodate the majority of the species previously in Xanthopygus and Xanthopygus sensu novo is used in a new restricted sense to accommodate the remaining species. Diagnostic features are provided to distinguish species in the genera Photinopygus and Xanthopygus from each other and all other Xanthopygina genera.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 09:56:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diagnosing diagnoses – can we improve our taxonomy?</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 43-48</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72904</p>
					<p>Authors: Art Borkent</p>
					<p>Abstract: Taxonomic diagnoses should be clear but minimal statements that precisely distinguish a given specimen from other taxa at the same stage of development (e.g., pupa, adult female, egg). Presently, most diagnoses are of uncertain value. It is a great advantage for readers to be able to simply and confidently confirm their identifications after using a key.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Commentary</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 15:37:36 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A review of tangle-veined flies (Nemestrinidae, Diptera) in Egypt</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 11-42</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.70743</p>
					<p>Authors: Arafa Elsayed El-Hashash, Haitham Badrawy Mousa Badrawy, Ayman Mohyie-Eldin Ibrahim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Egyptian fauna of the genus Nemestrinus Latreille, 1802 is revised. In 1967, Steyskal and El-Bialy listed 12 species from the region, but only six species are now recognized. The primary type specimens of the species N. aegyptiacus (Wiedemann, 1828), N. rufipes (Olivier, 1810), and N. lateralis Wiedemann, 1828 (N. lateralis being a synonym of N. rufipes) deposited in the Museum für Naturkunde, Berlin, Germany were examined. Two species (N. abdominalis Olivier, 1811 and N. fascifrons (Bigot, 1888) are placed as new synonyms of N. ater (Olivier, 1811), and N. ruficornis Macquart, 1840 is synonymized with N. rufipes (Olivier, 1811). Nemestrinus jullieni (Efflatoun, 1925) is confirmed as a synonym of N. aegyptiacus. Furthermore, three species (N. caucasicus Fischer, 1806, N. pallipes (Olivier, 1811), and N. persicus Lichtwardt, 1909) have been removed and are doubtful records from Egypt. A key to the species, lists of specimens examined, and Illustrations and distributions for each species are provided. The status of species of doubtful occurrence in Egypt is discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:14:56 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First report of Eutrichosomella Girault (Hymenoptera, Aphelinidae) from China, with description of a new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 1-9</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.71909</p>
					<p>Authors: Ye Chen, Hai-feng Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Eutrichosomella Girault is recorded for the first time from China (Yunnan Province), and Eutrichosomella yunnanensis sp. nov. (♀, ♂) is described and illustrated. A distribution map of this genus is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:00:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of the genus Spio (Annelida, Spionidae) from the southern and western coasts of Korea</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 151-164</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73847</p>
					<p>Authors: Geon Hyeok Lee, Karin Meißner, Seong Myeong Yoon, Gi-Sik Min</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new spionid polychaete, Spio pigmentata sp. nov., is described from the southern and western coasts of Korea. This new species differs from its congeners by the combination of the following morphological characteristics: the presence of orange-brown pigmentation on the anterior part of the prostomium, black pigmentation on the peristomium and along the body, U-shaped nuchal organs, a comparatively long extension of metameric dorsal ciliated organs, three pairs of white dots per chaetiger, two to three posterior abranchiate chaetigers, and the presence of tridentate neuropodial hooded hooks. The partial 16S ribosomal DNA (rDNA) and nuclear 18S rDNA sequences of the new species and Spio sp. 2 reported by Abe and Sato-Okoshi (2021) from Japan showed high similarity, indicating that these two specimens belong to the same species. A detailed description and illustrations of the new species, together with molecular information, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:39:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Mitogenomics of historical type specimens clarifies the taxonomy of Ethiopian Ptychadena Boulenger, 1917 (Anura, Ptychadenidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 135-149</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.66598</p>
					<p>Authors: Jacobo Reyes-Velasco, Sandra Goutte, Xenia Freilich, Stéphane Boissinot</p>
					<p>Abstract: The taxonomy of the Ptychadena neumanni species complex, a radiation of grass frogs inhabiting the Ethiopian highlands, has puzzled scientists for decades because of the morphological resemblance among its members. Whilst molecular phylogenetic methods allowed the discovery of several species in recent years, assigning pre-existing and new names to clades was challenged by the unavailability of molecular data for century-old type specimens. We used Illumina short reads to sequence the mitochondrial DNA of type specimens in this group, as well as ddRAD-seq analyses to resolve taxonomic uncertainties surrounding the P. neumanni species complex. The phylogenetic reconstruction revealed recurrent confusion between Ptychadena erlangeri (Ahl, 1924) and P. neumanni (Ahl, 1924) in the literature. The phylogeny also established that P. largeni Perret, 1994 represents a junior synonym of P. erlangeri (Ahl, 1924) and distinguished between two small species, P. nana Perret, 1994, restricted to the Arussi Plateau, and P. robeensis Goutte, Reyes-Velasco, Freilich, Kassie &amp; Boissinot, 2021, which inhabits the Bale Mountains. The phylogenetic analyses of mitochondrial DNA from type specimens also corroborate the validity of seven recently described species within the group. Our study shows how modern molecular tools applied to historical type specimens can help resolve long-standing taxonomic issues in cryptic species complexes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 13:42:50 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 (Diptera, Ptychopteridae) from Zhejiang, China with an updated key to Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 87-99</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.67779</p>
					<p>Authors: Jiaqi Shao, Zehui Kang</p>
					<p>Abstract: We revise the taxonomy of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 from Zhejiang, East China. One new species from Zhejiang, P. tianmushana sp. nov., is described and illustrated. Morphologically, the new species is most similar to P. emeica Kang, Xue &amp; Zhang, 2019 and P. formosensis Alexander, 1924, but it can be distinguished by the coloration of the abdomen and the details of the male genitalia. In addition, P. bellula Alexander, 1937 is recorded from Zhejiang for the first time. Two known species from Zhejiang, P. longwangshana Yang &amp; Chen, 1998 and P. gutianshana Yang &amp; Chen, 1995, are redescribed and illustrated. A key to Chinese species of Ptychoptera is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:06:35 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 (Diptera, Ptychopteridae) from Yunnan, China with remarks on the distribution of Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 73-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.58859</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao Zhang, Zehui Kang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sixteen known species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 have been recorded from China, of which three occur in Yunnan Province. Herein, two new species from Yunnan, P. cordata sp. nov. and P. yunnanica sp. nov., are described from China. An updated key to Ptychoptera is presented for all Chinese species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:05:48 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Neohagenulus Traver, 1938 from Hispaniola (Ephemeroptera, Leptophlebiidae, Hagenulinae, Hagenulini)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 41-50</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73484</p>
					<p>Authors: Michel Sartori</p>
					<p>Abstract: Here, I report a new species of the genus Neohagenulus Traver, 1938 from the Dominican Republic. The genus was believed to be endemic to Puerto Rico until now. Neohagenulus hodeceki sp. nov. is described at the nymphal stage. Some discussion on the tribe Hagenulini is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 19:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Hylcalosia Fischer (Hymenoptera: Braconidae: Alysiinae) from South Korea, with a key to the Korean species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 31-40</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73377</p>
					<p>Authors: Ju-Hyeong Sohn, Cornelis van Achterberg, Yunjong Han, Hyojoong Kim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The species of the genus Hylcalosia Fischer, 1967 (Braconidae: Alysiinae) from South Korea are revised. One species, Hylcalosia bicolor sp. nov., is new to science. They are described and illustrated herein and an identification key to the Korean species is added. In addition, the DNA barcode region of the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI) has been analysed for the new species and H. sutchanica is used for genetic comparison.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Characterization of the complete mitochondrial genome of Myrmus lateralis (Heteroptera, Rhopalidae) and its implication for phylogenetic analyses</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 13-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.72742</p>
					<p>Authors: Wanqing Zhao, Dajun Liu, Qian Jia, Xin Wu, Hufang Zhang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Mitochondrial genomes (mitogenomes) are widely used in research studies on phylogenetic relationships and evolutionary history. Here, we sequenced and analyzed the mitogenome of the scentless plant bug Myrmus lateralis Hsiao, 1964 (Heteroptera, Rhopalidae). The complete 17,309 bp genome encoded 37 genes, including 13 protein-coding genes (PCGs), 22 transfer RNA (tRNA) genes, two ribosomal RNA (rRNA) genes, and a control region. The mitogenome revealed a high A+T content (75.8%), a positive AT-skew (0.092), and a negative GC-skew (–0.165). All 13 PCGs were found to start with ATN codons, except for cox1, in which TTG was the start codon. The Ka/Ks ratios of 13 PCGs were all lower than 1, indicating that purifying selection evolved in these genes. All tRNAs could be folded into the typical cloverleaf secondary structure, except for trnS1 and trnV, which lack dihydrouridine arms. Phylogenetic trees were constructed and analyzed based on the PCG+rRNA from 38 mitogenomes, using maximum likelihood and Bayesian inference methods, showed that M. lateralis and Chorosoma macilentum Stål, 1858 grouped together in the tribe Chorosomatini. In addition, Coreoidea and Pyrrhocoroidea were sister groups among the superfamilies of Trichophora, and Rhopalidae was a sister group to Alydidae + Coreidae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:34:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Effect of climate change on the potential distribution of Heloderma alvarezi (Squamata, Helodermatidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.69186</p>
					<p>Authors: Aarón Gómez-Cruz, Nancy G. Santos-Hernández, José Alberto Cruz, Daniel Ariano-Sánchez, Christian Ruiz-Castillejos, Eduardo E. Espinoza-Medinilla, José A. De Fuentes-Vicente</p>
					<p>Abstract: Climate change represents a real threat to biodiversity conservation worldwide. Although the effects on several species of conservation priority are known, comprehensive information about the impact of climate change on reptile populations is lacking. In the present study, we analyze outcomes on the potential distribution of the black beaded lizard (Heloderma alvarezi Bogert &amp; Martin del Campo, 1956) under global warming scenarios. Its potential distribution, at present and in projections for the years 2050 and 2070, under both optimistic and pessimistic climate change forecasts, were computed using current data records and seven bioclimatic variables. General results predict a shift in the future potential distribution of H. alvarezi due to temperature increase. The optimistic scenario (4.5 W/m2) for 2070 suggests an enlargement in the species’ distribution as a response to the availability of new areas of suitable habitat. On the contrary, the worst-case scenario (7 W/m2) shows a distribution decrease by 65%. Moreover, the range distribution of H. alvarezi is directly related to the human footprint, which consequently could magnify negative outcomes for this species. Our research elucidates the importance of conservation strategies to prevent the extinction of the black beaded lizard, especially considering that this species is highly threatened by aversive hunting.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:34:14 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Byrrhinus Motschulsky, 1858 (Coleoptera, Limnichidae, Limnichinae) from Negros, Philippines</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 51-72</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.70531</p>
					<p>Authors: Emmanuel D. Delocado, Hendrik Freitag</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Limnichidae beetles, Byrrhinus negrosensis sp. nov. and Byrrhinus villarini sp. nov., are described from the Island of Negros in the Philippines. The adult specimens of the new species can be differentiated by patterns of body punctation, colour and orientation of elytral pubescence, posterolateral angle of pronotum, tarsomere length ratio and aedeagal form. Two clades, representing the two new species, were retrieved in the Maximum Likelihood gene tree using the 3’-end of the COI gene. Maximum genetic divergence within B. negrosensis sp. nov. and B. villarini sp. nov. were recorded to be 2.3% and 1.3%, respectively, while the mean interspecific divergence between the two new species was 19.7%. Morphological descriptions, digital photographs and COI sequences were provided for the two species. The state of knowledge of Byrrhinus is reviewed and an updated Philippine checklist is provided. By coupling morphological and molecular data, this paper provides the first additional new species of Philippine Byrrhinus in the last 28 years.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:47:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An annotated checklist of the eukaryotic parasites of humans, exclusive of fungi and algae</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1069: 1-313</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1069.67403</p>
					<p>Authors: Blaine A. Mathison, Sarah G. H. Sapp</p>
					<p>Abstract: The classification of “parasites” in the medical field is a challenging notion, a group which historically has included all eukaryotes exclusive of fungi that invade and derive resources from the human host. Since antiquity, humans have been identifying and documenting parasitic infections, and this collective catalog of parasitic agents has expanded considerably with technology. As our understanding of species boundaries and the use of molecular tools has evolved, so has our concept of the taxonomy of human parasites. Consequently, new species have been recognized while others have been relegated to synonyms. On the other hand, the decline of expertise in classical parasitology and limited curricula have led to a loss of awareness of many rarely encountered species. Here, we provide a comprehensive checklist of all reported eukaryotic organisms (excluding fungi and allied taxa) parasitizing humans resulting in 274 genus-group taxa and 848 species-group taxa. For each species, or genus where indicated, a concise summary of geographic distribution, natural hosts, route of transmission and site within human host, and vectored pathogens are presented. Ubiquitous, human-adapted species as well as very rare, incidental zoonotic organisms are discussed in this annotated checklist. We also provide a list of 79 excluded genera and species that have been previously reported as human parasites but are not believed to be true human parasites or represent misidentifications or taxonomic changes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 9 Nov 2021 15:08:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The first fossil Coleoptera record from the Volyn Region, Ukraine, with description of a new Glesoconomorphus (Coleoptera, Mycteridae) in syninclusion with Winterschmidtiidae (Acari) and a key to species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 189-201</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.75391</p>
					<p>Authors: Dmitry Telnov, Evgeny E. Perkovsky, Dmitry V. Vasilenko, Shûhei Yamamoto</p>
					<p>Abstract: Glesoconomorphus ekaterinae sp. nov. (Coleoptera, Mycteridae), representing the first ever fossil species of Coleoptera from the Volyn Region of Ukraine and the first mycterid from late Eocene Rovno amber, is described and illustrated. A key to species of the fossil mycterid genus Glesoconomorphus Alekseev, Pollock &amp; Bukejs, 2019 is presented. The systematic position of Glesoconomorphus within Eurypinae J. Thomson, 1860 is briefly discussed. The oldest finding of phoretic Winterschmidtiidae Oudemans, 1923 mites, found on the type specimen of the new beetle species, is reported.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 13:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Additions to the cuckoo wasps (Hymenoptera, Chrysididae) of Mongolia, with description of eleven new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 149-187</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.73549</p>
					<p>Authors: Paolo Rosa, Maxim Yu. Proshchalykin, Marek Halada</p>
					<p>Abstract: An addendum to the recent checklist of the Chrysididae from Mongolia is given. Examination of old museum material and recently collected specimens has led to the discovery of eight new records for the country and eleven new species for science. Eight species are newly recorded from Mongolia: Chrysis inclinata Linsenmaier, 1959, C. martinella du Buysson, 1900, C. speciosa Radoszkowski, 1877, Euchroeus purpuratus (Fabricius, 1787), Holopyga lucida (Lepeletier, 1806), H. similis Mocsáry, 1889, Hedychridium femoratum (Dahlbom, 1854) and H. leleji Rosa, 2017. Two species, Hedychridium cupreum (Dahlbom, 1845) and H. propodeale Rosa, 2017 are excluded from the checklist of Mongolian Chrysididae: the former is described here as H. erythrosoma sp. nov., the latter is identified as H. leleji Rosa, 2017. The hitherto unknown male of Chrysis mocsaryi Radoszkowski, 1889 is described and illustrated. Eleven new species are described: Chrysis strakai sp. nov., C. woodi sp. nov., Hedychridium erythrosoma sp. nov., H. frontale sp. nov., H. jacobsi sp. nov., H. splendens sp. nov., H. striatum sp. nov., H. varvarae sp. nov., H. weii sp. nov., Holopyga tyrneri sp. nov., and Philoctetes boreki sp. nov. Keys to males and females of all known Mongolian species of Hedychridium Abeille de Perrin, 1878 are provided. The Mongolian cuckoo wasp fauna now comprises 107 species in 18 genera and two subfamilies.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 13:08:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A checklist of Mantodea of Belize, with a regional key to species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 51-71</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.58193</p>
					<p>Authors: Lohitashwa Garikipati, Jason E. Bond</p>
					<p>Abstract: The list of known Mantodea in Belize is updated, with notes of 12 new country records, bringing the total known species of Mantodea in Belize to 21. Further information on habitat and microhabitat observations are included. A regional dichotomous key and Lucid interactive key are provided to known species in Belize. A list of other possibly endemic species is provided. Remarks on the merit of further sampling efforts in central America are made, based on recent studies. Our findings suggest that our understanding of Central American Mantodean diversity could be vastly improved by further documentation.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 18:28:06 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the genus Cenophengus LeConte, 1881 (Coleoptera, Phengodidae), with the description of four new species, new geographic records and a new synonymy</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 73-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70295</p>
					<p>Authors: Viridiana Vega-Badillo, Juan J. Morrone, Santiago Zaragoza-Caballero</p>
					<p>Abstract: A taxonomic revision of the genus Cenophengus LeConte, 1881 (Coleoptera: Phengodidae) is provided, including new data on geographic ranges of the species. This is the first time this genus has been recorded for Belize and in Honduras. Four new species (C. gardunoi, C. saasil, C. tsiik and C. zuritai) are described and a new synonymy (C. guerrerensis, Zaragoza-Caballero, 1991 = C. major Wittmer, 1976) is established. The study includes a key to the 30 valid species, diagnoses, descriptions, photographs and distribution maps.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 08:53:52 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Four new species of the jumping spider genus Portia (Araneae, Salticidae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 27-40</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.72805</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin Xu, Xianjin Peng, Daiqin Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: We diagnose and describe four new species of Portia Karsch, 1878 and describe for the first time the male of P. zhaoi Peng, Li &amp; Chen, 2003 from China based on morphological characters. The females of Portia bawang sp. nov. have the narrowest epigyne orifice. The males of Portia erlangping sp. nov. have the shortest embolus among all the species. The females of Portia fajing sp. nov. can be distinguished from other species by the anterior orifice margin, which is nearly parallel to the posterior orifice margin. The males of Portia xishan sp. nov. can be identified by the tegular furrow which extends to form a membrane and by the tegular apophysis which is obscured; the females of Portia xishan sp. nov. can be diagnosed by the slit-like epigynal orifice. The males of P. zhaoi have the longest embolus among all the species, and females can be diagnosed by the circular epigyne orifice and the longest copulatory ducts. To facilitate future identification, we also provide the GenBank accession codes of the DNA barcode gene, Cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI), for all the type specimens.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 3 Nov 2021 13:46:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Elachista Treitschke, 1833 (Lepidoptera, Elachistidae, Elachistinae) from China, with identification keys to the Asian species of the Elachista saccharella species group</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 41-50</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70807</p>
					<p>Authors: Virginijus Sruoga</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Elachista olekarsholti sp. nov., is described from Henan, China. The habitus and male genitalia are diagnosed and illustrated in detail. This is the first record of the Elachista saccharella species group in China. Identification keys to the Asian species of Elachista saccharella species group, based on male and female genitalia, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 3 Nov 2021 13:45:40 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Epeorus (Caucasiron) (Ephemeroptera, Heptageniidae) from Azerbaijan and Iran</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 13-26</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70717</p>
					<p>Authors: Ľuboš Hrivniak, Pavel Sroka, Jindriska Bojkova, Roman J. Godunko, Peter Manko</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Epeorus (Caucasiron) hyrcanicus sp. nov., is described based on larval morphology and molecular data (COI) containing sequences from all Caucasian Caucasiron species described to date. The species is distributed in the Hyrcanian forest of southeastern Azerbaijan and northwestern Iran. Based on our wide-range sampling, the new species is likely endemic to this area. The most pronounced larval morphological diagnostic characters are the coloration pattern of abdominal sterna (a pair of oblique stripes and stripe-like medio-lateral maculae) and terga (triangular medial maculae), poorly developed projection of the costal margin of gill plates III, presence of hair-like setae on the surface of abdominal terga, and relatively wide shape of gill plates VII (in natural position from ventral view). The diagnostic characters are compared to related species, and primary information to habitat is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 2 Nov 2021 13:16:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species and a new species record of Orbiniidae Hartman, 1942 (Annelida, Polychaeta) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 1-11</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.71925</p>
					<p>Authors: Yue Sun, Lei Yu, Xinzheng Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the orbiniid genus Phylo Kinberg, 1866, P. heterochaetus sp. nov., is described based on material collected from the northern Yellow Sea, China. This is the thirteenth species in Phylo. The new species can be easily identified by the combination of the following characters: anterior thorax with 13 chaetigers, interramal cirri absent, anterior thoracic neuropodia with 4 or 5 rows of uncini, intermixed with a few subuluncini in the first 1 or 2 rows, and a ventral fringe of numerous stomach papillae present on chaetigers 12–24. Phylo fimbriata is recorded for the first time from China seas.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 2 Nov 2021 09:36:18 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of Labiobaetis Novikova &amp; Kluge from Southeast Asia and New Guinea (Ephemeroptera, Baetidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 159-208</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72251</p>
					<p>Authors: Thomas Kaltenbach, Jean-Luc Gattolliat</p>
					<p>Abstract: Material collected between 2006 and 2016 in Borneo, Sulawesi, and New Guinea further increased our knowledge of Labiobaetis Novikova &amp; Kluge in these regions. Five species were previously reported from Borneo, two from Sulawesi, and 33 from New Guinea. Six new species have been identified using a combination of morphology and genetic distance (COI, Kimura 2-parameter), one species from Borneo (Brunei), one from Sulawesi, and four from New Guinea. They are described and illustrated based on their larvae and keys to the species of the relevant groups are provided. Additionally, new reports, a complementary description, and the COI sequence for L. dendrisetis Kaltenbach &amp; Gattolliat are presented. The distribution of Labiobaetis in the Wallacea region is discussed based on the new findings. The total number of Labiobaetis species worldwide is augmented to 153.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 1 Nov 2021 12:34:42 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First description of the female of Sinopoda yichangensis Zhu, Zhong &amp; Yang, 2020 (Araneae, Sparassidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 93-100</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72419</p>
					<p>Authors: Li-Jun Gong, Yang Zhong</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sinopoda yichangensis Zhu, Zhong &amp; Yang, 2020 was described from a single male from Qiaoliao Village, Hubei Province, China. To date, no additional specimens have been recorded. The female is reported for the first time from the type locality. Detailed morphological descriptions of the female, with photographs of living specimens and copulatory organs, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 16:00:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Petta (Annelida, Pectinariidae), with comments on Petta assimilis McIntosh, 1885</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 83-92</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72596</p>
					<p>Authors: Jinghuai Zhang, Pat Hutchings</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Petta Malmgren, 1866 is a small and poorly known genus of the annelid family Pectinariidae Quatrefages, 1866. A previous revision of the genus found that the type material of the species P. assimilis McIntosh, 1885 had been lost. While searching for material from the type locality, we were able to examine material from a similar area but collected in much shallower water from off South Africa which represents another undescribed species of Petta. The new species, Petta brevis sp. nov., is described and compared to P. assimilis McIntosh, 1885, and a revised key to all species in the genus is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 15:58:45 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Behningiidae and Potamanthidae (Insecta, Ephemeroptera) in Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 57-82</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72779</p>
					<p>Authors: Sedtawut Kwanboon, Michel Sartori, Boonsatien Boonsoong</p>
					<p>Abstract: The aim of this study is to review the family Behningiidae and Potamanthidae in Thailand. Two genera and three species of Behningiidae are recognised: Protobehningia merga Peters &amp; Gillies, 1991, Behningia baei McCafferty &amp; Jacobus, 2006, and Behningia nujiangensis Zhou &amp; Bisset, 2019, which is newly reported from Thailand. The egg structure of B. nujiangensis is described for the first time using scanning electron microscopy. The larva of P. merga is redescribed and its distribution is expended northward with a new record from Chiang Mai province. Two genera and five species of Potamanthidae are identified: Potamanthus formosus Eaton, 1892, Rhoenanthus magnificus Ulmer, 1920 (new record for Thailand), Rhoenanthus obscurus Navás, 1922, Rhoenanthus distafurcus Bae &amp; McCafferty, 1991, and Rhoenanthus speciosus Eaton, 1881. Our morphological evidence is supported by COI data for the family Potamanthidae. Diagnostic characters, distributions, and keys are presented for the larvae of all known species of Thai behningiid and potamanthid mayflies.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 15:55:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An overview of Estonian woodlice (Isopoda, Oniscidea)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 1-17</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.68105</p>
					<p>Authors: Kaarel Sammet, Getriin Orgusaar, Mari Ivask, Olavi Kurina</p>
					<p>Abstract: An overview of the Estonian terrestrial isopod fauna is given, based on literature data and material collected from 1984 to 2021. The identified material consisted of 10915 specimens belonging to 14 species and collected from 172 localities throughout Estonia. In combination with previous data from the literature data, there are now reliable records of 16 species of woodlice from Estonia. Two species, viz. Platyarthrus hoffmannseggii Brandt, 1833 and Hyloniscus riparius (C. Koch, 1838), are new for the fauna. The latter has probably colonised Estonia recently and range expansions have been reported elsewhere. The data on Philoscia muscorum (Scopoli, 1763) are dubious, and this species is currently excluded from the Estonian list.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 14:11:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Twelve new species of Dipara Walker, 1833 (Hymenoptera, Chalcidoidea, Pteromalidae, Diparinae) from Kenya, with a key to the Afrotropical species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 101-157</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72395</p>
					<p>Authors: Christoph Braun, Ralph S. Peters</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on 261 female specimens of the genus Dipara Walker, 1833 from leaf litter samples of the Kakamega Forest in Kenya, we describe the following twelve new species: Dipara andreabalzerae sp. nov., Dipara corona sp. nov., Dipara fastigata sp. nov., Dipara kakamegensis sp. nov., Dipara lux sp. nov., Dipara nigroscutellata sp. nov., Dipara nyani sp. nov., Dipara reticulata sp. nov., Dipara rodneymulleni sp. nov., Dipara sapphirus sp. nov., Dipara tenebra sp. nov., and Dipara tigrina sp. nov. For Dipara albomaculata (Hedqvist, 1963) and Dipara nigrita Hedqvist, 1969, we give new distribution records. We examined the available type material of all described Dipara species from the Afrotropical mainland, i.e., Dipara albomaculata (Hedqvist, 1963), Dipara machadoi (Hedqvist, 1971), Dipara maculata (Hedqvist, 1963), Dipara nigrita Hedqvist, 1969, Dipara pallida (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara punctulata (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara saetosa (Delucchi, 1962), Dipara straminea (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara striata (Hedqvist, 1969), and Dipara turneri Hedqvist, 1969. We provide figures, descriptions, and diagnoses of the newly described species and figures and diagnoses of the ten known species as well as an identification key to all species of the Afrotropical mainland.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:33:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The giant pill-millipede genus Zephronia Gray, 1832 from Thailand, with a redescription of Z. siamensis Hirst, 1907 and descriptions of three new species (Diplopoda, Sphaerotheriida, Zephroniidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 19-56</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72369</p>
					<p>Authors: Ruttapon Srisonchai, Chirasak Sutcharit, Natdanai Likhitrakarn</p>
					<p>Abstract: Material of the giant pill-millipede genus Zephronia Gray, 1832 recently collected from Thailand contains three new species: Zephronia enghoffi sp. nov., Zephronia golovatchi sp. nov., and Zephronia panhai sp. nov. The first Zephronia species recorded for Thailand, Z. siamensis Hirst, 1907, is also redescribed based on new specimens collected both from the type locality in Chonburi Province and from neighboring areas. Morphological characters of all new species, Z. phrain Likhitrakarn &amp; Golovatch, 2021, and Z. siamensis are illustrated, and a distribution map of the confirmed Zephronia species occurring in Thailand is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:05:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Azooxanthellate Scleractinia (Cnidaria, Anthozoa) from South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1066: 1-198</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1066.69697</p>
					<p>Authors: Zoleka N. Filander, Marcelo V. Kitahara, Stephen D. Cairns, Kerry J. Sink, Amanda T. Lombard</p>
					<p>Abstract: Globally, South Africa ranks in the top five countries regarding marine species richness per unit area. Given the high diversity, it is not surprising that many invertebrate taxa in the region are poorly characterised. The South African azooxanthellate Scleractinia (Anthozoa) is one such taxonomic group, and was last reviewed by Boshoff in 1980. Although more recent regional publications have reported on some species, there has not been a faunistic review that accounts for the country’s species diversity since then. Moreover, numerous unidentified specimens representing more than three decades of sampling effort have accumulated. In this study the authors update the state of knowledge of South African azooxanthellate coral species. Specimens, particularly those within the extensive collections of the Iziko South African and Smithsonian museums, were morphologically examined and identified. Other data considered included historic data represented as imagery data, associated species data from recent research surveys, and the scientific literature. To date, the study has increased the total number of known species from 77 to 108 across eleven families, 28 new South African records, and three are new species with one new genus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Monograph</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:55:44 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic and identification review of adventive Fiorinia Targioni Tozzetti (Hemiptera, Coccomorpha, Diaspididae) of the United States</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 141-203</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.69171</p>
					<p>Authors: Muhammad Z. Ahmed, Matthew R. Moore, Eric A. Rohrig, Cindy L. McKenzie, Di Liu, Jinian Feng, Benjamin B. Normark, Douglass R. Miller</p>
					<p>Abstract: This work provides general descriptions, illustrations, molecular diagnostic data, taxonomic keys, slide mounting recommendations, and Florida distribution records for Fiorinia Targioni Tozzetti species occurring in the USA. Species treated are F. externa Ferris, F. fioriniae (Targioni Tozzetti), F. japonica Kuwana, F. pinicola Maskell, F. phantasma Cockerell &amp; Robinson, F. proboscidaria Green, and F. theae Green. New descriptions of second-instar males and females of all seven species in addition to first-instar nymphs and adult females of F. phantasma and F. proboscidaria are presented. Taxonomic keys to second-instar males and females are developed for the first time and previously available taxonomic keys to first-instar nymphs and adult females are improved. DNA sequences were used to further evaluate the monophyly of Fiorinia and provide additional diagnostic tools for Fiorinia species. Multigene phylogenetic analyses, COI barcoding methods, and examination of type material indicate that F. yongxingensis Liu, Cai &amp; Feng, 2020, syn. nov. is a junior synonym of F. phantasma. A morphological survey of the genus demonstrates, for the first time, the utility of second-instar males for diagnostics. This study will help inform regulatory and pest management decisions by facilitating morphological and molecular identification of adventive Fiorinia species occurring in the USA.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:18:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the brink of extinction: a new freshwater amphipod Jesogammarus acalceolus (Anisogammaridae) from Japan</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 81-100</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.71687</p>
					<p>Authors: Ko Tomikawa, Naoya Kimura</p>
					<p>Abstract: Freshwater habitats, especially cold springs, are environments in which the risk of extinction faced by organisms remains high due to human activities. To conserve endangered species, it is important to describe and name them. Here, a new, endangered freshwater anisogammarid amphipod species, Jesogammarus (Jesogammarus) acalceolus sp. nov., found in a spring in Aomori Prefecture, Japan, is described which is potentially the sole remaining habitat of this species. Both morphological and molecular phylogenetic results strongly support the nesting of the new species within Jesogammarus. Jesogammarus (J.) acalceolus sp. nov. is the first species of genus Jesogammarus that was found to lack a calceolus, a sensory organ located on male antenna 2. Thus, the diagnostic criteria for this genus required amendment. A reconstruction of ancestral calceoli, based on a molecular phylogenetic tree, revealed that the common ancestor of Jesogammarus possessed calceoli, which were secondarily lost in J. (J.) acalceolus sp. nov. Our results indicate that this new species, which is key to clarifying the evolution of the calceolus, is of high conservation significance.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:49:04 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New archidermapteran earwigs (Dermaptera) from the Middle Jurassic of Inner Mongolia, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 125-139</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.72720</p>
					<p>Authors: Shurong Xiong, Michael S. Engel, Lifang Xiao, Dong Ren</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Archidermaptera are described and figured from the Middle Jurassic Jiulonghsan Formation of Daohugou, Inner Mongolia, China. Aneuroderma oiodes gen. &amp; sp. nov. is described in the family Protodiplatyidae and Sinopalaeodermata concavum sp. nov. is established in the family Dermapteridae. Both new species share the typical characters of the extinct suborder Archidermaptera (e.g., pentamerous metatarsi, filiform and multimerous cerci, externalized ovipositor). Aneuroderma gen. nov. is compared with other genera of the Protodiplatyidae, while S. concavum sp. nov. allows us to emend the diagnosis of the genus Sinopalaeodermata. We briefly discuss the diversity of Archidermaptera and challenges to understanding relationships among this mid-Mesozoic diversity.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:41:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Rana sensu lato Linnaeus, 1758 (Anura, Ranidae) from Wuyi Mountain, Fujian Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 101-124</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.67005</p>
					<p>Authors: Yanqing Wu, Shengchao Shi, Huiguang Zhang, Weicai Chen, Bin Cai, Van Chung Hoang, Jun Wu, Bin Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the frog genus Rana sensu lato from Wuyi Mountain, Fujian Province, China is described. Molecular phylogenetic analyses clustered the new species into the R. johnsi group and indicated that it was genetically divergent from its closely related species. The new species could be distinguished from its congeners by a combination of the following characters: body size medium, SVL 41.4–45.6 mm (42.9 ± 1.9 mm, n = 4) in adult males and 47.6–50.3 mm (n = 2) in adult females; adult male with a pair of internal subgular vocal sacs; lateroventral grooves present on tip of toes; webbing on fourth toes reaching the tip of toe; transverse skin ridges distinctly present on the dorsal surface of thigh and tibia, the number large (mean 26.5 ± 2.7, range 22–29, n = 6); breeding males possess creamy white nuptial pad with tiny velvety spines on the dorsal surface of the first finger, divided into three parts.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:39:11 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The first Western Palearctic record of Euprosthenops Pocock (Araneae, Pisauridae), with description of a new species from Israel</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 13-27</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.74119</p>
					<p>Authors: Sergei Zonstein, Yuri M. Marusik</p>
					<p>Abstract: The primarily Afrotropical genus Euprosthenops Pocock, 1897 is recorded in the Western Palearctic for the first time. A diagnosis and an illustrated description of E. insperatus sp. nov., based on a single male from southern Israel, are provided. Considering the structure of the male palp, the holotype of E. insperatus sp. nov. resembles males of two widespread African species, E. australis Simon, 1898 and E. proximus Lessert, 1916; it differs from them by colouration pattern as well as by the different shapes of the retrolateral tibial apophysis and the palpal sclerites. A short survey of the regional insect and spider genera of the paleotropical origin is also presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:57:46 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the genus Polypedilum, subgenus Collartomyia, with description of P. (Col.) baishanzuensis sp. nov. from Baishanzu Nature Reserve, China (Diptera, Chironomidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.69870</p>
					<p>Authors: Chao Song, Binqing Zhu, Wei Liu, Xin Qi</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Polypedilum Kieffer, 1912 is described from Baishanzu Nature Reserve, China, based on molecular and morphological data. Molecular phylogenetic analysis based on standard barcode sequences confirmed a new clade of Polypedilum (Collartomyia) species. The new species is easily distinguished from its congeners by a combination of the following morphological characters: membrane of wing with a large spot occupying 70% of the proximal area; tergite without dark brown band pigmentation; tarsi I–V dark brown; superior volsella with three outer lateral setae and six long setae along inner base; inferior volsella with setose tubercules. An updated key to adult males of the subgenus Collartomyia is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:57:03 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Twenty-eight new species of Trigonopterus Fauvel (Coleoptera, Curculionidae) from Central Sulawesi</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 29-79</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.71680</p>
					<p>Authors: Raden Pramesa Narakusumo, Alexander Riedel</p>
					<p>Abstract: Here we present 28 new species of Trigonopterus from Central Sulawesi, mostly from Mt Dako and Mt Pompangeo: Trigonopterus acutus sp. nov., T. ancora sp. nov., T. arcanus sp. nov., T. corona sp. nov., T. dakoensis sp. nov., T. daun sp. nov., T. ewok sp. nov., T. gundala sp. nov., T. hoppla sp. nov., T. kakimerah sp. nov., T. katopasensis sp. nov., T. matakensis sp. nov., T. moduai sp. nov., T. mons sp. nov., T. paramoduai sp. nov. T. pomberimbensis sp. nov., T. pompangeensis sp. nov., T. puspoi sp. nov., T. rosichoni sp. nov., T. rubidus sp. nov., T. sarinoi sp. nov., T. sutrisnoi sp. nov., T. tanah sp. nov., T. tejokusumoi sp. nov., T. toboliensis sp. nov., T. tolitoliensis sp. nov., T. tounaensis sp. nov., T. unyil sp. nov. This fills important areas of distribution and brings the number of Trigonopterus species recorded from Sulawesi to 132.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 11:16:28 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Annotated catalogue of the Tachinidae (Insecta, Diptera) of Chile</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1064: 1-200</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1064.62972</p>
					<p>Authors: James E. O'Hara, D. Monty Wood, Christian R. González</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Tachinidae (Diptera) of Chile are catalogued and information is given on distributions, name-bearing types, synonyms, nomenclatural issues, and pertinent literature. The history of tachinid collectors in Chile and authors who have contributed to the systematic knowledge of Chilean tachinids is extensively reviewed. The classification has been updated and 122 genera and 264 species are recognised in Chile. There is a significant amount of endemism with 28 genera and 100 species known only from Chile. There are also 113 species with distributions shared only between Chile and Argentina, particularly in the southern portions of these countries comprising Patagonia.        The catalogue is based on examination of the original descriptions of all nominal species and all other references known to us containing relevant taxonomic and distributional information, for a total of approximately 450 references. Many of the name-bearing types and other Chilean specimens housed in collections were examined. Taxa are arranged hierarchically and alphabetically under the categories of subfamily, tribe, genus, subgenus (where recognised), and species. Nomenclatural information is provided for genus-group and species-group names, including lists of synonyms (mostly restricted to Neotropical taxa) and name-bearing type data. Species distributions are recorded by country within the New World and by larger geographical divisions in the Old World. Additional information is given in the form of notes and references under valid names at the level of tribe, genus, and species. Two genera are newly recorded from Chile: Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Tachinini) (also newly recorded from Argentina) and Patelloa Townsend, 1916 (Goniini). Four species are newly recorded from Chile or other countries: Lypha ornata Aldrich, 1934 (Chile); Chaetoepalpus coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Argentina and Chile); Phytomyptera evanescens (Cortés, 1967) (Argentina); and Xanthobasis unicolor Aldrich, 1934 (Chile). Eight species previously recorded from Chile are deemed to have been misidentified or misrecorded from Chile (known distributions in parentheses): Archytas incertus (Macquart, 1851) (Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, Uruguay); Archytas seminiger (Wiedemann, 1830) (Brazil, Colombia); Gonia crassicornis (Fabricius, 1794) (Brazil, Peru, Venezuela, Middle America, West Indies, Nearctic); Lespesia andina (Bigot, 1888) (Cuba); Lespesia archippivora (Riley, 1871) (widespread Nearctic and most of Neotropical); Neoethilla ignobilis (van der Wulp, 1890) (Mexico, United States); Siphona (Siphona) geniculata (De Geer, 1776) (Palaearctic, Nearctic [introduced]); and Winthemia quadripustulata (Fabricius, 1794) (Palaearctic, Nearctic, Oriental]. As First Reviser we fix Paratheresia rufiventris Townsend, 1929 as the senior homonym and Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929 as the junior homonym when the two are placed together in Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830; and we fix Mayophorinia angusta Townsend, 1927 as the senior homonym and Metarrhinomyia angusta Townsend, 1927 as the junior homonym when the two are placed together in Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889. New replacement names are proposed for eight preoccupied names of Neotropical species (country of type locality in parentheses): Billaea rufescens O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929, preoccupied in the genus Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 by Paratheresia rufiventris Townsend, 1929 (Peru), nom. nov.; Billaea triquetrus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sarcoprosena triangulifera Townsend, 1927, preoccupied in the genus Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 by Dexia triangulifera Zetterstedt, 1844 (Peru), nom. nov.; Eucelatoria nudioculata O’Hara &amp; Wood for Eucelatorioidea nigripalpis Thompson, 1968, preoccupied in the genus Eucelatoria Townsend, 1909 by Chetolyga nigripalpis Bigot, 1889 (Trinidad), nom. nov.; Eucelatoria oblonga O’Hara &amp; Wood for Urodexodes elongatum Cortés &amp; Campos, 1974, preoccupied in the genus Eucelatoria Townsend, 1909 by Exorista elongata van der Wulp, 1890 (Chile), nom. nov.; Lespesia thompsoni O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sturmiopsoidea obscura Thompson, 1966, preoccupied in the genus Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 by Eurigaster obscurus Bigot, 1857 (Cuba), nom. nov.; Myiopharus charapensis O’Hara &amp; Wood for Metarrhinomyia angusta Townsend, 1927, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Mayophorinia angusta Townsend, 1927 (Peru), nom. nov.; Myiopharus incognitus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Stenochaeta claripalpis Thompson, 1968, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Neoxynopsoidea claripalpis Thompson, 1968 (Trinidad), nom. nov.; and Myiopharus rufopalpus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Paralispe palpalis Townsend, 1929, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Myioxynops palpalis Townsend, 1927 (Peru), nom. nov. New type species fixations are made under the provisions of Article 70.3.2 of the ICZN Code for three genus-group names: Parafabricia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1894 (synonym of Archytas Jaennicke, 1867), type species newly fixed as Parafabricia perplexa Townsend, 1931; Tachinodes Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 (synonym of Archytas Jaennicke, 1867), type species newly fixed as Jurinia metallica Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830; and Willistonia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 (synonym of Belvosia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830), type species newly fixed as Willistonia aldrichi Townsend, 1931. Lectotypes are designated for the following four nominal species, all described or possibly described from Chile: Echinomyia pygmaea Macquart, 1851 (a valid name in the genus Peleteria Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830); Gonia chilensis Macquart, 1844 (a junior synonym of Gonia pallens Wiedemann, 1830); Masicera auriceps Macquart, 1844 (a valid name in the genus Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863); and Prosopochoeta nitidiventris Macquart, 1851 (a valid name in the genus Prosopochaeta Macquart, 1851). The following 27 new or revived combinations are proposed (distributions in parentheses): Blepharipeza andina Bigot, 1888 is moved to Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 as L. andina, nomen dubium (Cuba), comb. nov.; Camposodes evanescens Cortés, 1967 is moved to Phytomyptera Rondani, 1845 as P. evanescens (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Ectophasiopsis ypiranga Dios &amp; Nihei, 2017 is moved to Trichopoda Berthold, 1827 and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia Townsend, 1908 as T. (G.) ypiranga (Argentina, Brazil), comb. nov.; Embiomyia australis Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Steleoneura Stein, 1924 as S. australis (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Eurigaster modestus Bigot, 1857 is moved to Lespesia as L. modesta (Cuba), comb. nov.; Eurigaster obscurus Bigot, 1857 is moved to Lespesia as L. obscura (Cuba), comb. nov.; Macropatelloa tanumeana Townsend, 1931 is moved to Patelloa Townsend, 1916 as P. tanumeana (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Masicera insignis van der Wulp, 1882 is moved to Drino Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 as D. insignis (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Parasetigena hichinsi Cortés, 1967 is moved to Chetogena Rondani, 1856 as C. hichinsi (Chile), comb. nov.; Parasetigena porteri Brèthes, 1920 and junior synonym Stomatotachina splendida Townsend, 1931 are moved to Chetogena as C. porteri (Chile), both comb. nov.; Phorocera calyptrata Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 as A. calyptrata (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Poliops auratus Campos, 1953 is moved to Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 as A. aurata (Chile), comb. nov.; Poliops striatus Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Admontia as A. striata (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Ruiziella frontosa Cortés, 1951 is moved to Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 and placed in synonymy with C. coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Argentina, Chile, Peru), comb. nov.; Ruiziella luctuosa Cortés, 1951 is moved to Chaetoepalpus as C. luctuosus (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena luteola Cortés &amp; Campos, 1974 is moved to Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 as B. luteola (Chile), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929 is moved to Billaea where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed B. rufescens O’Hara &amp; Wood (Peru), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena triangulifera Townsend, 1927 is moved to Billaea where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed B. triquetrus O’Hara &amp; Wood (Peru),comb. nov.; Saundersia aurea Giglio-Tos, 1893 is moved to “Unplaced species of Tachinini” (Mexico), comb. nov.; Schistostephana aurifrons Townsend, 1919 is moved to Billaea as B. aurifrons (Peru), comb. nov.; Siphoactia charapensis Townsend, 1927 is moved to Clausicella Rondani, 1856 as C. charapensis (Peru), comb. nov.; Siphoactia peregrina Cortés &amp; Campos, 1971 is moved to Clausicella as C. peregrina (Chile), comb. nov.; Sturmia festiva Cortés, 1944 is moved to Drino as D. festiva (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Sturmiopsoidea obscura Thompson, 1966 is moved to Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863, where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed L. thompsoni O’Hara &amp; Wood (Trinidad), comb. nov.; Trichopoda arcuata Bigot, 1876 is returned to Trichopoda from Ectophasiopsis Townsend, 1915 and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia (Argentina, Chile), comb. revived; and Trichopoda gradata Wiedemann, 1830 is returned to Trichopoda from Ectophasiopsis and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia (Argentina, Brazil, Uruguay), comb. revived. New or revived generic and specific synonymies are proposed for the following 14 names: Camposodes Cortés, 1967 with Phytomyptera Rondani, 1845, syn. nov.; Ectophasiopsis Townsend, 1915 with Trichopoda Berthold, 1827, subgenus Galactomyia Townsend, 1908, syn. nov.; Embiomyia Aldrich, 1934 with Steleoneura Stein, 1924, syn. nov.; Fabricia andicola Bigot, 1888 with Peleteria robusta (Wiedemann, 1830), syn. revived; Macropatelloa Townsend, 1931 with Patelloa Townsend, 1916, syn. nov.; Peleteria inca Curran, 1925 with Peleteria robusta (Wiedemann, 1830), syn. revived; Poliops Aldrich, 1934 with Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889, syn. nov.; Ruiziella Cortés, 1951 with Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940, syn. nov.; Ruiziella frontosa Cortés, 1951 with Chaetoepalpus coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940, syn. nov.; Sarcoprosena Townsend, 1927 with Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830, syn. nov.; Schistostephana Townsend, 1919 with Billaea, syn. nov.; Siphoactia Townsend, 1927 with Clausicella Rondani, 1856, syn. nov.; Stomatotachina Townsend, 1931 with Chetogena Rondani, 1856, syn. nov.; and Sturmiopsoidea Thompson, 1966 with Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863, syn. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Catalogue</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:11:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Pseudosinella Schäffer, 1897 (Collembola, Entomobryidae) from Hungary and Romania, with redescription of the related species Pseudosinella huetheri Stomp, 1971</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 121-137</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.73094</p>
					<p>Authors: Daniel Winkler, Márton Tamás Németh, Cristina Fiera</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Pseudosinella Schäffer, 1897 from Hungary and Romania is described and illustrated. Pseudosinella hartnerae sp. nov. belongs to the group with 5+5 eyes, and can be identified by its unique labial chaetotaxy (M1m2rel1L2) within this group. Pseudosinella huetheri Stomp, 1971, the closest related species sharing the same dorsal macrochaetae formula (R0R1R2001/00/0101+2), is also redescribed here based on the holotype. Comparative analysis between the two species and among other related species is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 17:46:04 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Gelechia omelkoi sp. nov. – a new species from the Russian Altai Mountains related to the Nearctic Gelechia mandella Busck, 1904 (Lepidoptera, Gelechiidae), with a synopsis of Gelechia from the Altai Republic of Russia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 105-120</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.71914</p>
					<p>Authors: Oleksiy Bidzilya, Peter Huemer, Jean-François Landry, Jan Šumpich</p>
					<p>Abstract: Gelechia omelkoi sp. nov. is described from the Ukok plateau and South Chuisky ridge in the Altai Mountains of Russia. The adult of the new species, including its male genitalia, is illustrated and compared with species most similar in morphology and DNA barcodes—G. sororculella (Hübner, 1817) and G. jakovlevi Krulikovsky, 1905 from the Palaearctic region, as well as G. mandella Busck, 1904 from Canada. This last species is redescribed based on adult specimens, including the genitalia of both sexes, and a lectotype is designated. Gelechia sirotina Omelko, 1986 is recorded from the Altai Republic for the first time. An updated list of six species of Gelechia from the Altai Mountains of Russia is given. Dorsal habitus photographs of all species are provided. The male genitalia of the lectotype of G. jakovlevi is illustrated for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 07:00:10 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the genus Niphta (Diptera, Thaumaleidae) Theischinger of South America, with descriptions of nine new species and a new immature morphotype</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 49-104</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.71180</p>
					<p>Authors: Robert J. Pivar, Bradley J. Sinclair, John K. Moulton</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Niphta Theischinger fauna of South America is revised to include 11 species, nine of which are described as new to science (N. acus Pivar, sp. nov., N. bifurcata Pivar &amp; Moulton, sp. nov., N. bispinosa Pivar &amp; Sinclair, sp. nov., N. brunnea Pivar, sp. nov., N. courtneyi Pivar, sp. nov., N. daniellae Pivar, sp. nov., N. downesi Pivar, sp. nov., N. eurydactyla Pivar, sp. nov., N. mapuche Pivar, sp. nov.). The genus Niphta is redefined, both previously described Chilean species are redescribed, N. halteralis (Edwards) and N. nudipennis (Edwards), and females are described or redescribed where possible. The first descriptions of the immature stages of South American Niphta are provided, which represent a new larval morphotype in Thaumaleidae, as larvae and pupae possess ventral adhesive structures. Furthermore, these larvae were collected from vegetation rather than rocky substrates. Illustrations and micrographs are provided for all species, and scanning electron microscopy images are included for select immatures. A key to species, distribution maps, and discussions regarding phylogenetic affinities and habitat are also included.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 07:00:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the Chinese species of subgenus Koreonialoe (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Pterostichus), with descriptions of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 1-21</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.69942</p>
					<p>Authors: Wen-Qi Yin, Hong-Liang Shi, Hong-Bin Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Chinese species of subgenus Koreonialoe Park &amp; Kwon, 1996 of the genus Pterostichus are revised, including four species from the eastern part of Jilin and Liaoning provinces. Two new species are described: Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) micropoides sp. nov. (type locality: Jilin, Changbai county), and Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) tetralobatus sp. nov. (type locality: Liaoning, Xiuyan county). Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) bellatrix (Tschitschérine) is newly recorded from China (Jilin). The subgenus Koreonialoe is classified into two groups on account of their differences on the endophallus, and all Chinese species accord with the microps group defined herein. A key to all six species in the microps group is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 15:04:55 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Amphibians of the equatorial seasonally dry forests of Ecuador and Peru</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 23-48</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.69580</p>
					<p>Authors: Diego Armijos-Ojeda, Diana Székely, Paul Székely, Dan Cogălniceanu, Diego F. Cisneros-Heredia, Leonardo Ordóñez-Delgado, Adrián Escudero, Carlos Iván Espinosa</p>
					<p>Abstract: Seasonally dry forests (SDFs) are one of the most challenging ecosystems for amphibians, fueling the diversity of this group of vertebrates. An updated inventory of native amphibians present in the Equatorial SDF is provided, which extends along the Pacific coast of Ecuador and northwestern Peru. The study is based on an extensive field sampling (two thirds of the total records) carried out throughout the Equatorial SDF, along with a compilation of the available information on distribution of amphibians in the region from published scientific papers, museum collections and on-line databases. The final dataset included 2,032 occurrence records for 30 amphibian species, belonging to eight anuran families. Additionally, data regarding conservation status, habitat use, spawn deposition site, reproductive mode, and body size, along with an identification key for all encountered species are provided. The results indicate a strong sampling bias with a deficit in the Peruvian part of the study area, and a need for urgent inventories targeted at under-sampled areas, using modern taxonomic methods. The study emphasizes the conservation priorities in the Equatorial SDF, based on the distribution, conservation status and life-history data. This information should be useful for the local authorities and institutions involved in the management and conservation of biodiversity in SDF.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:46:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Marine diversity in the biosphere reserve of the most oceanic island in the Gulf of California: San Pedro Mártir</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 177-201</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.67964</p>
					<p>Authors: Imelda G. Amador-Castro, Francisco J. Fernández-Rivera Melo, Jorge Torre</p>
					<p>Abstract: San Pedro Mártir island is of high biological, ecological, and fishery importance and was declared a biosphere reserve in 2002. This island is the most oceanic in the Gulf of California, and information on its rocky reefs is scarce. The present study aimed to generate the first list of conspicuous invertebrate and fish species based on in situ observations and to examine the community structure of the shallow rocky reefs of the reserve. In addition, we estimated the ecological indicators of richness, abundance, Shannon diversity, and Pielou evenness to evaluate the conservation status of the biosphere reserve. Data were collected annually from 2007 to 2017 through 2,192 underwater SCUBA transects. A total of 35 species of invertebrates and 73 species of fish were recorded. Most of the species are widely distributed along the eastern Pacific. Overall, 64% of the species found in this study are commercially important, and 11 species have been listed as protected. The abundance of commercially important invertebrate species (i.e., the sea cucumber Isostichopus fuscus and the spiny oyster Spondylus limbatus) is decreasing, while commercially important fish species have maintained their abundance with periods of increase. The ecological indicators and the abundance and size of the commercial species indicate that the reserve is in good condition while meeting its conservation objectives.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 15:00:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Amphibian fauna of Pakistan with notes on future prospects of research and conservation</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 157-175</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.66913</p>
					<p>Authors: Muhammad Rais, Waseem Ahmed, Anum Sajjad, Ayesha Akram, Muhammad Saeed, Hannan Nasib Hamid, Aamina Abid</p>
					<p>Abstract: Research on amphibians and their conservation have gained worldwide attention, as the group includes the highest number of threatened and Data Deficient species when compared to other vertebrates. However, amphibians have long been neglected in wildlife conservation, management decisions, policy making, and research agendas in Pakistan. In this paper, an annotated checklist of the 21 amphibian species of Pakistan, a key to their identification, and detailed discussions on variation in species, including the genera Minervarya and Sphaerotheca, are provided. We found a statistically significant difference in the morphometric measurements of males but non-significant difference in the females of the two forms (rusty dorsum and dotted dorsum) of S. maskeyi. Some genera, such as Microhyla, Uperodon, Minervarya, Allopaa, Chrysopaa, Euphlyctis, Nanorana, and Sphaerotheca, in Pakistan are in need of additional data for molecular and morphological comparisons with taxa in other South Asian countries. The predicaments of amphibian research in Pakistan are discussed, gaps identified, and suggestions are made. Although the occurrence of chytrid fungus in Pakistan is predicted of low likelihood, a lack of data merits studying the prevalence of the fungus, particularly in the northern regions of the country which exhibit complex and dynamic ecosystems. It is recommended that systematic and coordinated surveys are conducted throughout the country to build a database of species occurrences and distributions. Additionally, the monitoring of wild populations and threat mitigation, as well as appropriate legislation, are suggested as long-term measures. By adopting an inclusive wildlife conservation approach in Pakistan, amphibians could be integrated into wildlife conservation and management efforts.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Review Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 14:58:58 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On ten species of jumping spiders from Xishuangbanna, China (Araneae, Salticidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 123-155</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.72531</p>
					<p>Authors: Cheng Wang, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Nine new species of jumping spiders from Xishuangbanna Tropical Botanical Garden are described: Euochin yaoi sp. nov. (♀♂), Laufeia banna sp. nov. (♀♂), Marengo tangi sp. nov. (♀♂), Myrmarachne liui sp. nov. (♀♂), Nandicius proszynskii sp. nov. (♂), Phintelloides pengi sp. nov. (♀♂), Poecilorchestes zhengi sp. nov. (♀♂), Rhene wandae sp. nov. (♂) and Simaetha cheni sp. nov. (♀♂). The female of Chinattus inflatus Wang &amp; Li, 2020 is described for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the clubionid spiders (Araneae, Clubionidae) from Xishuangbanna, China, with descriptions of two new genera and seven new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 73-122</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.66845</p>
					<p>Authors: Jianshuang Zhang, Hao Yu, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Clubionid spiders from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, China are studied. A total of seven genera and 13 species have been found, including two new genera with one new species each, i.e., Ramosatidia Yu &amp; Li, gen. nov., with R. situ Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀) as the type species and Sinostidia Yu &amp; Li, gen. nov., with S. shuangjiao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀) as the type species. Five additional new species are Sinostidia dujiao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), Matidia xieqian Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), Nusatidia changao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), N. mianju Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♀), and N. subjavana Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♀). The following genera and species are reported from China for the first time: Malamatidia Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Pteroneta Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Malamatidia zu Jäger &amp; Dankittipakul, 2010, Nusatidia aeria (Simon, 1897), N. camouflata Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Porrhoclubiona pteronetoides (Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001), and Pteroneta ultramarina (Ono, 1989). Malamatidia christae Jäger &amp; Dankittipakul, 2010 syn. nov. is a junior synonym of Malamatidia zu. Nusatidia rama Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001 syn. nov. is synonymised with N. aeria (Simon, 1897).</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:36:32 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Unexpected diversity in Central European Vespoidea (Hymenoptera, Mutillidae, Myrmosidae, Sapygidae, Scoliidae, Tiphiidae, Thynnidae, Vespidae), with description of two species of Smicromyrme Thomson, 1870</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 49-72</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.70763</p>
					<p>Authors: Christian Schmid-Egger, Stefan Schmidt</p>
					<p>Abstract: The present study presents DNA barcoding results for 134 species of Central European Vespoidea, families Mutillidae, Myrmosidae, Sapygidae, Scoliidae, Tiphiidae, Thynnidae, and Vespidae, including DNA barcodes for 100 of the 114 German species. DNA barcoding resulted in unexpected diversity in several families, each with two or more genetic clusters identified by Barcode Index Numbers (BINs). Smicromyrme burgeri Schmid-Egger, sp. nov. and S. langobardensis Schmid-Egger, sp. nov. are described as new from Germany and Italy, respectively. A neotype is designated for Smicromyrme rufipes (Fabricius, 1878). The results of DNA barcoding are discussed in respect to detecting cryptic species and refining species limits.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 09:30:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new insular species of the Cyrtodactylus pulchellus group (Reptilia, Gekkonidae) from Tarutao Island, southern Thailand revealed by morphological and genetic evidence</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 101-134</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73659</p>
					<p>Authors: Korkhwan Termprayoon, Attapol Rujirawan, Natee Ampai, Perry L. Wood Jr, Anchalee Aowphol</p>
					<p>Abstract: The bent-toed geckos of the Cyrtodactylus pulchellus group are widely distributed along the Thai-Malay Peninsula. Although taxonomic and phylogenetic studies of this species group have been continuously conducted, only some populations from Thailand have been included, resulting in hidden diversity within this group. In this study, we used morphological and molecular data to clarify the taxonomic status and describe a new population from Tarutao Island, Satun Province, southern Thailand. Cyrtodactylus stellatus sp. nov. can be distinguished from its congeners by the combination of the following morphological characters: body size; tuberculation; number of dark body bands, ventral scales, and femoroprecloacal pores in males; presence of precloacal pores in females; and scattered pattern on dorsum. Phylogenetic analyses of the mitochondrial ND2 gene recovered the new species as the sister species to C. astrum, with an uncorrected pairwise divergence of 9.78–12.37%. Cyrtodactylus stellatus sp. nov. is currently only known from Tarutao Island, Thailand. The discovery of this species suggests that the diversity within the C. pulchellus group remains underestimated and future exploration of unsurveyed areas are needed to further the understanding of this group and its geographic range.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:37:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of freshwater crab of the genus Nanhaipotamon Bott, 1968 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Brachyura, Potamidae) from Longhai, Fujian Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 11-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.71171</p>
					<p>Authors: Mao-Rong Cai, Qi-Hong Tan, Jie-Xin Zou</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of freshwater crab of the genus Nanhaipotamon Bott, 1968 is described from Xiaye Village, Chengxiang Town, Longhai County, Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province, China. The new species is distinguished from congeners by the combination of characters of its carapace, third maxilliped, unequal chelipeds, triangular male abdomen and unique male first gonopod. Molecular evidence derived from partial mitochondrial 16S rRNA and COI genes also support the species as new.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:11:29 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Stenomesius Westwood (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) from China, with a key to Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 1-10</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.67487</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun-Jie Fan, Cheng-De Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Stenomesius Westwood, S. guanshanensis sp. nov., S. hani sp. nov., and S. harbinensis sp. nov., are described from China. A key to all species of the genus Stenomesius in China is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:09:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New data on the valvatiform-shelled Hydrobiidae (Caenogastropoda, Truncatelloidea) from southern Greece</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 31-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.64746</p>
					<p>Authors: Sebastian Hofman, Jozef Grego, Zoltán Fehér, Zoltán Péter Erőss, Aleksandra Rysiewska, Artur Osikowski, Andrzej Falniowski</p>
					<p>Abstract: The minute valvatiform-shelled Hydrobiidae are less studied than other hydrobiid gastropods. In this paper, new data on these snails are presented, which have been collected at twelve springs in southern Greece: one in Boeotia, one on Evvoia Island, and ten on the Peloponnese Peninsula. Mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) and nuclear histone (H3) have been used to confirm the determinations and infer the relationships of the studied gastropods. They represent the genera Daphniola, Graecoarganiella and Isimerope. New localities, expanding the known geographic ranges, have been presented for Daphniola hadei and Daphniola louisi. A species of Daphniola found at two localities has been identified as a species new to science, and its description, including the shell, penis, and female reproductive organs is given. Possible relationships between Graecoarganiella and Isimerope are discussed; their representatives are possibly new species. At one locality a single specimen likely represents a new genus: it was found to be most closely related with Islamia, but genetically (p-distance) too distant to be congeneric with Islamia.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 11:48:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The Herniosina story continues in the Mediterranean: H. calabra sp. nov. from Calabria and H. erymantha Roháček, new female from the Peloponnese (Diptera, Sphaeroceridae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 165-190</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.72235</p>
					<p>Authors: Jindřich Roháček</p>
					<p>Abstract: A study of recently acquired material of Herniosina Roháček, 1983 (Diptera: Sphaeroceridae: Limosininae) in the Mediterranean subregion revealed a new species, H. calabra sp. nov. (Italy: Calabria: Serre Calabresi Mts) and the first females of H. erymantha Roháček, 2016 (Greece: southern Peloponnese: Taygetos Mts). Herniosina calabra sp. nov. (both sexes) and the female of H. erymantha are described and illustrated in detail including structures of terminalia, their relationships are discussed and new information on their biology (habitat association) is given. An update of a key to all know species of Herniosina species is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 15:48:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Micrurapteryx (Lepidoptera, Gracillariidae) feeding on Thermopsis lanceolata (Fabaceae) in southern Siberia and its hymenopterous parasitoids</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 131-163</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70929</p>
					<p>Authors: Natalia I. Kirichenko, Evgeny N. Akulov, Paolo Triberti, Sergey A. Belokobylskij</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of leaf-mining moth described here as Micrurapteryx baranchikovi Kirichenko, Akulov &amp; Triberti, sp. nov. was detected in large numbers feeding on Thermopsis lanceolata (Fabaceae) in the Republic of Khakassia (Russia) in 2020. A morphological diagnosis of adults, bionomics and DNA barcoding data of the new species are provided. The developmental stages (larva, pupa, adult), male and female genitalia, as well as the leaf mines and the infestation plot in Khakassia are illustrated; the pest status of the new species in the studied region is discussed. Additionally, parasitism rate was estimated, the parasitoid wasps reared from pupae of the new species were identified (morphologically and genetically) and illustrated . Among them, one ichneumonid, Campoplex sp. aff. borealis (Zetterstedt) and two braconids, Agathis fuscipennis (Zetterstedt) and Illidops subversor (Tobias et Kotenko), are novel records for the Republic of Khakassia. Furthermore, they are all documented as parasitoids of Gracillariidae for the first time. The DNA barcode of A. fuscipennis is newly obtained and can be used as a reference sequence for species identification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 8 Oct 2021 14:24:47 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Molecular phylogenetic analysis of the genus Gloydius (Squamata, Viperidae, Crotalinae), with description of two new alpine species from Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 87-108</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70420</p>
					<p>Authors: Jing-Song Shi, Jin-Cheng Liu, Rohit Giri, John Benjamin Owens, Vishal Santra, Sourish Kuttalam, Melvin Selvan, Ke-Ji Guo, Anita Malhotra</p>
					<p>Abstract: We provide a molecular phylogeny of Asian pit vipers (the genus Gloydius) based on four mitochondrial genes (12S, 16S, ND4, and cytb). Sequences of Gloydius himalayanus, the only member of the genus that occurs south of the Himalayan range, are included for the first time. In addition, two new species of the genus Gloydius are described based on specimens collected from Zayu, Tibet, west of the Nujiang River and Heishui, Sichuan, east of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. The new species, Gloydius lipipengi sp. nov., can be differentiated from its congeners by the combination of the following characters: the third supralabial not reaching the orbit (separated from it by a suborbital scale); wide, black-bordered greyish postorbital stripe extending from the posterior margin of the orbit (not separated by the postoculars, covering most of the anterior temporal scale) to the ventral surface of the neck; irregular black annular crossbands on the mid-body; 23-21-15 dorsal scales; 165 ventral scales, and 46 subcaudal scales. Gloydius swild sp. nov. can be differentiated from its congeners by the narrower postorbital stripe (only half the width of the anterior temporal scale, the lower edge is approximately straight and bordered with white); a pair of arched stripes on the occiput; lateral body lakes black spots; a pair of round spots on the parietal scales; 21 rows of mid-body dorsal scales; zigzag dark brown stripes on the dorsum; 168–170 ventral scales, and 43–46 subcaudal scales. The molecular phylogeny in this study supports the sister relationship between G. lipipengi sp. nov. and G. rubromaculatus, another recently described species from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, more than 500 km away, and indicate the basal position of G. himalayanus within the genus and relatively distant relationship to its congeners.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 4 Oct 2021 15:52:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Feather mites (Acariformes, Astigmata) from marine birds of the Barton Peninsula (King George Island, Antarctica), with descriptions of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 109-130</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.71212</p>
					<p>Authors: Yeong-Deok Han, Sergey V. Mironov, Jeong-Hoon Kim, Gi-Sik Min</p>
					<p>Abstract: We report on the first investigation of feather mites associated with birds living on the Barton Peninsula (King George Island, Antarctica). We found seven feather mite species of the superfamily Analgoidea from four host species. Two new species are described from two charadriiform hosts: Alloptes (Sternalloptes) antarcticus sp. nov. (Alloptidae) from Stercorarius maccormicki Saunders (Stercorariidae), and Ingrassia chionis sp. nov. (Xolalgidae) from Chionis albus (Gmelin) (Chionidae). Additionally, we provide partial sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI), which was utilized as a DNA barcode, for all seven feather mite species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 4 Oct 2021 10:43:16 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The complete mitochondrial genome of Microphysogobio elongatus (Teleostei, Cyprinidae) and its phylogenetic implications</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 57-73</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70176</p>
					<p>Authors: Renyi Zhang, Qian Tang, Lei Deng</p>
					<p>Abstract: Mitochondria are important organelles with independent genetic material of eukaryotic organisms. In this study, we sequenced and analyzed the complete mitogenome of a small cyprinid fish, Microphysogobio elongatus (Yao &amp; Yang, 1977). The mitogenome of M. elongatus is a typical circular molecule of 16,612 bp in length containing 13 protein-coding genes (PCGs), 22 transfer RNA genes, two ribosomal RNA genes, and a 930 bp control region. The base composition of the M. elongatus mitogenome is 30.8% A, 26.1% T, 16.7% G, and 26.4% C. All PCGs used the standard ATG start codon with the exception of COI. Six PCGs terminate with complete stop codons, whereas seven PCGs (ND2, COII, ATPase 6, COIII, ND3, ND4, and Cyt b) terminate with incomplete (T or TA) stop codons. All tRNA genes exhibited typical cloverleaf secondary structures with the exception of tRNASer(AGY), for which the dihydrouridine arm forms a simple loop. The phylogenetic analysis divided the subfamily Gobioninae in three clades with relatively robust support, and that Microphysogobio is not a monophyletic group. The complete mitogenome of M. elongatus provides a valuable resource for future studies about molecular phylogeny and/or population genetics of Microphysogobio.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 15:00:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Extinct before discovered? Epactoides giganteus sp. nov. (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae, Scarabaeinae), the first native dung beetle to Réunion island</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 75-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70130</p>
					<p>Authors: Michele Rossini, Fernando Z. Vaz-de-Mello, Olivier Montreuil, Nicholas Porch, Sergei Tarasov</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe a new species of dung beetle, Epactoides giganteus sp. nov., from a single female specimen allegedly collected in the 19th century on Réunion island and recently found at the Muséum national d’Histoire naturelle, Paris. This species differs from other species of Epactoides by larger size and a set of other distinctive morphological characters. Epactoides giganteus sp. nov. is the first native dung beetle (Scarabaeinae) of Réunion, and its discovery expands the known area of distribution of the genus Epactoides, which was hitherto believed to be endemic to Madagascar. Like other taxa from Madagascar and peripheral islands (e.g., Comoro, Seychelles, Mascarenes), E. giganteus sp. nov. may have reached Réunion by over-water dispersal. Given the rapid loss of biodiversity on Réunion island and the fact that no additional specimens were re-collected over the last two centuries, it is very likely that E. giganteus sp. nov. has gone extinct. However, we have unconfirmed evidence that the holotype of E. giganteus sp. nov. might be a mislabeled specimen from Madagascar, which would refute the presence of native dung beetles on Réunion. We discuss both hypotheses about the specimen origin and assess the systematic position of E. giganteus sp. nov. by examining most of the described species of Madagascan Epactoides. Additionally, we provide a brief overview of the dung beetle fauna of Mascarene Archipelago.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 11:55:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Tipula (Vestiplex) crane flies (Diptera, Tipulidae) of Korea</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 23-55</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.49999</p>
					<p>Authors: Pavel Starkevich, Sigitas Podėnas, Virginija Podėnienė, Sun-Jae Park, A-Young Kim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Korean species of Tipula (Vestiplex) Bezzi, 1924 crane flies are taxonomically revised. Five species are recognized. Tipula (V.) coquillettiana Alexander, 1924, T. (V.) kuwayamai Alexander, 1921, T. (V.) tchukchi Alexander, 1934, and T. (V.) verecunda Alexander, 1924 are newly recorded from the Korean Peninsula, and T. (V.) serricauda Alexander, 1914 was previously recorded. The larva of T. (V.) serricauda is described and illustrated, and the larvae of the subgenus T. (Vestiplex) are divided into four groups based on spiracular lobe morphology. An identification key, redescriptions, and illustrations of Korean T. (Vestiplex) adults and grouping of known larvae are presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:35:06 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
	