<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
		<id>http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/issue/feed</id>
	<title>Entomologisk Tidskrift</title>

																																																							<updated>2021-07-15T07:29:32+00:00</updated>

				<author>
			<name>Emma Wahlberg</name>
						<email>editor@et-online.nu</email>
					</author>
	
	<link rel="alternate" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/feed/atom" />

	
		
	<generator uri="http://pkp.sfu.ca/ojs/" version="3.3.0.5">Open Journal Systems</generator>
				
	<subtitle type="html">&lt;p&gt;Entomologisk Tidskrift har utgivits sedan 1880 och är en av världens äldsta entomologiska tidskrifter. Sveriges Entomologiska Förening bildades 1976 och tog därefter över utgivningen från Stockholm Entomologiska Förening. Tidskriften utkommer med fyra nummer varav ett kan vara ett dubbelnummer. En volym (fyra nummer) omfattar ca 190-220 sidor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Entomologisk Tidskrift publicerar originalarbeten, översiktsartiklar, notiser och bokrecensioner om alla aspekter av entomologi och småkryp. I första hand antas uppsatser av svenskt eller nordiskt intresse. Huvudspråket är svenska men även danska, norska och engelska accepteras. Alla inskickade arbeten bedöms av två fackgranskare.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Entomologisk Tidskrift ges ut av Sveriges Entomologiska Förening och ansvarig utgivare är Linda Strand.&lt;/p&gt;</subtitle>

						<entry>
								<id>http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/84</id>
				<title>Mykofaga gallmyggor (Diptera: Cecidomyiidae exkl. Cecidomyiinae) i Sverige: statusrapport efter 15 års taxonomisk inventering, kommentarer till artlistan och beskrivning av Camptomyia alstromi sp. nov.</title>
				<updated>2021-07-15T07:08:44+00:00</updated>

				
									<author>
						<name>Mathias Jaschhof</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
									<author>
						<name>Catrin Jaschhof</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
								<link rel="alternate" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/84" />

									<summary type="html" xml:base="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/84">&lt;p&gt;As a result of 15 years of taxonomic inventory, the Swedish fauna of mycophagous gall midges (Diptera: Cecidomyiidae excl. Cecidomyiinae) is shown to include 97 genera (incl. 2 subgenera) and 639 species (incl. 19 aggregate species), not counting 178 species identified as unnamed. Species are listed and annotated regarding their geographical distribution outside and within Sweden, their first mention for Sweden in literature (“first report”), and publications useful for identification. &lt;em&gt;Camptomyia alstromi&lt;/em&gt; Jaschhof &amp;amp; Jaschhof is described as a new species. &lt;em&gt;Paurodyla serrulata&lt;/em&gt; (Jaschhof, 2013), previously classified in the genus &lt;em&gt;Porricondyla&lt;/em&gt; Rondani, 1840, is a new combination. Species reported for the first time as occurring in Sweden are: &lt;em&gt;Anarete corni&lt;/em&gt; (Felt, 1907); &lt;em&gt;Anarete johnsoni&lt;/em&gt; (Felt, 1908); &lt;em&gt;Anarete triarthra&lt;/em&gt; Edwards, 1938; &lt;em&gt;Campylomyza cornuta&lt;/em&gt; Jaschhof, 1998; &lt;em&gt;Campylomyza nigroliminata&lt;/em&gt; Mamaev, 1998; and &lt;em&gt;Parepidosis ulmicorticis&lt;/em&gt; Mamaev, 1964. The last two species are diagnosed and illustrated. Provided also are: an introduction to the target group regarding diversity, biology, geographical distribution and study methods; an overview of classification; an outline of the inventory’s history; and a discussion reflecting on the status quo and the prospects for mycophagous cecidomyiid taxonomy. As a further component of the discussion, an attempt is made to estimate the number of species of Cecidomyiidae both in Sweden and the World, based on data at the authors’ disposal including that presented here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
				
												
									<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
				
								<rights>Copyright (c) 2021 Entomologisk Tidskrift</rights>
			</entry>
					<entry>
								<id>http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/85</id>
				<title>Acrotona pilosicollis (Brundin, 1952) (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae) – beskrivning av honan och noteringar om biologin</title>
				<updated>2021-07-15T07:21:43+00:00</updated>

				
									<author>
						<name>Tom Clayhills</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
									<author>
						<name>Jyrki Muona</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
								<link rel="alternate" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/85" />

									<summary type="html" xml:base="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/85">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acrotona pilosicollis&lt;/em&gt; (Brundin, 1952) is a poorly known staphylinid species. Only two records exist from NE Europe after it was described in 1952. Here we report 97 individuals caught in pitfall traps in a dry meadow in eastern Finland in 2017. The species is similar to &lt;em&gt;A. exigua&lt;/em&gt; (Erichson, 1837) but may be distinguished both on genital and external characters. The diagnostic spermatheca of the previously unknown female is described. On the basis of the new finds in Finland, &lt;em&gt;A. pilosicollis&lt;/em&gt; is considered to be a stenotypic species of dry xerothermic meadows.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
				
												
									<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
				
								<rights>Copyright (c) 2021 Entomologisk Tidskrift</rights>
			</entry>
					<entry>
								<id>http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/86</id>
				<title>Skalbaggarna i luften</title>
				<updated>2021-07-15T07:26:16+00:00</updated>

				
									<author>
						<name>Christer Solbreck</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
									<author>
						<name>Mikael Sörensson</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
									<author>
						<name>Åke Lindelöw</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
								<link rel="alternate" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/86" />

									<summary type="html" xml:base="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/86">&lt;p&gt;Flight activity and dispersal habits are still poorly known for most small Coleoptera species. Here, we investigate patterns of flight activity and flight altitude of beetles in the hemiboreal zone of northern Europe. Flying beetles were collected during one summer using four large suction traps mounted up to 93m above ground on a TV tower. The trapping site is situated in a mixed coniferous forest area subjected to standard logging practice in the province of Värmland, western Sweden. Altogether, 450 flying beetle species were collected in this rather ”trivial” habitat, representing about 20% of the provincial fauna and 10% of the entire Swedish beetle fauna. Rove beetles (Staphylinidae) comprised the most species rich family with 183 species. A total of over 47 700 individual beetles were caught. The catch was dominated by featherwing beetles (Ptiliidae) (over 40 000 individuals) among which &lt;em&gt;Acrotrichis insularis&lt;/em&gt; (Mäklin, 1852) was by far the most numerous species. Staphylinidae comprised the second most individual-rich family (6.5%), whereas all other families together comprised less than 4% of the catch. Calculations of height - abundance distributions revealed that many beetles fly above the forest canopy. Our observations of density - height distributions in combination with the long species list suggest that a large segment of the forest beetle fauna is under constant flux.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
				
												
									<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
				
								<rights>Copyright (c) 2021 Entomologisk Tidskrift</rights>
			</entry>
					<entry>
								<id>http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/87</id>
				<title>Föreningsinformation</title>
				<updated>2021-07-15T07:29:32+00:00</updated>

				
									<author>
						<name>Emma Wahlberg</name>
													<email>ellentwofourtwo@gmail.com</email>
											</author>
								<link rel="alternate" href="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/87" />

									<summary type="html" xml:base="http://et-online.nu/index.php/contents/article/view/87">&lt;p&gt;Sveriges entomologiska förening (SEF) är en riksorganisation för entomologiska föreningar i Sverige. Medlemmar i SEF är de&amp;nbsp; föreningar som presenteras nedan. SEF har som uppgift att ge ut Entomologisk Tidskrift och att stimulera intresset för entomologi i Sverige, bland annat genom att stödja bildandet av insektsföreningar i nya områden.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
				
												
									<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
				
								<rights>Copyright (c) 2021 Entomologisk Tidskrift</rights>
			</entry>
			</feed>
