
<rss version="0.91">
    <channel>
        <title>Latest Articles from ZooKeys</title>
        <description>Latest 100 Articles from ZooKeys</description>
        <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 23:32:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Pensoft FeedCreator</generator>
        <image>
            <url>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/i/logo.jpg</url>
            <title>Latest Articles from ZooKeys</title>
            <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Feed provided by https://zookeys.pensoft.net/. Click to visit.]]></description>
        </image>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomy of the Proisotoma complex. VI. Rediscovery of the genus Bagnallella Salmon, 1951 and epitoky in Bagnallella davidi (Barra, 2001), comb. nov. from South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 185-204</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.71307</p>
					<p>Authors: Mikhail Potapov, Louis Deharveng, Charlene Janion-Scheepers</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Bagnallella Salmon is restored and given a diagnosis. It takes an intermediate position between Proisotoma Börner and Cryptopygus Willem complexes and is characterized by the separation of the two last abdominal segments (like in Proisotoma) and 3 and 5 s-chaetae on the fourth and fifth abdominal segments (like in Cryptopygus and its allies). A list of and key to species belonging to Bagnallella is given. Bagnallella biseta comb. nov., B. dubia comb. nov., B. sedecimoculata comb. nov., and B. tenella comb. nov. are commented and redescribed. Morphology of Bagnallella davidi (Barra), comb. nov. is described from the specimens from South Africa. So far B. davidi appears to be a complex of forms differing in size of the furca and macrochaetae. Two types of strongly modified males were found and described. Antennae, ventral side of abdomen, posterior edge of abdominal tergites, and mandibles are affected with epitoky. The nature of the discovered strong polymorphism is unclear.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71307/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 16:04:11 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On two new species of deep-sea carrier crabs (Crustacea, Brachyura, Homolodromiidae, Dicranodromia) from Taiwan and the Philippines, with notes on other Indo-West Pacific species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 129-165</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.72978</p>
					<p>Authors: Peter K. L. Ng, Chien-Hui Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The systematics of four species of the homolodromiid genus Dicranodromia A. Milne-Edwards, 1880, from East Asia and the Philippines is reappraised: D. danielae Ng &amp; McLay, 2005, D. doederleini Ortmann, 1892, D. karubar Guinot, 1993, and D. martini Guinot, 1995; and key characters such as the epistome, gonopods, and spermatheca are figured in detail. Two new species, D. erinaceus sp. nov. and D. robusta sp. nov., are described from Taiwan and the Philippines, respectively. Dicranodromia erinaceus sp. nov. resembles D. spinulata Guinot, 1995, and D. delli Ahyong, 2008 (from New Caledonia and New Zealand) but can be separated by its distinctly spinulated carapace surfaces and proportionately shorter fifth ambulatory legs. Dicranodromia robusta sp. nov. is superficially similar to D. baffini (Alcock &amp; Anderson, 1899) and D. karubar Guinot, 1993, but can easily be separated by possessing a broad dorsoventrally flattened infraorbital tooth. A genetic study of the species using the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase I gene confirms that the taxa are distinct, with D. erinaceus sp. nov. coming out in a well-supported clade from congeners. The megalopa of D. doederleini is also reported for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72978/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 14:23:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Transcriptional identification of genes light-interacting in the extraretinal photoreceptors of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 107-127</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.73075</p>
					<p>Authors: Gabina Calderón-Rosete, Juan Antonio González-Barrios, Celia Piña-Leyva, Hayde Nallely Moreno-Sandoval, Manuel Lara-Lozano, Leonardo Rodríguez-Sosa</p>
					<p>Abstract: Crayfish serve as a model for studying the effect of environmental lighting on locomotor activity and neuroendocrine functions. The effects of light on this organism are mediated differentially by retinal and extraretinal photoreceptors located in the cerebroid ganglion and the pleonal nerve cord. However, some molecular aspects of the phototransduction cascade in the pleonal extraretinal photoreceptors remain unknown. In this study, transcriptome data from the pleonal nerve cord of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii (Girard,1852) were analyzed to identify transcripts that potentially interact with phototransduction process. The Illumina MiSeq System and the pipeline Phylogenetically Informed Annotation (PIA) were employed, which places uncharacterized genes into pre-calculated phylogenies of gene families. Here, for the first time 62 transcripts identified from the pleonal nerve cord that are related to light-interacting pathways are reported; they can be classified into the following 11 sets: 1) retinoid pathway in vertebrates and invertebrates, 2) photoreceptor specification, 3) rhabdomeric phototransduction, 4) opsins 5) ciliary phototransduction, 6) melanin synthesis, 7) pterin synthesis, 8) ommochrome synthesis, 9) heme synthesis, 10) diurnal clock, and 11) crystallins. Moreover, this analysis comparing the sequences located on the pleonal nerve cord to eyestalk sequences reported in other studies reveals 94–100% similarity between the 55 common proteins identified. These results show that both retinal and pleonal non-visual photoreceptors in the crayfish equally expressed the transcripts involved in light detection. Moreover, they suggest that the genes related to ocular and extraocular light perception in the crayfish P. clarkii use biosynthesis pathways and phototransduction cascades commons.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73075/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:58:55 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Tylototriton (Urodela, Salamandridae) from western Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 83-105</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.75320</p>
					<p>Authors: Porrawee Pomchote, Parada Peerachidacho, Axel Hernandez, Pitak Sapewisut, Wichase Khonsue, Panupong Thammachoti, Kanto Nishikawa</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe a new species of the newt genus Tylototriton from Umphang Wildlife Sanctuary, Tak Province, western Thailand based on molecular and morphological evidence and named here as Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. The new species is assigned to the subgenus Tylototriton and differs from other species in having dark-brown to blackish-brown body and limbs, truncate snout, prominent antero-medial ends of the expansion of the dentary bones, laterally protruding quadrate regions, indistinct and small rib nodules, a well-segmented vertebral ridge, and rough dorsolateral bony ridges, which are steeper anterior, and curved medially at the posterior ends. The molecular data show that Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. differs from T. uyenoi sensu stricto by a 5% genetic sequence divergence of the mitochondrial NADH dehydrogenase subunit 2 region gene. The new species and T. uyenoi are both endemic to Thailand, distributed along the Northwest Thai (Dawna) Uplands of Indochina. To clarify the species boundary between Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. and T. uyenoi, additional field research is needed in adjacent areas. Tylototriton umphangensis sp. nov. is restricted to evergreen hill forests in Umphang Wildlife Sanctuary. We suggest that the new species should be classified as Endangered (EN) in the IUCN Red List.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75320/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:58:15 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Nine new species of the spider family Araneidae (Arachnida, Araneae) from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 49-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.73345</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiaoqi Mi, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Nine new species of the orb-weaver spider family Araneidae Clerck, 1757 from Menglun Town, Xishuangbanna, Yunnan, China are described: Acusilas tongi sp. nov. (♂♀), Chorizopes yui sp. nov. (♂♀), Chorizopesoides guoi sp. nov. (♂♀), Deione cheni sp. nov. (♀), D. yangi sp. nov. (♂♀), Hypsosinga pulla sp. nov. (♂♀), Mangora baii sp. nov. (♂♀), M. cephala sp. nov. (♂♀) and Milonia gemella sp. nov. (♂♀). The genus Milonia Thorell, 1890 is recorded from China for the first time. The previous description of Chorizopesoides wulingensis (Yin, Wang &amp; Xie, 1994) from Libo County, Guizhou by Mi and Wang (2018) refers to Chorizopesoides annasestakovae sp. nov. (♂♀). Diagnostic photos of the habitus and copulatory organs of the new species are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73345/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:55:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic study on fourteen symphytognathid species from Asia (Araneae, Symphytognathidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1072: 1-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1072.67935</p>
					<p>Authors: Ya Li, Shuqiang Li, Yucheng Lin</p>
					<p>Abstract: Fourteen symphytognathid species belonging to three genera are examined, including the descriptions of eight new species and two new genera from China, Vietnam, Thailand and Myanmar: Patu Marples, 1951: P. catba S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂, Vietnam), P. dakou S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China), P. damtao S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂, Vietnam), P. jiangzhou S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♀, China), P. jidanweishi Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♂♀, China), P. nagarat S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, Thailand), P. nigeri Lin &amp; S. Li, 2009 (♀, China), P. putao S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♀, Myanmar), P. qiqi Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♀, China) and P. xiaoxiao Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009 (♂♀, China); Kirinua S. Li &amp; Lin, gen. nov.: K. maguai S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China) and K. yangshuo S. Li &amp; Lin, sp. nov. (♂♀, China); Swilda S. Li &amp; Lin, gen. nov.: S. longtou (Miller, Griswold &amp; Yin, 2009), comb. nov. (♂♀, China) is transferred from Crassignatha Wunderlich, 1995 and S. spinathoraxi (Lin &amp; S. Li, 2009), comb. nov. (♂♀, China) is transferred from Patu. Diagnoses, descriptions and illustrations are provided for new taxa, as well as a distribution map. The males of P. xiaoxiao and S. longtou are described for the first time. Type specimens of P. jidanweishi, P. nigeri, P. qiqi, P. xiaoxiao, S. longtou and S. spinathoraxi are re-examined and photographed. All Asian Patu species are revised and two species, P. kishidai Shinkai, 2009 and P. bispina Lin, Pham &amp; S. Li, 2009, are transferred to Crassignatha and proposed as new combinations: Crassignatha kishidai comb. nov. and C. bispina comb. nov. In addition, DNA barcodes and genetic distances of ten species treated in this paper were obtained to confirm identification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67935/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 08:54:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New genetic data reveals a new species of Zospeum in Bosnia (Gastropoda, Ellobioidea, Carychiinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 175-193</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.66417</p>
					<p>Authors: Thomas Inäbnit, Adrienne Jochum, Raijko Slapnik, Eike Neubert</p>
					<p>Abstract: Recent integrative investigations of the terrestrial ellobiid genus, Zospeum, have revealed significant findings concerning its Alpine-Dinaric evolution and taxonomy. Due to the expected discrepancy between the useful, but limited, 1970s’ classification system based on shell data and the results of recent genetic analyses in the latest investigation, a revision of the entire radiation was undertaken, and a new classification system was devised by the present authors in an earlier paper. Concurrent to this work, molecular sequences from two Austrian caves were published independently of our revision by another research group. By incorporating these genetic data within our phylogenetic framework here, we show that the Austrian individuals are genetically most similar to Zospeum amoenum and consequently, classify them within that species. We additionally reveal two new genetic lineages from the largely under-sampled southern extension of Zospeum’s known distributional range. The first lineage, deriving from the region of Dubrovnik, Croatia, is a potential candidate for genetically clarifying Zospeum troglobalcanicum. The second lineage derives from the municipality of Tomislavgrad, Bosnia-Herzegovina and is herein, described a new species: Zospeum simplex Inäbnit, Jochum &amp; Neubert, sp. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66417/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:51:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Hexatoma (Eriocera) Macquart (Diptera, Limoniidae) from Xizang, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 155-173</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.66750</p>
					<p>Authors: Bing Zhang, Qicheng Yang, Yan Li, Ding Yang</p>
					<p>Abstract: One new species of the subgenus Eriocera Macquart,1838, Hexatoma (Eriocera) xizangensis sp. nov. is described and illustrated from Xizang, China. The following four species are re-described and reported from Xizang for the first time: H. (E.) latigrisea Alexander, 1971, H. (E.) nepalensis (Westwood, 1836), H. (E.) paragnava Alexander, 1973 and H. (E.) perhirsuta Alexander, 1973. A key to the species of Eriocera from Xizang is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66750/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:03:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Contribution to the knowledge of the genus Takobia Novikova &amp; Kluge, 1987 (Ephemeroptera, Baetidae) in Central Asia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 127-154</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.71582</p>
					<p>Authors: Pavel Sroka, Zohar Yanai, Dmitry Palatov, Jean-Luc Gattolliat</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on the original type material, the nymphal stage of the mayfly Takobia maxillare is redescribed; in parallel, a lectotype is designated. Takobia maxillare is the type species of the genus Takobia, and an accurate and complete knowledge of its morphology is crucial to the delimitation of this problematic genus and clarification of its phylogenetic affinities. Ambiguous characters, previously reported for this species in the literature are clarified. Furthermore, two new species in the same genus are described, namely Takobia sinusopalpata sp. nov. and Takobia shughnonica sp. nov. based on the morphology of nymphs from Central Asia, supplemented with COI sequences. Implications for the systematics of Takobia and related taxa are discussed and the need for an extensive phylogenetic study of this group is stressed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71582/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 07:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Helen’s twins in the Balkans: discovery of two new Paraptychoptera Tonnoir, 1919 species closely related to P. helena Peus, 1958, with systematic revision of the “lacustris” group (Diptera, Ptychopteridae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 63-81</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.58598</p>
					<p>Authors: Lujza Keresztes, Jürgen Kappert, Mária Henning, Edina Török</p>
					<p>Abstract: Ptychoptera castor Keresztes &amp; Kappert, sp. nov. and P. pollux Keresztes &amp; Török, sp. nov. both belong to the subgenus Ptychoptera (Paraptychoptera) Tonnoir (1919) and are described from boggy headwaters in the south Balkan area. These new species are closely related to the range-restricted P. helena Peus, 1958, which is known only from Oiti village, Mount Oeta, Phthioitis region, Greece and, together with P. lacustris, forms a morphologically well-defined unit in the subgenus Paraptychoptera. Based on cladistic analyses of 53 different morphological characters using the male antenna, wing, and genital structures, a general revision of the “lacustris” group is proposed with a dichotomous key of Paraptychoptera species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58598/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:20:26 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Another Laurasian connection in the Early Eocene of India: Myrmecarchaea spiders (Araneae, Archaeidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 49-61</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72515</p>
					<p>Authors: Hannah M. Wood, Hukam Singh, David A. Grimaldi</p>
					<p>Abstract: The first fossil Archaeidae in Cambay amber from India, of Eocene age, is documented. The inclusion is a spider exuvium and is placed as Myrmecarchaea based on the presence of elongated legs, a slightly elongated pedicel with lateral spurs, and a diastema between coxae III and IV that is similar to M. antecessor from Oise amber. The previous occurrences of the genus are from Baltic and Oise amber, both of Eocene age. Because most spiders, including Archaeidae, only molt as juveniles, the exuvium does not have adult features nor have distinct species-specific features, and a new taxon is not erected. This new record further extends the distribution of the family and genus to India 50–52 million years ago. Myrmecarchaea in Indian Cambay amber provides additional evidence that India in the Early Eocene had affinities with the Palearctic mainland rather than showing Gondwanan insularity.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72515/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Morphological and molecular identification of arrhenotokous strain of Diglyphus wani (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) found in China as a control agent against agromyzid leafminers</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 109-126</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72433</p>
					<p>Authors: Su-Jie Du, Zoya Yefremova, Fu-Yu Ye, Chao-Dong Zhu, Jian-Yang Guo, Wan-Xue Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Diglyphus species are ecologically and economically important on agromyzid leafminers. In 2018, a thelytokous species, Diglyphus wani Liu, Zhu &amp; Yefremova, was firstly reported and described. Subsequently, the arrhenotokous D. wani were discovered in Yunnan and Guizhou Provinces of China. We compared the morphological characteristics of thelytokous and arrhenotokous strains. However, the females of two strains had a strongly similar morphology and showed subtle differences in fore- and hind-wings. The difference was that forewing of arrhenotokous female was with denser setae overall, showing that costal cell with 2 ~ 4 rows of setae on dorsal surface and the setae of basal cell with 15 ~ 21 hairs and forewing of thelytokous female was with two rows of setae on dorsal surface and basal cell with 10 ~ 15 hairs generally. The setation beneath the marginal vein of the hind-wing of arrhenotokous female is denser than the same area of thelytokous female. To explore the genetic divergence between thelytokous and arrhenotokous strains of D. wani, the mitochondrial and nuclear gene were applied and sequenced. The polygenic analyses revealed that two strains can be distinguished by COI, ITS1 and ITS2. The mean sequence divergence between the two strains was 0.052, 0.010 and 0.007, respectively. Nevertheless, the 28S gene was unfeasible due to its containing a sharing haplotype between different strains. The two strains of D. wani are dominant parasitoids against agromyzid leafminers and such effective discernible foundation provides future in-depth studies on biological characteristics, along with insight into field application of two strains of D. wani.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72433/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 10:59:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Out of Xanthopygus (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae): escape from polyphyly</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 83-107</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.75947</p>
					<p>Authors: Stylianos Chatzimanolis</p>
					<p>Abstract: Xanthopygus as currently defined is the largest genus in the subtribe Xanthopygina (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Staphylininae) with 40 described species. However, the genus is poorly defined, morphologically heterogeneous and previous studies have questioned whether it is a natural group. A morphological (51 characters) Bayesian phylogenetic analysis was performed to test whether Xanthopygus is a monophyletic group. The analysis indicated that Xanthopygus was polyphyletic, and therefore species were split into four different genera. Xanthopygus nigricornis Scheerpeltz was transferred to Oligotergus as Oligotergus nigricornis comb. nov. and Xanthopygus skalitzkyi (Bernhauer) was transferred to Styngetus as Styngetus skalitzkyi comb. nov. A new genus, Photinopygus gen. nov. was erected to accommodate the majority of the species previously in Xanthopygus and Xanthopygus sensu novo is used in a new restricted sense to accommodate the remaining species. Diagnostic features are provided to distinguish species in the genera Photinopygus and Xanthopygus from each other and all other Xanthopygina genera.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75947/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 09:56:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Diagnosing diagnoses – can we improve our taxonomy?</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 43-48</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.72904</p>
					<p>Authors: Art Borkent</p>
					<p>Abstract: Taxonomic diagnoses should be clear but minimal statements that precisely distinguish a given specimen from other taxa at the same stage of development (e.g., pupa, adult female, egg). Presently, most diagnoses are of uncertain value. It is a great advantage for readers to be able to simply and confidently confirm their identifications after using a key.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72904/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Commentary</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 15:37:36 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A review of tangle-veined flies (Nemestrinidae, Diptera) in Egypt</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 11-42</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.70743</p>
					<p>Authors: Arafa Elsayed El-Hashash, Haitham Badrawy Mousa Badrawy, Ayman Mohyie-Eldin Ibrahim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Egyptian fauna of the genus Nemestrinus Latreille, 1802 is revised. In 1967, Steyskal and El-Bialy listed 12 species from the region, but only six species are now recognized. The primary type specimens of the species N. aegyptiacus (Wiedemann, 1828), N. rufipes (Olivier, 1810), and N. lateralis Wiedemann, 1828 (N. lateralis being a synonym of N. rufipes) deposited in the Museum für Naturkunde, Berlin, Germany were examined. Two species (N. abdominalis Olivier, 1811 and N. fascifrons (Bigot, 1888) are placed as new synonyms of N. ater (Olivier, 1811), and N. ruficornis Macquart, 1840 is synonymized with N. rufipes (Olivier, 1811). Nemestrinus jullieni (Efflatoun, 1925) is confirmed as a synonym of N. aegyptiacus. Furthermore, three species (N. caucasicus Fischer, 1806, N. pallipes (Olivier, 1811), and N. persicus Lichtwardt, 1909) have been removed and are doubtful records from Egypt. A key to the species, lists of specimens examined, and Illustrations and distributions for each species are provided. The status of species of doubtful occurrence in Egypt is discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70743/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:14:56 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First report of Eutrichosomella Girault (Hymenoptera, Aphelinidae) from China, with description of a new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1071: 1-9</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1071.71909</p>
					<p>Authors: Ye Chen, Hai-feng Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Eutrichosomella Girault is recorded for the first time from China (Yunnan Province), and Eutrichosomella yunnanensis sp. nov. (♀, ♂) is described and illustrated. A distribution map of this genus is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71909/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 08:00:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of the genus Spio (Annelida, Spionidae) from the southern and western coasts of Korea</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 151-164</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73847</p>
					<p>Authors: Geon Hyeok Lee, Karin Meißner, Seong Myeong Yoon, Gi-Sik Min</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new spionid polychaete, Spio pigmentata sp. nov., is described from the southern and western coasts of Korea. This new species differs from its congeners by the combination of the following morphological characteristics: the presence of orange-brown pigmentation on the anterior part of the prostomium, black pigmentation on the peristomium and along the body, U-shaped nuchal organs, a comparatively long extension of metameric dorsal ciliated organs, three pairs of white dots per chaetiger, two to three posterior abranchiate chaetigers, and the presence of tridentate neuropodial hooded hooks. The partial 16S ribosomal DNA (rDNA) and nuclear 18S rDNA sequences of the new species and Spio sp. 2 reported by Abe and Sato-Okoshi (2021) from Japan showed high similarity, indicating that these two specimens belong to the same species. A detailed description and illustrations of the new species, together with molecular information, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73847/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:39:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Mitogenomics of historical type specimens clarifies the taxonomy of Ethiopian Ptychadena Boulenger, 1917 (Anura, Ptychadenidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 135-149</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.66598</p>
					<p>Authors: Jacobo Reyes-Velasco, Sandra Goutte, Xenia Freilich, Stéphane Boissinot</p>
					<p>Abstract: The taxonomy of the Ptychadena neumanni species complex, a radiation of grass frogs inhabiting the Ethiopian highlands, has puzzled scientists for decades because of the morphological resemblance among its members. Whilst molecular phylogenetic methods allowed the discovery of several species in recent years, assigning pre-existing and new names to clades was challenged by the unavailability of molecular data for century-old type specimens. We used Illumina short reads to sequence the mitochondrial DNA of type specimens in this group, as well as ddRAD-seq analyses to resolve taxonomic uncertainties surrounding the P. neumanni species complex. The phylogenetic reconstruction revealed recurrent confusion between Ptychadena erlangeri (Ahl, 1924) and P. neumanni (Ahl, 1924) in the literature. The phylogeny also established that P. largeni Perret, 1994 represents a junior synonym of P. erlangeri (Ahl, 1924) and distinguished between two small species, P. nana Perret, 1994, restricted to the Arussi Plateau, and P. robeensis Goutte, Reyes-Velasco, Freilich, Kassie &amp; Boissinot, 2021, which inhabits the Bale Mountains. The phylogenetic analyses of mitochondrial DNA from type specimens also corroborate the validity of seven recently described species within the group. Our study shows how modern molecular tools applied to historical type specimens can help resolve long-standing taxonomic issues in cryptic species complexes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66598/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 13:42:50 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 (Diptera, Ptychopteridae) from Zhejiang, China with an updated key to Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 87-99</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.67779</p>
					<p>Authors: Jiaqi Shao, Zehui Kang</p>
					<p>Abstract: We revise the taxonomy of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 from Zhejiang, East China. One new species from Zhejiang, P. tianmushana sp. nov., is described and illustrated. Morphologically, the new species is most similar to P. emeica Kang, Xue &amp; Zhang, 2019 and P. formosensis Alexander, 1924, but it can be distinguished by the coloration of the abdomen and the details of the male genitalia. In addition, P. bellula Alexander, 1937 is recorded from Zhejiang for the first time. Two known species from Zhejiang, P. longwangshana Yang &amp; Chen, 1998 and P. gutianshana Yang &amp; Chen, 1995, are redescribed and illustrated. A key to Chinese species of Ptychoptera is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67779/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:06:35 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 (Diptera, Ptychopteridae) from Yunnan, China with remarks on the distribution of Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 73-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.58859</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao Zhang, Zehui Kang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sixteen known species of the genus Ptychoptera Meigen, 1803 have been recorded from China, of which three occur in Yunnan Province. Herein, two new species from Yunnan, P. cordata sp. nov. and P. yunnanica sp. nov., are described from China. An updated key to Ptychoptera is presented for all Chinese species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58859/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:05:48 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Neohagenulus Traver, 1938 from Hispaniola (Ephemeroptera, Leptophlebiidae, Hagenulinae, Hagenulini)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 41-50</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73484</p>
					<p>Authors: Michel Sartori</p>
					<p>Abstract: Here, I report a new species of the genus Neohagenulus Traver, 1938 from the Dominican Republic. The genus was believed to be endemic to Puerto Rico until now. Neohagenulus hodeceki sp. nov. is described at the nymphal stage. Some discussion on the tribe Hagenulini is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73484/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 19:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Hylcalosia Fischer (Hymenoptera: Braconidae: Alysiinae) from South Korea, with a key to the Korean species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 31-40</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73377</p>
					<p>Authors: Ju-Hyeong Sohn, Cornelis van Achterberg, Yunjong Han, Hyojoong Kim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The species of the genus Hylcalosia Fischer, 1967 (Braconidae: Alysiinae) from South Korea are revised. One species, Hylcalosia bicolor sp. nov., is new to science. They are described and illustrated herein and an identification key to the Korean species is added. In addition, the DNA barcode region of the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI) has been analysed for the new species and H. sutchanica is used for genetic comparison.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73377/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Characterization of the complete mitochondrial genome of Myrmus lateralis (Heteroptera, Rhopalidae) and its implication for phylogenetic analyses</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 13-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.72742</p>
					<p>Authors: Wanqing Zhao, Dajun Liu, Qian Jia, Xin Wu, Hufang Zhang</p>
					<p>Abstract: Mitochondrial genomes (mitogenomes) are widely used in research studies on phylogenetic relationships and evolutionary history. Here, we sequenced and analyzed the mitogenome of the scentless plant bug Myrmus lateralis Hsiao, 1964 (Heteroptera, Rhopalidae). The complete 17,309 bp genome encoded 37 genes, including 13 protein-coding genes (PCGs), 22 transfer RNA (tRNA) genes, two ribosomal RNA (rRNA) genes, and a control region. The mitogenome revealed a high A+T content (75.8%), a positive AT-skew (0.092), and a negative GC-skew (–0.165). All 13 PCGs were found to start with ATN codons, except for cox1, in which TTG was the start codon. The Ka/Ks ratios of 13 PCGs were all lower than 1, indicating that purifying selection evolved in these genes. All tRNAs could be folded into the typical cloverleaf secondary structure, except for trnS1 and trnV, which lack dihydrouridine arms. Phylogenetic trees were constructed and analyzed based on the PCG+rRNA from 38 mitogenomes, using maximum likelihood and Bayesian inference methods, showed that M. lateralis and Chorosoma macilentum Stål, 1858 grouped together in the tribe Chorosomatini. In addition, Coreoidea and Pyrrhocoroidea were sister groups among the superfamilies of Trichophora, and Rhopalidae was a sister group to Alydidae + Coreidae.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72742/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:34:59 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Effect of climate change on the potential distribution of Heloderma alvarezi (Squamata, Helodermatidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.69186</p>
					<p>Authors: Aarón Gómez-Cruz, Nancy G. Santos-Hernández, José Alberto Cruz, Daniel Ariano-Sánchez, Christian Ruiz-Castillejos, Eduardo E. Espinoza-Medinilla, José A. De Fuentes-Vicente</p>
					<p>Abstract: Climate change represents a real threat to biodiversity conservation worldwide. Although the effects on several species of conservation priority are known, comprehensive information about the impact of climate change on reptile populations is lacking. In the present study, we analyze outcomes on the potential distribution of the black beaded lizard (Heloderma alvarezi Bogert &amp; Martin del Campo, 1956) under global warming scenarios. Its potential distribution, at present and in projections for the years 2050 and 2070, under both optimistic and pessimistic climate change forecasts, were computed using current data records and seven bioclimatic variables. General results predict a shift in the future potential distribution of H. alvarezi due to temperature increase. The optimistic scenario (4.5 W/m2) for 2070 suggests an enlargement in the species’ distribution as a response to the availability of new areas of suitable habitat. On the contrary, the worst-case scenario (7 W/m2) shows a distribution decrease by 65%. Moreover, the range distribution of H. alvarezi is directly related to the human footprint, which consequently could magnify negative outcomes for this species. Our research elucidates the importance of conservation strategies to prevent the extinction of the black beaded lizard, especially considering that this species is highly threatened by aversive hunting.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69186/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:34:14 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Byrrhinus Motschulsky, 1858 (Coleoptera, Limnichidae, Limnichinae) from Negros, Philippines</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 51-72</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.70531</p>
					<p>Authors: Emmanuel D. Delocado, Hendrik Freitag</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Limnichidae beetles, Byrrhinus negrosensis sp. nov. and Byrrhinus villarini sp. nov., are described from the Island of Negros in the Philippines. The adult specimens of the new species can be differentiated by patterns of body punctation, colour and orientation of elytral pubescence, posterolateral angle of pronotum, tarsomere length ratio and aedeagal form. Two clades, representing the two new species, were retrieved in the Maximum Likelihood gene tree using the 3’-end of the COI gene. Maximum genetic divergence within B. negrosensis sp. nov. and B. villarini sp. nov. were recorded to be 2.3% and 1.3%, respectively, while the mean interspecific divergence between the two new species was 19.7%. Morphological descriptions, digital photographs and COI sequences were provided for the two species. The state of knowledge of Byrrhinus is reviewed and an updated Philippine checklist is provided. By coupling morphological and molecular data, this paper provides the first additional new species of Philippine Byrrhinus in the last 28 years.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70531/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:47:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An annotated checklist of the eukaryotic parasites of humans, exclusive of fungi and algae</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1069: 1-313</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1069.67403</p>
					<p>Authors: Blaine A. Mathison, Sarah G. H. Sapp</p>
					<p>Abstract: The classification of “parasites” in the medical field is a challenging notion, a group which historically has included all eukaryotes exclusive of fungi that invade and derive resources from the human host. Since antiquity, humans have been identifying and documenting parasitic infections, and this collective catalog of parasitic agents has expanded considerably with technology. As our understanding of species boundaries and the use of molecular tools has evolved, so has our concept of the taxonomy of human parasites. Consequently, new species have been recognized while others have been relegated to synonyms. On the other hand, the decline of expertise in classical parasitology and limited curricula have led to a loss of awareness of many rarely encountered species. Here, we provide a comprehensive checklist of all reported eukaryotic organisms (excluding fungi and allied taxa) parasitizing humans resulting in 274 genus-group taxa and 848 species-group taxa. For each species, or genus where indicated, a concise summary of geographic distribution, natural hosts, route of transmission and site within human host, and vectored pathogens are presented. Ubiquitous, human-adapted species as well as very rare, incidental zoonotic organisms are discussed in this annotated checklist. We also provide a list of 79 excluded genera and species that have been previously reported as human parasites but are not believed to be true human parasites or represent misidentifications or taxonomic changes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67403/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 9 Nov 2021 15:08:25 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The first fossil Coleoptera record from the Volyn Region, Ukraine, with description of a new Glesoconomorphus (Coleoptera, Mycteridae) in syninclusion with Winterschmidtiidae (Acari) and a key to species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 189-201</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.75391</p>
					<p>Authors: Dmitry Telnov, Evgeny E. Perkovsky, Dmitry V. Vasilenko, Shûhei Yamamoto</p>
					<p>Abstract: Glesoconomorphus ekaterinae sp. nov. (Coleoptera, Mycteridae), representing the first ever fossil species of Coleoptera from the Volyn Region of Ukraine and the first mycterid from late Eocene Rovno amber, is described and illustrated. A key to species of the fossil mycterid genus Glesoconomorphus Alekseev, Pollock &amp; Bukejs, 2019 is presented. The systematic position of Glesoconomorphus within Eurypinae J. Thomson, 1860 is briefly discussed. The oldest finding of phoretic Winterschmidtiidae Oudemans, 1923 mites, found on the type specimen of the new beetle species, is reported.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/75391/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 13:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Additions to the cuckoo wasps (Hymenoptera, Chrysididae) of Mongolia, with description of eleven new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 149-187</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.73549</p>
					<p>Authors: Paolo Rosa, Maxim Yu. Proshchalykin, Marek Halada</p>
					<p>Abstract: An addendum to the recent checklist of the Chrysididae from Mongolia is given. Examination of old museum material and recently collected specimens has led to the discovery of eight new records for the country and eleven new species for science. Eight species are newly recorded from Mongolia: Chrysis inclinata Linsenmaier, 1959, C. martinella du Buysson, 1900, C. speciosa Radoszkowski, 1877, Euchroeus purpuratus (Fabricius, 1787), Holopyga lucida (Lepeletier, 1806), H. similis Mocsáry, 1889, Hedychridium femoratum (Dahlbom, 1854) and H. leleji Rosa, 2017. Two species, Hedychridium cupreum (Dahlbom, 1845) and H. propodeale Rosa, 2017 are excluded from the checklist of Mongolian Chrysididae: the former is described here as H. erythrosoma sp. nov., the latter is identified as H. leleji Rosa, 2017. The hitherto unknown male of Chrysis mocsaryi Radoszkowski, 1889 is described and illustrated. Eleven new species are described: Chrysis strakai sp. nov., C. woodi sp. nov., Hedychridium erythrosoma sp. nov., H. frontale sp. nov., H. jacobsi sp. nov., H. splendens sp. nov., H. striatum sp. nov., H. varvarae sp. nov., H. weii sp. nov., Holopyga tyrneri sp. nov., and Philoctetes boreki sp. nov. Keys to males and females of all known Mongolian species of Hedychridium Abeille de Perrin, 1878 are provided. The Mongolian cuckoo wasp fauna now comprises 107 species in 18 genera and two subfamilies.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73549/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 8 Nov 2021 13:08:01 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A checklist of Mantodea of Belize, with a regional key to species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 51-71</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.58193</p>
					<p>Authors: Lohitashwa Garikipati, Jason E. Bond</p>
					<p>Abstract: The list of known Mantodea in Belize is updated, with notes of 12 new country records, bringing the total known species of Mantodea in Belize to 21. Further information on habitat and microhabitat observations are included. A regional dichotomous key and Lucid interactive key are provided to known species in Belize. A list of other possibly endemic species is provided. Remarks on the merit of further sampling efforts in central America are made, based on recent studies. Our findings suggest that our understanding of Central American Mantodean diversity could be vastly improved by further documentation.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/58193/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 18:28:06 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the genus Cenophengus LeConte, 1881 (Coleoptera, Phengodidae), with the description of four new species, new geographic records and a new synonymy</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 73-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70295</p>
					<p>Authors: Viridiana Vega-Badillo, Juan J. Morrone, Santiago Zaragoza-Caballero</p>
					<p>Abstract: A taxonomic revision of the genus Cenophengus LeConte, 1881 (Coleoptera: Phengodidae) is provided, including new data on geographic ranges of the species. This is the first time this genus has been recorded for Belize and in Honduras. Four new species (C. gardunoi, C. saasil, C. tsiik and C. zuritai) are described and a new synonymy (C. guerrerensis, Zaragoza-Caballero, 1991 = C. major Wittmer, 1976) is established. The study includes a key to the 30 valid species, diagnoses, descriptions, photographs and distribution maps.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70295/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 08:53:52 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Four new species of the jumping spider genus Portia (Araneae, Salticidae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 27-40</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.72805</p>
					<p>Authors: Xin Xu, Xianjin Peng, Daiqin Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: We diagnose and describe four new species of Portia Karsch, 1878 and describe for the first time the male of P. zhaoi Peng, Li &amp; Chen, 2003 from China based on morphological characters. The females of Portia bawang sp. nov. have the narrowest epigyne orifice. The males of Portia erlangping sp. nov. have the shortest embolus among all the species. The females of Portia fajing sp. nov. can be distinguished from other species by the anterior orifice margin, which is nearly parallel to the posterior orifice margin. The males of Portia xishan sp. nov. can be identified by the tegular furrow which extends to form a membrane and by the tegular apophysis which is obscured; the females of Portia xishan sp. nov. can be diagnosed by the slit-like epigynal orifice. The males of P. zhaoi have the longest embolus among all the species, and females can be diagnosed by the circular epigyne orifice and the longest copulatory ducts. To facilitate future identification, we also provide the GenBank accession codes of the DNA barcode gene, Cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI), for all the type specimens.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72805/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 3 Nov 2021 13:46:21 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Elachista Treitschke, 1833 (Lepidoptera, Elachistidae, Elachistinae) from China, with identification keys to the Asian species of the Elachista saccharella species group</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 41-50</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70807</p>
					<p>Authors: Virginijus Sruoga</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Elachista olekarsholti sp. nov., is described from Henan, China. The habitus and male genitalia are diagnosed and illustrated in detail. This is the first record of the Elachista saccharella species group in China. Identification keys to the Asian species of Elachista saccharella species group, based on male and female genitalia, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70807/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 3 Nov 2021 13:45:40 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Epeorus (Caucasiron) (Ephemeroptera, Heptageniidae) from Azerbaijan and Iran</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 13-26</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.70717</p>
					<p>Authors: Ľuboš Hrivniak, Pavel Sroka, Jindriska Bojkova, Roman J. Godunko, Peter Manko</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species, Epeorus (Caucasiron) hyrcanicus sp. nov., is described based on larval morphology and molecular data (COI) containing sequences from all Caucasian Caucasiron species described to date. The species is distributed in the Hyrcanian forest of southeastern Azerbaijan and northwestern Iran. Based on our wide-range sampling, the new species is likely endemic to this area. The most pronounced larval morphological diagnostic characters are the coloration pattern of abdominal sterna (a pair of oblique stripes and stripe-like medio-lateral maculae) and terga (triangular medial maculae), poorly developed projection of the costal margin of gill plates III, presence of hair-like setae on the surface of abdominal terga, and relatively wide shape of gill plates VII (in natural position from ventral view). The diagnostic characters are compared to related species, and primary information to habitat is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70717/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 2 Nov 2021 13:16:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species and a new species record of Orbiniidae Hartman, 1942 (Annelida, Polychaeta) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1068: 1-11</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1068.71925</p>
					<p>Authors: Yue Sun, Lei Yu, Xinzheng Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the orbiniid genus Phylo Kinberg, 1866, P. heterochaetus sp. nov., is described based on material collected from the northern Yellow Sea, China. This is the thirteenth species in Phylo. The new species can be easily identified by the combination of the following characters: anterior thorax with 13 chaetigers, interramal cirri absent, anterior thoracic neuropodia with 4 or 5 rows of uncini, intermixed with a few subuluncini in the first 1 or 2 rows, and a ventral fringe of numerous stomach papillae present on chaetigers 12–24. Phylo fimbriata is recorded for the first time from China seas.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71925/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 2 Nov 2021 09:36:18 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New species of Labiobaetis Novikova &amp; Kluge from Southeast Asia and New Guinea (Ephemeroptera, Baetidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 159-208</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72251</p>
					<p>Authors: Thomas Kaltenbach, Jean-Luc Gattolliat</p>
					<p>Abstract: Material collected between 2006 and 2016 in Borneo, Sulawesi, and New Guinea further increased our knowledge of Labiobaetis Novikova &amp; Kluge in these regions. Five species were previously reported from Borneo, two from Sulawesi, and 33 from New Guinea. Six new species have been identified using a combination of morphology and genetic distance (COI, Kimura 2-parameter), one species from Borneo (Brunei), one from Sulawesi, and four from New Guinea. They are described and illustrated based on their larvae and keys to the species of the relevant groups are provided. Additionally, new reports, a complementary description, and the COI sequence for L. dendrisetis Kaltenbach &amp; Gattolliat are presented. The distribution of Labiobaetis in the Wallacea region is discussed based on the new findings. The total number of Labiobaetis species worldwide is augmented to 153.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72251/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 1 Nov 2021 12:34:42 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First description of the female of Sinopoda yichangensis Zhu, Zhong &amp; Yang, 2020 (Araneae, Sparassidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 93-100</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72419</p>
					<p>Authors: Li-Jun Gong, Yang Zhong</p>
					<p>Abstract: Sinopoda yichangensis Zhu, Zhong &amp; Yang, 2020 was described from a single male from Qiaoliao Village, Hubei Province, China. To date, no additional specimens have been recorded. The female is reported for the first time from the type locality. Detailed morphological descriptions of the female, with photographs of living specimens and copulatory organs, are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72419/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 16:00:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Petta (Annelida, Pectinariidae), with comments on Petta assimilis McIntosh, 1885</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 83-92</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72596</p>
					<p>Authors: Jinghuai Zhang, Pat Hutchings</p>
					<p>Abstract: The genus Petta Malmgren, 1866 is a small and poorly known genus of the annelid family Pectinariidae Quatrefages, 1866. A previous revision of the genus found that the type material of the species P. assimilis McIntosh, 1885 had been lost. While searching for material from the type locality, we were able to examine material from a similar area but collected in much shallower water from off South Africa which represents another undescribed species of Petta. The new species, Petta brevis sp. nov., is described and compared to P. assimilis McIntosh, 1885, and a revised key to all species in the genus is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72596/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 15:58:45 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Behningiidae and Potamanthidae (Insecta, Ephemeroptera) in Thailand</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 57-82</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72779</p>
					<p>Authors: Sedtawut Kwanboon, Michel Sartori, Boonsatien Boonsoong</p>
					<p>Abstract: The aim of this study is to review the family Behningiidae and Potamanthidae in Thailand. Two genera and three species of Behningiidae are recognised: Protobehningia merga Peters &amp; Gillies, 1991, Behningia baei McCafferty &amp; Jacobus, 2006, and Behningia nujiangensis Zhou &amp; Bisset, 2019, which is newly reported from Thailand. The egg structure of B. nujiangensis is described for the first time using scanning electron microscopy. The larva of P. merga is redescribed and its distribution is expended northward with a new record from Chiang Mai province. Two genera and five species of Potamanthidae are identified: Potamanthus formosus Eaton, 1892, Rhoenanthus magnificus Ulmer, 1920 (new record for Thailand), Rhoenanthus obscurus Navás, 1922, Rhoenanthus distafurcus Bae &amp; McCafferty, 1991, and Rhoenanthus speciosus Eaton, 1881. Our morphological evidence is supported by COI data for the family Potamanthidae. Diagnostic characters, distributions, and keys are presented for the larvae of all known species of Thai behningiid and potamanthid mayflies.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72779/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 15:55:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>An overview of Estonian woodlice (Isopoda, Oniscidea)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 1-17</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.68105</p>
					<p>Authors: Kaarel Sammet, Getriin Orgusaar, Mari Ivask, Olavi Kurina</p>
					<p>Abstract: An overview of the Estonian terrestrial isopod fauna is given, based on literature data and material collected from 1984 to 2021. The identified material consisted of 10915 specimens belonging to 14 species and collected from 172 localities throughout Estonia. In combination with previous data from the literature data, there are now reliable records of 16 species of woodlice from Estonia. Two species, viz. Platyarthrus hoffmannseggii Brandt, 1833 and Hyloniscus riparius (C. Koch, 1838), are new for the fauna. The latter has probably colonised Estonia recently and range expansions have been reported elsewhere. The data on Philoscia muscorum (Scopoli, 1763) are dubious, and this species is currently excluded from the Estonian list.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68105/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 14:11:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Twelve new species of Dipara Walker, 1833 (Hymenoptera, Chalcidoidea, Pteromalidae, Diparinae) from Kenya, with a key to the Afrotropical species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 101-157</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72395</p>
					<p>Authors: Christoph Braun, Ralph S. Peters</p>
					<p>Abstract: Based on 261 female specimens of the genus Dipara Walker, 1833 from leaf litter samples of the Kakamega Forest in Kenya, we describe the following twelve new species: Dipara andreabalzerae sp. nov., Dipara corona sp. nov., Dipara fastigata sp. nov., Dipara kakamegensis sp. nov., Dipara lux sp. nov., Dipara nigroscutellata sp. nov., Dipara nyani sp. nov., Dipara reticulata sp. nov., Dipara rodneymulleni sp. nov., Dipara sapphirus sp. nov., Dipara tenebra sp. nov., and Dipara tigrina sp. nov. For Dipara albomaculata (Hedqvist, 1963) and Dipara nigrita Hedqvist, 1969, we give new distribution records. We examined the available type material of all described Dipara species from the Afrotropical mainland, i.e., Dipara albomaculata (Hedqvist, 1963), Dipara machadoi (Hedqvist, 1971), Dipara maculata (Hedqvist, 1963), Dipara nigrita Hedqvist, 1969, Dipara pallida (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara punctulata (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara saetosa (Delucchi, 1962), Dipara straminea (Hedqvist, 1969), Dipara striata (Hedqvist, 1969), and Dipara turneri Hedqvist, 1969. We provide figures, descriptions, and diagnoses of the newly described species and figures and diagnoses of the ten known species as well as an identification key to all species of the Afrotropical mainland.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72395/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:33:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The giant pill-millipede genus Zephronia Gray, 1832 from Thailand, with a redescription of Z. siamensis Hirst, 1907 and descriptions of three new species (Diplopoda, Sphaerotheriida, Zephroniidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1067: 19-56</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1067.72369</p>
					<p>Authors: Ruttapon Srisonchai, Chirasak Sutcharit, Natdanai Likhitrakarn</p>
					<p>Abstract: Material of the giant pill-millipede genus Zephronia Gray, 1832 recently collected from Thailand contains three new species: Zephronia enghoffi sp. nov., Zephronia golovatchi sp. nov., and Zephronia panhai sp. nov. The first Zephronia species recorded for Thailand, Z. siamensis Hirst, 1907, is also redescribed based on new specimens collected both from the type locality in Chonburi Province and from neighboring areas. Morphological characters of all new species, Z. phrain Likhitrakarn &amp; Golovatch, 2021, and Z. siamensis are illustrated, and a distribution map of the confirmed Zephronia species occurring in Thailand is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72369/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:05:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Azooxanthellate Scleractinia (Cnidaria, Anthozoa) from South Africa</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1066: 1-198</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1066.69697</p>
					<p>Authors: Zoleka N. Filander, Marcelo V. Kitahara, Stephen D. Cairns, Kerry J. Sink, Amanda T. Lombard</p>
					<p>Abstract: Globally, South Africa ranks in the top five countries regarding marine species richness per unit area. Given the high diversity, it is not surprising that many invertebrate taxa in the region are poorly characterised. The South African azooxanthellate Scleractinia (Anthozoa) is one such taxonomic group, and was last reviewed by Boshoff in 1980. Although more recent regional publications have reported on some species, there has not been a faunistic review that accounts for the country’s species diversity since then. Moreover, numerous unidentified specimens representing more than three decades of sampling effort have accumulated. In this study the authors update the state of knowledge of South African azooxanthellate coral species. Specimens, particularly those within the extensive collections of the Iziko South African and Smithsonian museums, were morphologically examined and identified. Other data considered included historic data represented as imagery data, associated species data from recent research surveys, and the scientific literature. To date, the study has increased the total number of known species from 77 to 108 across eleven families, 28 new South African records, and three are new species with one new genus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69697/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Monograph</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:55:44 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Taxonomic and identification review of adventive Fiorinia Targioni Tozzetti (Hemiptera, Coccomorpha, Diaspididae) of the United States</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 141-203</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.69171</p>
					<p>Authors: Muhammad Z. Ahmed, Matthew R. Moore, Eric A. Rohrig, Cindy L. McKenzie, Di Liu, Jinian Feng, Benjamin B. Normark, Douglass R. Miller</p>
					<p>Abstract: This work provides general descriptions, illustrations, molecular diagnostic data, taxonomic keys, slide mounting recommendations, and Florida distribution records for Fiorinia Targioni Tozzetti species occurring in the USA. Species treated are F. externa Ferris, F. fioriniae (Targioni Tozzetti), F. japonica Kuwana, F. pinicola Maskell, F. phantasma Cockerell &amp; Robinson, F. proboscidaria Green, and F. theae Green. New descriptions of second-instar males and females of all seven species in addition to first-instar nymphs and adult females of F. phantasma and F. proboscidaria are presented. Taxonomic keys to second-instar males and females are developed for the first time and previously available taxonomic keys to first-instar nymphs and adult females are improved. DNA sequences were used to further evaluate the monophyly of Fiorinia and provide additional diagnostic tools for Fiorinia species. Multigene phylogenetic analyses, COI barcoding methods, and examination of type material indicate that F. yongxingensis Liu, Cai &amp; Feng, 2020, syn. nov. is a junior synonym of F. phantasma. A morphological survey of the genus demonstrates, for the first time, the utility of second-instar males for diagnostics. This study will help inform regulatory and pest management decisions by facilitating morphological and molecular identification of adventive Fiorinia species occurring in the USA.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69171/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:18:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the brink of extinction: a new freshwater amphipod Jesogammarus acalceolus (Anisogammaridae) from Japan</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 81-100</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.71687</p>
					<p>Authors: Ko Tomikawa, Naoya Kimura</p>
					<p>Abstract: Freshwater habitats, especially cold springs, are environments in which the risk of extinction faced by organisms remains high due to human activities. To conserve endangered species, it is important to describe and name them. Here, a new, endangered freshwater anisogammarid amphipod species, Jesogammarus (Jesogammarus) acalceolus sp. nov., found in a spring in Aomori Prefecture, Japan, is described which is potentially the sole remaining habitat of this species. Both morphological and molecular phylogenetic results strongly support the nesting of the new species within Jesogammarus. Jesogammarus (J.) acalceolus sp. nov. is the first species of genus Jesogammarus that was found to lack a calceolus, a sensory organ located on male antenna 2. Thus, the diagnostic criteria for this genus required amendment. A reconstruction of ancestral calceoli, based on a molecular phylogenetic tree, revealed that the common ancestor of Jesogammarus possessed calceoli, which were secondarily lost in J. (J.) acalceolus sp. nov. Our results indicate that this new species, which is key to clarifying the evolution of the calceolus, is of high conservation significance.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71687/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:49:04 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New archidermapteran earwigs (Dermaptera) from the Middle Jurassic of Inner Mongolia, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 125-139</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.72720</p>
					<p>Authors: Shurong Xiong, Michael S. Engel, Lifang Xiao, Dong Ren</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of Archidermaptera are described and figured from the Middle Jurassic Jiulonghsan Formation of Daohugou, Inner Mongolia, China. Aneuroderma oiodes gen. &amp; sp. nov. is described in the family Protodiplatyidae and Sinopalaeodermata concavum sp. nov. is established in the family Dermapteridae. Both new species share the typical characters of the extinct suborder Archidermaptera (e.g., pentamerous metatarsi, filiform and multimerous cerci, externalized ovipositor). Aneuroderma gen. nov. is compared with other genera of the Protodiplatyidae, while S. concavum sp. nov. allows us to emend the diagnosis of the genus Sinopalaeodermata. We briefly discuss the diversity of Archidermaptera and challenges to understanding relationships among this mid-Mesozoic diversity.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72720/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:41:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of the genus Rana sensu lato Linnaeus, 1758 (Anura, Ranidae) from Wuyi Mountain, Fujian Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 101-124</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.67005</p>
					<p>Authors: Yanqing Wu, Shengchao Shi, Huiguang Zhang, Weicai Chen, Bin Cai, Van Chung Hoang, Jun Wu, Bin Wang</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the frog genus Rana sensu lato from Wuyi Mountain, Fujian Province, China is described. Molecular phylogenetic analyses clustered the new species into the R. johnsi group and indicated that it was genetically divergent from its closely related species. The new species could be distinguished from its congeners by a combination of the following characters: body size medium, SVL 41.4–45.6 mm (42.9 ± 1.9 mm, n = 4) in adult males and 47.6–50.3 mm (n = 2) in adult females; adult male with a pair of internal subgular vocal sacs; lateroventral grooves present on tip of toes; webbing on fourth toes reaching the tip of toe; transverse skin ridges distinctly present on the dorsal surface of thigh and tibia, the number large (mean 26.5 ± 2.7, range 22–29, n = 6); breeding males possess creamy white nuptial pad with tiny velvety spines on the dorsal surface of the first finger, divided into three parts.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67005/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:39:11 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The first Western Palearctic record of Euprosthenops Pocock (Araneae, Pisauridae), with description of a new species from Israel</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 13-27</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.74119</p>
					<p>Authors: Sergei Zonstein, Yuri M. Marusik</p>
					<p>Abstract: The primarily Afrotropical genus Euprosthenops Pocock, 1897 is recorded in the Western Palearctic for the first time. A diagnosis and an illustrated description of E. insperatus sp. nov., based on a single male from southern Israel, are provided. Considering the structure of the male palp, the holotype of E. insperatus sp. nov. resembles males of two widespread African species, E. australis Simon, 1898 and E. proximus Lessert, 1916; it differs from them by colouration pattern as well as by the different shapes of the retrolateral tibial apophysis and the palpal sclerites. A short survey of the regional insect and spider genera of the paleotropical origin is also presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/74119/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:57:46 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the genus Polypedilum, subgenus Collartomyia, with description of P. (Col.) baishanzuensis sp. nov. from Baishanzu Nature Reserve, China (Diptera, Chironomidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 1-12</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.69870</p>
					<p>Authors: Chao Song, Binqing Zhu, Wei Liu, Xin Qi</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Polypedilum Kieffer, 1912 is described from Baishanzu Nature Reserve, China, based on molecular and morphological data. Molecular phylogenetic analysis based on standard barcode sequences confirmed a new clade of Polypedilum (Collartomyia) species. The new species is easily distinguished from its congeners by a combination of the following morphological characters: membrane of wing with a large spot occupying 70% of the proximal area; tergite without dark brown band pigmentation; tarsi I–V dark brown; superior volsella with three outer lateral setae and six long setae along inner base; inferior volsella with setose tubercules. An updated key to adult males of the subgenus Collartomyia is also provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69870/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:57:03 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Twenty-eight new species of Trigonopterus Fauvel (Coleoptera, Curculionidae) from Central Sulawesi</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1065: 29-79</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1065.71680</p>
					<p>Authors: Raden Pramesa Narakusumo, Alexander Riedel</p>
					<p>Abstract: Here we present 28 new species of Trigonopterus from Central Sulawesi, mostly from Mt Dako and Mt Pompangeo: Trigonopterus acutus sp. nov., T. ancora sp. nov., T. arcanus sp. nov., T. corona sp. nov., T. dakoensis sp. nov., T. daun sp. nov., T. ewok sp. nov., T. gundala sp. nov., T. hoppla sp. nov., T. kakimerah sp. nov., T. katopasensis sp. nov., T. matakensis sp. nov., T. moduai sp. nov., T. mons sp. nov., T. paramoduai sp. nov. T. pomberimbensis sp. nov., T. pompangeensis sp. nov., T. puspoi sp. nov., T. rosichoni sp. nov., T. rubidus sp. nov., T. sarinoi sp. nov., T. sutrisnoi sp. nov., T. tanah sp. nov., T. tejokusumoi sp. nov., T. toboliensis sp. nov., T. tolitoliensis sp. nov., T. tounaensis sp. nov., T. unyil sp. nov. This fills important areas of distribution and brings the number of Trigonopterus species recorded from Sulawesi to 132.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71680/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 11:16:28 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Annotated catalogue of the Tachinidae (Insecta, Diptera) of Chile</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1064: 1-200</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1064.62972</p>
					<p>Authors: James E. O'Hara, D. Monty Wood, Christian R. González</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Tachinidae (Diptera) of Chile are catalogued and information is given on distributions, name-bearing types, synonyms, nomenclatural issues, and pertinent literature. The history of tachinid collectors in Chile and authors who have contributed to the systematic knowledge of Chilean tachinids is extensively reviewed. The classification has been updated and 122 genera and 264 species are recognised in Chile. There is a significant amount of endemism with 28 genera and 100 species known only from Chile. There are also 113 species with distributions shared only between Chile and Argentina, particularly in the southern portions of these countries comprising Patagonia.        The catalogue is based on examination of the original descriptions of all nominal species and all other references known to us containing relevant taxonomic and distributional information, for a total of approximately 450 references. Many of the name-bearing types and other Chilean specimens housed in collections were examined. Taxa are arranged hierarchically and alphabetically under the categories of subfamily, tribe, genus, subgenus (where recognised), and species. Nomenclatural information is provided for genus-group and species-group names, including lists of synonyms (mostly restricted to Neotropical taxa) and name-bearing type data. Species distributions are recorded by country within the New World and by larger geographical divisions in the Old World. Additional information is given in the form of notes and references under valid names at the level of tribe, genus, and species. Two genera are newly recorded from Chile: Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Tachinini) (also newly recorded from Argentina) and Patelloa Townsend, 1916 (Goniini). Four species are newly recorded from Chile or other countries: Lypha ornata Aldrich, 1934 (Chile); Chaetoepalpus coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Argentina and Chile); Phytomyptera evanescens (Cortés, 1967) (Argentina); and Xanthobasis unicolor Aldrich, 1934 (Chile). Eight species previously recorded from Chile are deemed to have been misidentified or misrecorded from Chile (known distributions in parentheses): Archytas incertus (Macquart, 1851) (Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, Uruguay); Archytas seminiger (Wiedemann, 1830) (Brazil, Colombia); Gonia crassicornis (Fabricius, 1794) (Brazil, Peru, Venezuela, Middle America, West Indies, Nearctic); Lespesia andina (Bigot, 1888) (Cuba); Lespesia archippivora (Riley, 1871) (widespread Nearctic and most of Neotropical); Neoethilla ignobilis (van der Wulp, 1890) (Mexico, United States); Siphona (Siphona) geniculata (De Geer, 1776) (Palaearctic, Nearctic [introduced]); and Winthemia quadripustulata (Fabricius, 1794) (Palaearctic, Nearctic, Oriental]. As First Reviser we fix Paratheresia rufiventris Townsend, 1929 as the senior homonym and Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929 as the junior homonym when the two are placed together in Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830; and we fix Mayophorinia angusta Townsend, 1927 as the senior homonym and Metarrhinomyia angusta Townsend, 1927 as the junior homonym when the two are placed together in Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889. New replacement names are proposed for eight preoccupied names of Neotropical species (country of type locality in parentheses): Billaea rufescens O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929, preoccupied in the genus Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 by Paratheresia rufiventris Townsend, 1929 (Peru), nom. nov.; Billaea triquetrus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sarcoprosena triangulifera Townsend, 1927, preoccupied in the genus Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 by Dexia triangulifera Zetterstedt, 1844 (Peru), nom. nov.; Eucelatoria nudioculata O’Hara &amp; Wood for Eucelatorioidea nigripalpis Thompson, 1968, preoccupied in the genus Eucelatoria Townsend, 1909 by Chetolyga nigripalpis Bigot, 1889 (Trinidad), nom. nov.; Eucelatoria oblonga O’Hara &amp; Wood for Urodexodes elongatum Cortés &amp; Campos, 1974, preoccupied in the genus Eucelatoria Townsend, 1909 by Exorista elongata van der Wulp, 1890 (Chile), nom. nov.; Lespesia thompsoni O’Hara &amp; Wood for Sturmiopsoidea obscura Thompson, 1966, preoccupied in the genus Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 by Eurigaster obscurus Bigot, 1857 (Cuba), nom. nov.; Myiopharus charapensis O’Hara &amp; Wood for Metarrhinomyia angusta Townsend, 1927, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Mayophorinia angusta Townsend, 1927 (Peru), nom. nov.; Myiopharus incognitus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Stenochaeta claripalpis Thompson, 1968, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Neoxynopsoidea claripalpis Thompson, 1968 (Trinidad), nom. nov.; and Myiopharus rufopalpus O’Hara &amp; Wood for Paralispe palpalis Townsend, 1929, preoccupied in the genus Myiopharus Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 by Myioxynops palpalis Townsend, 1927 (Peru), nom. nov. New type species fixations are made under the provisions of Article 70.3.2 of the ICZN Code for three genus-group names: Parafabricia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1894 (synonym of Archytas Jaennicke, 1867), type species newly fixed as Parafabricia perplexa Townsend, 1931; Tachinodes Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 (synonym of Archytas Jaennicke, 1867), type species newly fixed as Jurinia metallica Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830; and Willistonia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 (synonym of Belvosia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830), type species newly fixed as Willistonia aldrichi Townsend, 1931. Lectotypes are designated for the following four nominal species, all described or possibly described from Chile: Echinomyia pygmaea Macquart, 1851 (a valid name in the genus Peleteria Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830); Gonia chilensis Macquart, 1844 (a junior synonym of Gonia pallens Wiedemann, 1830); Masicera auriceps Macquart, 1844 (a valid name in the genus Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863); and Prosopochoeta nitidiventris Macquart, 1851 (a valid name in the genus Prosopochaeta Macquart, 1851). The following 27 new or revived combinations are proposed (distributions in parentheses): Blepharipeza andina Bigot, 1888 is moved to Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 as L. andina, nomen dubium (Cuba), comb. nov.; Camposodes evanescens Cortés, 1967 is moved to Phytomyptera Rondani, 1845 as P. evanescens (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Ectophasiopsis ypiranga Dios &amp; Nihei, 2017 is moved to Trichopoda Berthold, 1827 and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia Townsend, 1908 as T. (G.) ypiranga (Argentina, Brazil), comb. nov.; Embiomyia australis Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Steleoneura Stein, 1924 as S. australis (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Eurigaster modestus Bigot, 1857 is moved to Lespesia as L. modesta (Cuba), comb. nov.; Eurigaster obscurus Bigot, 1857 is moved to Lespesia as L. obscura (Cuba), comb. nov.; Macropatelloa tanumeana Townsend, 1931 is moved to Patelloa Townsend, 1916 as P. tanumeana (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Masicera insignis van der Wulp, 1882 is moved to Drino Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863 as D. insignis (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Parasetigena hichinsi Cortés, 1967 is moved to Chetogena Rondani, 1856 as C. hichinsi (Chile), comb. nov.; Parasetigena porteri Brèthes, 1920 and junior synonym Stomatotachina splendida Townsend, 1931 are moved to Chetogena as C. porteri (Chile), both comb. nov.; Phorocera calyptrata Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 as A. calyptrata (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Poliops auratus Campos, 1953 is moved to Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889 as A. aurata (Chile), comb. nov.; Poliops striatus Aldrich, 1934 is moved to Admontia as A. striata (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Ruiziella frontosa Cortés, 1951 is moved to Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 and placed in synonymy with C. coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940 (Argentina, Chile, Peru), comb. nov.; Ruiziella luctuosa Cortés, 1951 is moved to Chaetoepalpus as C. luctuosus (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena luteola Cortés &amp; Campos, 1974 is moved to Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830 as B. luteola (Chile), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena rufiventris Townsend, 1929 is moved to Billaea where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed B. rufescens O’Hara &amp; Wood (Peru), comb. nov.; Sarcoprosena triangulifera Townsend, 1927 is moved to Billaea where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed B. triquetrus O’Hara &amp; Wood (Peru),comb. nov.; Saundersia aurea Giglio-Tos, 1893 is moved to “Unplaced species of Tachinini” (Mexico), comb. nov.; Schistostephana aurifrons Townsend, 1919 is moved to Billaea as B. aurifrons (Peru), comb. nov.; Siphoactia charapensis Townsend, 1927 is moved to Clausicella Rondani, 1856 as C. charapensis (Peru), comb. nov.; Siphoactia peregrina Cortés &amp; Campos, 1971 is moved to Clausicella as C. peregrina (Chile), comb. nov.; Sturmia festiva Cortés, 1944 is moved to Drino as D. festiva (Argentina, Chile), comb. nov.; Sturmiopsoidea obscura Thompson, 1966 is moved to Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863, where it is a junior secondary homonym and is renamed L. thompsoni O’Hara &amp; Wood (Trinidad), comb. nov.; Trichopoda arcuata Bigot, 1876 is returned to Trichopoda from Ectophasiopsis Townsend, 1915 and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia (Argentina, Chile), comb. revived; and Trichopoda gradata Wiedemann, 1830 is returned to Trichopoda from Ectophasiopsis and assigned to subgenus Galactomyia (Argentina, Brazil, Uruguay), comb. revived. New or revived generic and specific synonymies are proposed for the following 14 names: Camposodes Cortés, 1967 with Phytomyptera Rondani, 1845, syn. nov.; Ectophasiopsis Townsend, 1915 with Trichopoda Berthold, 1827, subgenus Galactomyia Townsend, 1908, syn. nov.; Embiomyia Aldrich, 1934 with Steleoneura Stein, 1924, syn. nov.; Fabricia andicola Bigot, 1888 with Peleteria robusta (Wiedemann, 1830), syn. revived; Macropatelloa Townsend, 1931 with Patelloa Townsend, 1916, syn. nov.; Peleteria inca Curran, 1925 with Peleteria robusta (Wiedemann, 1830), syn. revived; Poliops Aldrich, 1934 with Admontia Brauer &amp; Bergenstamm, 1889, syn. nov.; Ruiziella Cortés, 1951 with Chaetoepalpus Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940, syn. nov.; Ruiziella frontosa Cortés, 1951 with Chaetoepalpus coquilleti Vimmer &amp; Soukup, 1940, syn. nov.; Sarcoprosena Townsend, 1927 with Billaea Robineau-Desvoidy, 1830, syn. nov.; Schistostephana Townsend, 1919 with Billaea, syn. nov.; Siphoactia Townsend, 1927 with Clausicella Rondani, 1856, syn. nov.; Stomatotachina Townsend, 1931 with Chetogena Rondani, 1856, syn. nov.; and Sturmiopsoidea Thompson, 1966 with Lespesia Robineau-Desvoidy, 1863, syn. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62972/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Catalogue</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:11:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Pseudosinella Schäffer, 1897 (Collembola, Entomobryidae) from Hungary and Romania, with redescription of the related species Pseudosinella huetheri Stomp, 1971</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 121-137</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.73094</p>
					<p>Authors: Daniel Winkler, Márton Tamás Németh, Cristina Fiera</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Pseudosinella Schäffer, 1897 from Hungary and Romania is described and illustrated. Pseudosinella hartnerae sp. nov. belongs to the group with 5+5 eyes, and can be identified by its unique labial chaetotaxy (M1m2rel1L2) within this group. Pseudosinella huetheri Stomp, 1971, the closest related species sharing the same dorsal macrochaetae formula (R0R1R2001/00/0101+2), is also redescribed here based on the holotype. Comparative analysis between the two species and among other related species is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73094/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 17:46:04 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Gelechia omelkoi sp. nov. – a new species from the Russian Altai Mountains related to the Nearctic Gelechia mandella Busck, 1904 (Lepidoptera, Gelechiidae), with a synopsis of Gelechia from the Altai Republic of Russia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 105-120</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.71914</p>
					<p>Authors: Oleksiy Bidzilya, Peter Huemer, Jean-François Landry, Jan Šumpich</p>
					<p>Abstract: Gelechia omelkoi sp. nov. is described from the Ukok plateau and South Chuisky ridge in the Altai Mountains of Russia. The adult of the new species, including its male genitalia, is illustrated and compared with species most similar in morphology and DNA barcodes—G. sororculella (Hübner, 1817) and G. jakovlevi Krulikovsky, 1905 from the Palaearctic region, as well as G. mandella Busck, 1904 from Canada. This last species is redescribed based on adult specimens, including the genitalia of both sexes, and a lectotype is designated. Gelechia sirotina Omelko, 1986 is recorded from the Altai Republic for the first time. An updated list of six species of Gelechia from the Altai Mountains of Russia is given. Dorsal habitus photographs of all species are provided. The male genitalia of the lectotype of G. jakovlevi is illustrated for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71914/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 07:00:10 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the genus Niphta (Diptera, Thaumaleidae) Theischinger of South America, with descriptions of nine new species and a new immature morphotype</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 49-104</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.71180</p>
					<p>Authors: Robert J. Pivar, Bradley J. Sinclair, John K. Moulton</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Niphta Theischinger fauna of South America is revised to include 11 species, nine of which are described as new to science (N. acus Pivar, sp. nov., N. bifurcata Pivar &amp; Moulton, sp. nov., N. bispinosa Pivar &amp; Sinclair, sp. nov., N. brunnea Pivar, sp. nov., N. courtneyi Pivar, sp. nov., N. daniellae Pivar, sp. nov., N. downesi Pivar, sp. nov., N. eurydactyla Pivar, sp. nov., N. mapuche Pivar, sp. nov.). The genus Niphta is redefined, both previously described Chilean species are redescribed, N. halteralis (Edwards) and N. nudipennis (Edwards), and females are described or redescribed where possible. The first descriptions of the immature stages of South American Niphta are provided, which represent a new larval morphotype in Thaumaleidae, as larvae and pupae possess ventral adhesive structures. Furthermore, these larvae were collected from vegetation rather than rocky substrates. Illustrations and micrographs are provided for all species, and scanning electron microscopy images are included for select immatures. A key to species, distribution maps, and discussions regarding phylogenetic affinities and habitat are also included.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71180/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 07:00:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the Chinese species of subgenus Koreonialoe (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Pterostichus), with descriptions of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 1-21</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.69942</p>
					<p>Authors: Wen-Qi Yin, Hong-Liang Shi, Hong-Bin Liang</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Chinese species of subgenus Koreonialoe Park &amp; Kwon, 1996 of the genus Pterostichus are revised, including four species from the eastern part of Jilin and Liaoning provinces. Two new species are described: Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) micropoides sp. nov. (type locality: Jilin, Changbai county), and Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) tetralobatus sp. nov. (type locality: Liaoning, Xiuyan county). Pterostichus (Koreonialoe) bellatrix (Tschitschérine) is newly recorded from China (Jilin). The subgenus Koreonialoe is classified into two groups on account of their differences on the endophallus, and all Chinese species accord with the microps group defined herein. A key to all six species in the microps group is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69942/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 15:04:55 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Amphibians of the equatorial seasonally dry forests of Ecuador and Peru</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1063: 23-48</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1063.69580</p>
					<p>Authors: Diego Armijos-Ojeda, Diana Székely, Paul Székely, Dan Cogălniceanu, Diego F. Cisneros-Heredia, Leonardo Ordóñez-Delgado, Adrián Escudero, Carlos Iván Espinosa</p>
					<p>Abstract: Seasonally dry forests (SDFs) are one of the most challenging ecosystems for amphibians, fueling the diversity of this group of vertebrates. An updated inventory of native amphibians present in the Equatorial SDF is provided, which extends along the Pacific coast of Ecuador and northwestern Peru. The study is based on an extensive field sampling (two thirds of the total records) carried out throughout the Equatorial SDF, along with a compilation of the available information on distribution of amphibians in the region from published scientific papers, museum collections and on-line databases. The final dataset included 2,032 occurrence records for 30 amphibian species, belonging to eight anuran families. Additionally, data regarding conservation status, habitat use, spawn deposition site, reproductive mode, and body size, along with an identification key for all encountered species are provided. The results indicate a strong sampling bias with a deficit in the Peruvian part of the study area, and a need for urgent inventories targeted at under-sampled areas, using modern taxonomic methods. The study emphasizes the conservation priorities in the Equatorial SDF, based on the distribution, conservation status and life-history data. This information should be useful for the local authorities and institutions involved in the management and conservation of biodiversity in SDF.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/69580/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:46:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Marine diversity in the biosphere reserve of the most oceanic island in the Gulf of California: San Pedro Mártir</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 177-201</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.67964</p>
					<p>Authors: Imelda G. Amador-Castro, Francisco J. Fernández-Rivera Melo, Jorge Torre</p>
					<p>Abstract: San Pedro Mártir island is of high biological, ecological, and fishery importance and was declared a biosphere reserve in 2002. This island is the most oceanic in the Gulf of California, and information on its rocky reefs is scarce. The present study aimed to generate the first list of conspicuous invertebrate and fish species based on in situ observations and to examine the community structure of the shallow rocky reefs of the reserve. In addition, we estimated the ecological indicators of richness, abundance, Shannon diversity, and Pielou evenness to evaluate the conservation status of the biosphere reserve. Data were collected annually from 2007 to 2017 through 2,192 underwater SCUBA transects. A total of 35 species of invertebrates and 73 species of fish were recorded. Most of the species are widely distributed along the eastern Pacific. Overall, 64% of the species found in this study are commercially important, and 11 species have been listed as protected. The abundance of commercially important invertebrate species (i.e., the sea cucumber Isostichopus fuscus and the spiny oyster Spondylus limbatus) is decreasing, while commercially important fish species have maintained their abundance with periods of increase. The ecological indicators and the abundance and size of the commercial species indicate that the reserve is in good condition while meeting its conservation objectives.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67964/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 15:00:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Amphibian fauna of Pakistan with notes on future prospects of research and conservation</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 157-175</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.66913</p>
					<p>Authors: Muhammad Rais, Waseem Ahmed, Anum Sajjad, Ayesha Akram, Muhammad Saeed, Hannan Nasib Hamid, Aamina Abid</p>
					<p>Abstract: Research on amphibians and their conservation have gained worldwide attention, as the group includes the highest number of threatened and Data Deficient species when compared to other vertebrates. However, amphibians have long been neglected in wildlife conservation, management decisions, policy making, and research agendas in Pakistan. In this paper, an annotated checklist of the 21 amphibian species of Pakistan, a key to their identification, and detailed discussions on variation in species, including the genera Minervarya and Sphaerotheca, are provided. We found a statistically significant difference in the morphometric measurements of males but non-significant difference in the females of the two forms (rusty dorsum and dotted dorsum) of S. maskeyi. Some genera, such as Microhyla, Uperodon, Minervarya, Allopaa, Chrysopaa, Euphlyctis, Nanorana, and Sphaerotheca, in Pakistan are in need of additional data for molecular and morphological comparisons with taxa in other South Asian countries. The predicaments of amphibian research in Pakistan are discussed, gaps identified, and suggestions are made. Although the occurrence of chytrid fungus in Pakistan is predicted of low likelihood, a lack of data merits studying the prevalence of the fungus, particularly in the northern regions of the country which exhibit complex and dynamic ecosystems. It is recommended that systematic and coordinated surveys are conducted throughout the country to build a database of species occurrences and distributions. Additionally, the monitoring of wild populations and threat mitigation, as well as appropriate legislation, are suggested as long-term measures. By adopting an inclusive wildlife conservation approach in Pakistan, amphibians could be integrated into wildlife conservation and management efforts.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66913/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Review Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 14:58:58 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On ten species of jumping spiders from Xishuangbanna, China (Araneae, Salticidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 123-155</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.72531</p>
					<p>Authors: Cheng Wang, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Nine new species of jumping spiders from Xishuangbanna Tropical Botanical Garden are described: Euochin yaoi sp. nov. (♀♂), Laufeia banna sp. nov. (♀♂), Marengo tangi sp. nov. (♀♂), Myrmarachne liui sp. nov. (♀♂), Nandicius proszynskii sp. nov. (♂), Phintelloides pengi sp. nov. (♀♂), Poecilorchestes zhengi sp. nov. (♀♂), Rhene wandae sp. nov. (♂) and Simaetha cheni sp. nov. (♀♂). The female of Chinattus inflatus Wang &amp; Li, 2020 is described for the first time.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72531/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>On the clubionid spiders (Araneae, Clubionidae) from Xishuangbanna, China, with descriptions of two new genera and seven new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 73-122</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.66845</p>
					<p>Authors: Jianshuang Zhang, Hao Yu, Shuqiang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Clubionid spiders from Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, China are studied. A total of seven genera and 13 species have been found, including two new genera with one new species each, i.e., Ramosatidia Yu &amp; Li, gen. nov., with R. situ Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀) as the type species and Sinostidia Yu &amp; Li, gen. nov., with S. shuangjiao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀) as the type species. Five additional new species are Sinostidia dujiao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), Matidia xieqian Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), Nusatidia changao Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♂♀), N. mianju Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♀), and N. subjavana Yu &amp; Li, sp. nov. (♀). The following genera and species are reported from China for the first time: Malamatidia Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Pteroneta Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Malamatidia zu Jäger &amp; Dankittipakul, 2010, Nusatidia aeria (Simon, 1897), N. camouflata Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001, Porrhoclubiona pteronetoides (Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001), and Pteroneta ultramarina (Ono, 1989). Malamatidia christae Jäger &amp; Dankittipakul, 2010 syn. nov. is a junior synonym of Malamatidia zu. Nusatidia rama Deeleman-Reinhold, 2001 syn. nov. is synonymised with N. aeria (Simon, 1897).</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66845/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:36:32 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Unexpected diversity in Central European Vespoidea (Hymenoptera, Mutillidae, Myrmosidae, Sapygidae, Scoliidae, Tiphiidae, Thynnidae, Vespidae), with description of two species of Smicromyrme Thomson, 1870</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 49-72</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.70763</p>
					<p>Authors: Christian Schmid-Egger, Stefan Schmidt</p>
					<p>Abstract: The present study presents DNA barcoding results for 134 species of Central European Vespoidea, families Mutillidae, Myrmosidae, Sapygidae, Scoliidae, Tiphiidae, Thynnidae, and Vespidae, including DNA barcodes for 100 of the 114 German species. DNA barcoding resulted in unexpected diversity in several families, each with two or more genetic clusters identified by Barcode Index Numbers (BINs). Smicromyrme burgeri Schmid-Egger, sp. nov. and S. langobardensis Schmid-Egger, sp. nov. are described as new from Germany and Italy, respectively. A neotype is designated for Smicromyrme rufipes (Fabricius, 1878). The results of DNA barcoding are discussed in respect to detecting cryptic species and refining species limits.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70763/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 09:30:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new insular species of the Cyrtodactylus pulchellus group (Reptilia, Gekkonidae) from Tarutao Island, southern Thailand revealed by morphological and genetic evidence</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1070: 101-134</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1070.73659</p>
					<p>Authors: Korkhwan Termprayoon, Attapol Rujirawan, Natee Ampai, Perry L. Wood Jr, Anchalee Aowphol</p>
					<p>Abstract: The bent-toed geckos of the Cyrtodactylus pulchellus group are widely distributed along the Thai-Malay Peninsula. Although taxonomic and phylogenetic studies of this species group have been continuously conducted, only some populations from Thailand have been included, resulting in hidden diversity within this group. In this study, we used morphological and molecular data to clarify the taxonomic status and describe a new population from Tarutao Island, Satun Province, southern Thailand. Cyrtodactylus stellatus sp. nov. can be distinguished from its congeners by the combination of the following morphological characters: body size; tuberculation; number of dark body bands, ventral scales, and femoroprecloacal pores in males; presence of precloacal pores in females; and scattered pattern on dorsum. Phylogenetic analyses of the mitochondrial ND2 gene recovered the new species as the sister species to C. astrum, with an uncorrected pairwise divergence of 9.78–12.37%. Cyrtodactylus stellatus sp. nov. is currently only known from Tarutao Island, Thailand. The discovery of this species suggests that the diversity within the C. pulchellus group remains underestimated and future exploration of unsurveyed areas are needed to further the understanding of this group and its geographic range.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73659/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:37:30 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of freshwater crab of the genus Nanhaipotamon Bott, 1968 (Crustacea, Decapoda, Brachyura, Potamidae) from Longhai, Fujian Province, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 11-30</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.71171</p>
					<p>Authors: Mao-Rong Cai, Qi-Hong Tan, Jie-Xin Zou</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of freshwater crab of the genus Nanhaipotamon Bott, 1968 is described from Xiaye Village, Chengxiang Town, Longhai County, Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province, China. The new species is distinguished from congeners by the combination of characters of its carapace, third maxilliped, unequal chelipeds, triangular male abdomen and unique male first gonopod. Molecular evidence derived from partial mitochondrial 16S rRNA and COI genes also support the species as new.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71171/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:11:29 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of Stenomesius Westwood (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) from China, with a key to Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 1-10</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.67487</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun-Jie Fan, Cheng-De Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of Stenomesius Westwood, S. guanshanensis sp. nov., S. hani sp. nov., and S. harbinensis sp. nov., are described from China. A key to all species of the genus Stenomesius in China is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67487/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:09:48 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New data on the valvatiform-shelled Hydrobiidae (Caenogastropoda, Truncatelloidea) from southern Greece</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1062: 31-47</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1062.64746</p>
					<p>Authors: Sebastian Hofman, Jozef Grego, Zoltán Fehér, Zoltán Péter Erőss, Aleksandra Rysiewska, Artur Osikowski, Andrzej Falniowski</p>
					<p>Abstract: The minute valvatiform-shelled Hydrobiidae are less studied than other hydrobiid gastropods. In this paper, new data on these snails are presented, which have been collected at twelve springs in southern Greece: one in Boeotia, one on Evvoia Island, and ten on the Peloponnese Peninsula. Mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase subunit I (COI) and nuclear histone (H3) have been used to confirm the determinations and infer the relationships of the studied gastropods. They represent the genera Daphniola, Graecoarganiella and Isimerope. New localities, expanding the known geographic ranges, have been presented for Daphniola hadei and Daphniola louisi. A species of Daphniola found at two localities has been identified as a species new to science, and its description, including the shell, penis, and female reproductive organs is given. Possible relationships between Graecoarganiella and Isimerope are discussed; their representatives are possibly new species. At one locality a single specimen likely represents a new genus: it was found to be most closely related with Islamia, but genetically (p-distance) too distant to be congeneric with Islamia.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/64746/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 11:48:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The Herniosina story continues in the Mediterranean: H. calabra sp. nov. from Calabria and H. erymantha Roháček, new female from the Peloponnese (Diptera, Sphaeroceridae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 165-190</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.72235</p>
					<p>Authors: Jindřich Roháček</p>
					<p>Abstract: A study of recently acquired material of Herniosina Roháček, 1983 (Diptera: Sphaeroceridae: Limosininae) in the Mediterranean subregion revealed a new species, H. calabra sp. nov. (Italy: Calabria: Serre Calabresi Mts) and the first females of H. erymantha Roháček, 2016 (Greece: southern Peloponnese: Taygetos Mts). Herniosina calabra sp. nov. (both sexes) and the female of H. erymantha are described and illustrated in detail including structures of terminalia, their relationships are discussed and new information on their biology (habitat association) is given. An update of a key to all know species of Herniosina species is presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72235/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 15:48:24 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Micrurapteryx (Lepidoptera, Gracillariidae) feeding on Thermopsis lanceolata (Fabaceae) in southern Siberia and its hymenopterous parasitoids</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 131-163</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70929</p>
					<p>Authors: Natalia I. Kirichenko, Evgeny N. Akulov, Paolo Triberti, Sergey A. Belokobylskij</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of leaf-mining moth described here as Micrurapteryx baranchikovi Kirichenko, Akulov &amp; Triberti, sp. nov. was detected in large numbers feeding on Thermopsis lanceolata (Fabaceae) in the Republic of Khakassia (Russia) in 2020. A morphological diagnosis of adults, bionomics and DNA barcoding data of the new species are provided. The developmental stages (larva, pupa, adult), male and female genitalia, as well as the leaf mines and the infestation plot in Khakassia are illustrated; the pest status of the new species in the studied region is discussed. Additionally, parasitism rate was estimated, the parasitoid wasps reared from pupae of the new species were identified (morphologically and genetically) and illustrated . Among them, one ichneumonid, Campoplex sp. aff. borealis (Zetterstedt) and two braconids, Agathis fuscipennis (Zetterstedt) and Illidops subversor (Tobias et Kotenko), are novel records for the Republic of Khakassia. Furthermore, they are all documented as parasitoids of Gracillariidae for the first time. The DNA barcode of A. fuscipennis is newly obtained and can be used as a reference sequence for species identification.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70929/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 8 Oct 2021 14:24:47 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Molecular phylogenetic analysis of the genus Gloydius (Squamata, Viperidae, Crotalinae), with description of two new alpine species from Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 87-108</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70420</p>
					<p>Authors: Jing-Song Shi, Jin-Cheng Liu, Rohit Giri, John Benjamin Owens, Vishal Santra, Sourish Kuttalam, Melvin Selvan, Ke-Ji Guo, Anita Malhotra</p>
					<p>Abstract: We provide a molecular phylogeny of Asian pit vipers (the genus Gloydius) based on four mitochondrial genes (12S, 16S, ND4, and cytb). Sequences of Gloydius himalayanus, the only member of the genus that occurs south of the Himalayan range, are included for the first time. In addition, two new species of the genus Gloydius are described based on specimens collected from Zayu, Tibet, west of the Nujiang River and Heishui, Sichuan, east of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. The new species, Gloydius lipipengi sp. nov., can be differentiated from its congeners by the combination of the following characters: the third supralabial not reaching the orbit (separated from it by a suborbital scale); wide, black-bordered greyish postorbital stripe extending from the posterior margin of the orbit (not separated by the postoculars, covering most of the anterior temporal scale) to the ventral surface of the neck; irregular black annular crossbands on the mid-body; 23-21-15 dorsal scales; 165 ventral scales, and 46 subcaudal scales. Gloydius swild sp. nov. can be differentiated from its congeners by the narrower postorbital stripe (only half the width of the anterior temporal scale, the lower edge is approximately straight and bordered with white); a pair of arched stripes on the occiput; lateral body lakes black spots; a pair of round spots on the parietal scales; 21 rows of mid-body dorsal scales; zigzag dark brown stripes on the dorsum; 168–170 ventral scales, and 43–46 subcaudal scales. The molecular phylogeny in this study supports the sister relationship between G. lipipengi sp. nov. and G. rubromaculatus, another recently described species from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, more than 500 km away, and indicate the basal position of G. himalayanus within the genus and relatively distant relationship to its congeners.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70420/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 4 Oct 2021 15:52:15 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Feather mites (Acariformes, Astigmata) from marine birds of the Barton Peninsula (King George Island, Antarctica), with descriptions of two new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 109-130</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.71212</p>
					<p>Authors: Yeong-Deok Han, Sergey V. Mironov, Jeong-Hoon Kim, Gi-Sik Min</p>
					<p>Abstract: We report on the first investigation of feather mites associated with birds living on the Barton Peninsula (King George Island, Antarctica). We found seven feather mite species of the superfamily Analgoidea from four host species. Two new species are described from two charadriiform hosts: Alloptes (Sternalloptes) antarcticus sp. nov. (Alloptidae) from Stercorarius maccormicki Saunders (Stercorariidae), and Ingrassia chionis sp. nov. (Xolalgidae) from Chionis albus (Gmelin) (Chionidae). Additionally, we provide partial sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI), which was utilized as a DNA barcode, for all seven feather mite species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71212/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 4 Oct 2021 10:43:16 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The complete mitochondrial genome of Microphysogobio elongatus (Teleostei, Cyprinidae) and its phylogenetic implications</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 57-73</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70176</p>
					<p>Authors: Renyi Zhang, Qian Tang, Lei Deng</p>
					<p>Abstract: Mitochondria are important organelles with independent genetic material of eukaryotic organisms. In this study, we sequenced and analyzed the complete mitogenome of a small cyprinid fish, Microphysogobio elongatus (Yao &amp; Yang, 1977). The mitogenome of M. elongatus is a typical circular molecule of 16,612 bp in length containing 13 protein-coding genes (PCGs), 22 transfer RNA genes, two ribosomal RNA genes, and a 930 bp control region. The base composition of the M. elongatus mitogenome is 30.8% A, 26.1% T, 16.7% G, and 26.4% C. All PCGs used the standard ATG start codon with the exception of COI. Six PCGs terminate with complete stop codons, whereas seven PCGs (ND2, COII, ATPase 6, COIII, ND3, ND4, and Cyt b) terminate with incomplete (T or TA) stop codons. All tRNA genes exhibited typical cloverleaf secondary structures with the exception of tRNASer(AGY), for which the dihydrouridine arm forms a simple loop. The phylogenetic analysis divided the subfamily Gobioninae in three clades with relatively robust support, and that Microphysogobio is not a monophyletic group. The complete mitogenome of M. elongatus provides a valuable resource for future studies about molecular phylogeny and/or population genetics of Microphysogobio.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70176/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 15:00:42 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Extinct before discovered? Epactoides giganteus sp. nov. (Coleoptera, Scarabaeidae, Scarabaeinae), the first native dung beetle to Réunion island</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 75-86</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.70130</p>
					<p>Authors: Michele Rossini, Fernando Z. Vaz-de-Mello, Olivier Montreuil, Nicholas Porch, Sergei Tarasov</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe a new species of dung beetle, Epactoides giganteus sp. nov., from a single female specimen allegedly collected in the 19th century on Réunion island and recently found at the Muséum national d’Histoire naturelle, Paris. This species differs from other species of Epactoides by larger size and a set of other distinctive morphological characters. Epactoides giganteus sp. nov. is the first native dung beetle (Scarabaeinae) of Réunion, and its discovery expands the known area of distribution of the genus Epactoides, which was hitherto believed to be endemic to Madagascar. Like other taxa from Madagascar and peripheral islands (e.g., Comoro, Seychelles, Mascarenes), E. giganteus sp. nov. may have reached Réunion by over-water dispersal. Given the rapid loss of biodiversity on Réunion island and the fact that no additional specimens were re-collected over the last two centuries, it is very likely that E. giganteus sp. nov. has gone extinct. However, we have unconfirmed evidence that the holotype of E. giganteus sp. nov. might be a mislabeled specimen from Madagascar, which would refute the presence of native dung beetles on Réunion. We discuss both hypotheses about the specimen origin and assess the systematic position of E. giganteus sp. nov. by examining most of the described species of Madagascan Epactoides. Additionally, we provide a brief overview of the dung beetle fauna of Mascarene Archipelago.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70130/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 11:55:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Tipula (Vestiplex) crane flies (Diptera, Tipulidae) of Korea</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 23-55</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.49999</p>
					<p>Authors: Pavel Starkevich, Sigitas Podėnas, Virginija Podėnienė, Sun-Jae Park, A-Young Kim</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Korean species of Tipula (Vestiplex) Bezzi, 1924 crane flies are taxonomically revised. Five species are recognized. Tipula (V.) coquillettiana Alexander, 1924, T. (V.) kuwayamai Alexander, 1921, T. (V.) tchukchi Alexander, 1934, and T. (V.) verecunda Alexander, 1924 are newly recorded from the Korean Peninsula, and T. (V.) serricauda Alexander, 1914 was previously recorded. The larva of T. (V.) serricauda is described and illustrated, and the larvae of the subgenus T. (Vestiplex) are divided into four groups based on spiracular lobe morphology. An identification key, redescriptions, and illustrations of Korean T. (Vestiplex) adults and grouping of known larvae are presented.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/49999/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:35:06 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>First record of the lac-producing species Kerria nepalensis Varshney (Hemiptera, Kerriidae) from China, with a key to Chinese species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73114/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 1-9</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.73114</p>
					<p>Authors: Nawaz Haider Bashir, Weiwei Wang, Juan Liu, Wei Wang, Hang Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: Lac insects include astonishing species responsible for lac production. Lac is composed of resins, dyes, and shellac wax with significant economic importance. Previously, 11 species of the genus Kerria were reported from China, with the highest species diversity in Yunnan province. Another lac-producing species of the genus Kerria, namely Kerria nepalensis Varshney, is recorded for the first time in Yunnan province, China, on Dalbergia cochinchinensis Pierre ex Laness. (Fabaceae), a new host plant. In addition, a key to the 12 Kerria species recorded in China is also given.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73114/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73114/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/73114/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 15:00:58 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Cotesia cassina sp. nov. from southwestern Colombia: a new gregarious microgastrine wasp (Hymenoptera, Braconidae) reared from the pest species Opsiphanes cassina Felder &amp; Felder (Lepidoptera, Nymphalidae) feeding on Elaeis oil palm trees (Arecaceae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67458/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1061: 11-22</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1061.67458</p>
					<p>Authors: Geraldo Salgado-Neto, Consuelo Alexandra Narváez Vásquez, Dillon S. Max, James Whitfield</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of microgastrine wasp, Cotesia cassina Salgado-Neto, Vásquez &amp; Whitfield, sp. nov., is described from southwestern Colombia in Tumaco, Nariño. This species is a koinobiont gregarious larval endoparasitoid, and spins a common mass of cocoons underneath the host caterpillars of Opsiphanes cassina (Felder &amp; Felder) (Lepidoptera, Nymphalidae), feeding on oil palm trees (interspecific hybrid Elaeis oleifera × E. guineensis) (Arecaceae). While superficially similar, both morphologically and biologically, to C. invirae Salgado-Neto &amp; Whitfield from southern Brazil, the two species are distinct based on DNA barcodes, host species, geographical range and morphological characters.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67458/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67458/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67458/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 10:59:12 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new cockroach (Blattodea, Corydiidae) with pectinate antennae from mid-Cretaceous Burmese amber</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67216/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 155-169</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.67216</p>
					<p>Authors: Guanyu Chen, Lifang Xiao, Junhui Liang, Chungkun Shih, Dong Ren</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of fossil cockroach, Fragosublatta pectinata gen. et sp. nov., is described from mid-Cretaceous Burmese amber. The new species is assigned to the family Corydiidae based on the following combination of characters: pronotum with tubercles, tegmina obovate with smallish anal region and spinules on the antero-ventral margin of the front femur (type C1). The new species is the second reported cockroach with ramified antennae. This finding broadens the diversity of Blattodea in mid-Cretaceous Burmese amber and provides further evidence of convergent evolution for antennal structures among different insect lineages.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67216/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67216/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67216/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 14:06:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A solution to the enigma of the type locality of Telmatobius halli Noble, 1938 (Anura, Telmatobiidae), a frog lost for 86 years</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67904/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 183-192</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.67904</p>
					<p>Authors: Claudio Correa</p>
					<p>Abstract: For 80 years, there were no sightings of the Andean frog, Telmatobius halli, due to the ambiguity with which its type locality was described (“warm spring near Ollagüe”, northern Chile). The type specimens were collected during the International High Altitude Expedition to Chile (IHAEC) in 1935 and were subsequently described in 1938. In 2018 and 2020, two studies independently reported the rediscovery of the species, but they reached different conclusions about its identity and geographic distribution. In fact, the populations identified as T. halli in those studies are more phylogenetically related to other species than to each other, so they clearly do not belong to the same taxon. Although the study of 2020 is more in line with the geographic information of the description, it does not consider some bibliographic details and the transport limitations of the IHAEC. Here, based on a detailed analysis of the chronicles of the IHAEC and other bibliographic sources, I first refute the proposals of the 2018 and 2020 studies and then provide a possible solution. The combined information from the chronicles indicates that the type locality of T. halli is found at the sources of the Loa River, a different place from those identified in the two previous studies. By also incorporating geographic information of the time, I conclude that its true type locality is Miño, an abandoned mining camp located near the origin of the Loa River, where currently no populations of the genus have been described.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67904/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67904/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67904/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Commentary</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 11:26:37 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A parasitic insect on a parasitic plant: a new species of the genus Formicoccus Takahashi (Hemiptera, Coccomorpha, Pseudococcidae) from Ishigaki Island, Japan</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71652/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 171-182</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.71652</p>
					<p>Authors: Hirotaka Tanaka, Kenji Suetsugu, Satoshi Kamitani</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Formicoccus Takahashi (Hemiptera, Coccomorpha, Pseudococcidae) collected from the holoparasitic plant Balanophora fungosa J. R. &amp; G. Forst (Balanophoraceae), on Ishigaki Island, Japan, is described as Formicoccus yoshinoi Tanaka, sp. nov. based on the morphology of adult females. This species is similar to F. formicarius (1900) and F. erythrinae Williams, 2004, but differs from them by having fewer than six cerarii, and only one type of ventral oral collar tubular duct distributed on the medial area of the posterior abdominal segments. Keys to the Oriental species of the genus Formicoccus are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71652/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71652/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71652/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 11:25:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Amphibians and reptiles of the Atlantic Forest in Recôncavo Baiano, east Brazil: Cruz das Almas municipality</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62982/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 125-153</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.62982</p>
					<p>Authors: Arielson S. Protázio, Airan S. Protázio, Larissa S. Silva, Lennise C. Conceição, Hugo S. N. Braga, Uilton G. Santos, André C. Ribeiro, Amanda C. Almeida, Vívian Gama, Marcos V. S. A. Vieira, Tiago A. F. Silva</p>
					<p>Abstract: A list of amphibian and reptile species that occur in open and forested areas of the Atlantic Forest in the municipality of Cruz das Almas, in the Recôncavo Baiano, eastern Brazil is presented. Field sampling occurred between January 2015 to March 2019, totalling 117 samples distributed in three areas: Parque Florestal Mata de Cazuzinha, Mata da Cascalheira, and Riacho do Machado. A total of 1,848 individuals of 69 species (31 anurans, 14 lizards, 19 snakes, two amphisbaenians, and three testudines) was recorded. Additionally, one individual of Ophiodes striatus was found in Mata da Cascalheira after the end of sampling, totalling 15 lizard species and 70 herpetofaunal species. The prevalence of open-area species and the presence of Phyllopezus lutzae, Diploglossus lessonae, and Dryadosaura nordestina in interior forest patches are discussed. Additionally, a new record of the invasive terrapin Trachemys dorbigni in the State of Bahia is reported.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62982/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62982/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/62982/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Checklist</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:19:06 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of the genus Melixanthus Suffrian (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Cryptocephalinae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70203/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 111-123</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.70203</p>
					<p>Authors: Wen-Yuan Duan, Feng-Yan Wang, Hong-Zhang Zhou</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of the genus Melixanthus Suffrian, 1854 are described from China: M. menglaensis Duan, Wang &amp; Zhou, sp. nov. from Yunnan (also in Vietnam, Tonkin) and M. similibimaculicollis Duan, Wang &amp; Zhou, sp. nov. from Yunnan. Another species, M. rufiventris Pic, 1926, is reported for the first time in China. High-quality color images and line drawings of adult habitus, aedeagus, and other important structures are provided for all three species. The types of the new species are deposited in the collection of Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences (IZ-CAS).</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70203/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70203/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70203/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 15:54:17 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Rare specimen identification in an un-integrated taxonomy: implications of DNA sequences from a Taiwanese Philine (Mollusca, Philinidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/28809/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 93-110</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.28809</p>
					<p>Authors: Donald J. Colgan, Shane T. Ahyong, Karine Mardon, Ian M. Brereton</p>
					<p>Abstract: Many species of the gastropod genus Philine have been named from northeastern Asia but scanty descriptions based predominantly on shells make it difficult to determine which are valid. This, plus the sporadic anatomical and genetic information available for many of these species has led to what may be described as an un-integrated taxonomy. In this situation, it is generally preferable to postpone dissection of rare and unusual specimens until relevant diagnostic characters can be established in broader studies. Micro-CT scanning and DNA sequencing were used to examine such a specimen collected recently from deep waters off northeastern Taiwan. Micro-CT examination of the morphology of the internal shell and gizzard plates suggested that, among named species, the sequenced specimen is most similar to P. otukai. It cannot, however, be definitively referred to P. otukai as that species lacks adequate anatomical description or known DNA sequences. Phylogenetic analyses of newly collected DNA sequences show the specimen to be most closely related to, but distinct from the northern Atlantic Ocean and Mediterranean species, Philine quadripartita. The sequences also confirm genetically that five or more species of Philine occur in northeast Asia, including at least three subject to considerable taxonomic uncertainty.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/28809/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/28809/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/28809/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 15:53:40 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Bombyciella linzhiensis, a new species from southern Xizang, China (Lepidoptera, Noctuidae, Noctuinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71934/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 85-92</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.71934</p>
					<p>Authors: Enyong Chen, Zhaohui Pan, Anton V. Volynkin, Aidas Saldaitis, Balazs Benedek</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of the genus Bombyciella Draudt, 1950, Bombyciella linzhiensis sp. nov., is described from the Linzhi (Nyingchi) Prefecture in southern Xizang (China), following a diagnostic comparison with B. talpa Draudt, 1950 and B. antra Saldaitis, Benedek, Behounek &amp; Stüning, 2014. The adults and the male genitalia of the new and related species are illustrated.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71934/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71934/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71934/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Rossellid glass sponges (Porifera, Hexactinellida) from New Zealand waters, with description of one new genus and six new species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63307/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 33-84</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.63307</p>
					<p>Authors: Henry M. Reiswig, Martin Dohrmann, Michelle Kelly, Sadie Mills, Peter J. Schupp, Gert Wörheide</p>
					<p>Abstract: New Zealand’s surrounding deep waters have become known as a diversity hotspot for glass sponges (Porifera: Hexactinellida) in recent years, and description and collection efforts are continuing. Here we report on eight rossellids (Hexasterophora: Lyssacinosida: Rossellidae) collected during the 2017 RV Sonne cruise SO254 by ROV Kiel 6000 as part of Project PoribacNewZ of the University of Oldenburg, Germany. The material includes six species new to science, two of which are assigned to a so far undescribed genus; we further re-describe two previously known species. The known extant rossellid diversity from the New Zealand region is thus almost doubled, from nine species in five genera to 17 species in eight genera. The specimens described here are only a small fraction of hexactinellids collected on cruise SO254. Unfortunately, the first author passed away while working on this collection, only being able to complete the nine descriptions reported here. The paper concludes with an obituary to him, the world-leading expert on glass sponge taxonomy who will be greatly missed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63307/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63307/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63307/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 12:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species of the genus Araeopteron Hampson, 1893 (Lepidoptera, Erebidae, Boletobiinae) from the Xizang Autonomous Region, China with an updated list of the world species</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67674/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 17-32</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.67674</p>
					<p>Authors: Hui Lin Han, Vladimir S. Kononenko</p>
					<p>Abstract: Three new species of the genus Araeopteron Hampson, 1893: A. dawai sp. nov., A. medogensis sp. nov. and A. tibeta sp. nov. are described from Motuo (= Medog) County of the Xizang Autonomous Region (= Tibet), China. The imagines as well as the male genitalia are illustrated. A checklist of the 45 species of the genus Araeopteron in the world fauna is presented, including recently and presently described species.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67674/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67674/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67674/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Data Paper</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 16:59:12 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Three new species, and new distributional data, of Haltichella (Hymenoptera, Chalcididae) from China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70427/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1060: 1-16</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1060.70427</p>
					<p>Authors: Zi-Tong Wang, Cheng-De Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Five species of Haltichella (Hymenoptera, Chalcididae) from China are reviewed, including three new species, H. bimaculata Wang &amp; Li, sp. nov., H. bomiana Wang &amp; Li, sp. nov., H. strigata Wang &amp; Li, sp. nov. Haltichella clavicornis (Ashmead) is newly recorded from China and H. nipponensis Habu is newly recorded from Heilongjiang, Shanxi, Shandong, Xizang, Guangdong and Yunnan Provinces in China. A key to the Chinese species of the Haltichella is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70427/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70427/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70427/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 08:00:47 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of the genus Pseudidonauton Hering, 1931 from China (Lepidoptera, Limacodidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68512/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 173-181</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.68512</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun Wu, Alexey V. Solovyev, Hui-Lin Han</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of the genus Pseudidonauton Hering (Lepidoptera, Limacodidae), P. sinensis sp. nov. and P. puera sp. nov., are described from China. The new species are illustrated with images of the adults and male genitalia, and compared with similar species. Distribution maps of these species and a key to all known species of the genus are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68512/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68512/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68512/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 11:59:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The distribution and behavioral characteristics of plateau pikas (Ochotona curzoniae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63581/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 157-171</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.63581</p>
					<p>Authors: Jun Qiu, Cang Ma, Ying-Hui Jia, Jin-Zhao Wang, Shou-Kai Cao, Fang-Fang Li</p>
					<p>Abstract: Plateau pikas (Ochotona curzoniae) are regarded as one of the main causes of the degradation of alpine meadows in the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau (QTP). The population density of plateau pikas is directly related to the degree of grassland damage. In this study, field observation was conducted for one week in the southeastern QTP in August 2019. A random encounter model (REM) was used to estimate the population density of plateau pikas from photographs and videos, and the frequencies of different behaviors were calculated. In addition, the effects of water-source distance and terrain on the distribution of plateau pikas and the frequencies of different pika behaviors under different population densities were explored. The observations and knowledge derived from this study provide a reference for the population control of plateau pikas.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63581/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63581/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/63581/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 10:51:37 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Scenopinus jerei, a new species of window fly (Diptera, Scenopinidae) from Finland</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70085/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 135-156</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.70085</p>
					<p>Authors: Jaakko Pohjoismäki, Antti Haarto</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new species of window fly (Diptera: Scenopinidae), Scenopinus jerei sp. nov., with characteristic bicoloured legs and completely black halteres, is described from Finland. To exclude potential previously named species, a survey of the relevant type specimens as well as original descriptions of the Palearctic and Nearctic Scenopinus species has been conducted, including old Scenopinus fenestralis (Linnaeus) synonyms. Scenopinus jerei sp. nov. is likely to be an overlooked, boreal forest specialist living in the nests of cavity-nesting birds. An identification key to the European species is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70085/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70085/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70085/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:44:25 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The Nazeris fauna of the Nanling Mountain Range, China (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae, Paederinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72240/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 117-133</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.72240</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao-Bin Lin, Jia-Yao Hu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Fourteen species of Nazeris Fauvel, 1873 are reported for the Nanling Mountain Range, China. Four of them are described as new: N. xingmini Lin &amp; Hu, sp. nov. (Guangdong, Jiangxi), N. huaiweni Lin &amp; Hu, sp. nov. (Guangdong), N. meihuaae Lin &amp; Hu, sp. nov. (Guangdong, Jiangxi) and N. lichongi Lin &amp; Hu, sp. nov. (Hunan). An identification key to the Nazeris species reported for the Nanling Mountains, and a map showing their distribution are provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72240/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72240/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/72240/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Sep 2021 18:51:01 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new species of Dugesia (Platyhelminthes, Tricladida, Dugesiidae) from the tropical monsoon forest in southern China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/65633/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 89-116</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.65633</p>
					<p>Authors: Lei Wang, Jin-zi Chen, Zi-mei Dong, Guang-wen Chen, Ronald Sluys, De-zeng Liu</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new species of the genus Dugesia (Platyhelminthes, Tricladida, Dugesiidae) from the tropical monsoon forest in southern China are described on the basis of an integrative taxonomic study involving morphology, karyology, histology, and molecular analyses. The new species Dugesia circumcisa Chen &amp; Dong, sp. nov. is characterised by asymmetrical openings of the oviducts; right vas deferens opening at anterior portion of the seminal vesicle and the left one opening at mid-lateral portion of the seminal vesicle; two diaphragms in ejaculatory duct, the latter being ventrally displaced and opening at the tip of the penis papilla, which is provided with a nozzle; wide duct connecting male atrium and common atrium; chromosome complement triploid with 24 metacentric chromosomes. The other new species, Dugesia verrucula Chen &amp; Dong, sp. nov., is characterised by the large size of the living worm, usually exceeding 3.5 cm in length; asymmetrical openings of the oviducts; subterminal opening of ventrally displaced ejaculatory duct; vasa deferentia symmetrically opening into the postero-lateral portion of the seminal vesicle; well-developed duct between the seminal vesicle and diaphragm; single dorsal bump near the root of the penis papilla; bursal canal with pleated wall and spacious posterior section; unstalked cocoons; chromosome complement diploid with 16 metacentric chromosomes. Inter-specific molecular distances and their positions in the phylogenetic tree reveal that D. circumcisa and D. verrucula are clearly separated from their congeners.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/65633/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/65633/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/65633/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Sep 2021 18:08:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new Colombian species of Liodessus diving beetles from the Páramo de Sumapaz (Coleoptera, Dytiscidae, Bidessini)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70134/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 79-87</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.70134</p>
					<p>Authors: Michael Balke, Yoandri Suarez-Megna, Rodulfo Ospina-Torres, Juan Simon Venegas, Carlos Prieto, Lars Hendrich</p>
					<p>Abstract: Liodessus picinus sp. nov. is described from the Páramo de Sumapaz near Bogota D.C. at 3,500 m above sea level. The species can be distinguished from the other Colombian Liodessus species by its dark coloration, discontinuous habitus, shiny surface of the pronotum and elytron, presence of a distinct occipital line, distinct basal pronotal striae, short or even faint basal elytral striae, as well as by its distinct geographic distribution and cox1 signature.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70134/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70134/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70134/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 8 Sep 2021 17:46:14 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Two new genera and three new species of cavernicolous trechines from the western Wuling Mountains, China (Coleoptera, Carabidae, Trechinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70009/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 57-78</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.70009</p>
					<p>Authors: Mingyi Tian, Sunbin Huang, Xinyang Jia, Yi Zhao</p>
					<p>Abstract: Two new genera and three new species of cave-adapted ground beetles belonging to the tribe Trechini are established and described: Wulongius qilinger gen. nov. and sp. nov. from limestone cave Qiankou Dong (Chongqing: Wulong), Qianotrechus congcongae sp. nov. from cave Shigao Dong (Chongqing: Nanchuan), and Qianlongius zhoui gen. nov. and sp. nov. from cave Qianlong Dong (Guizhou: Songtao). Wulongius qilinger sp. nov. is a small aphaenopsian beetle with a thin and elongated body, while Qianlongius zhoui sp. nov. is a semi-aphaenopsian with a stout body. Both new genera are not closely related to any genus of Trechini occurring in the South China Karst, and so their systematic positions remain unclear.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70009/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70009/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70009/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 3 Sep 2021 17:46:27 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Music frog (Anura, Ranidae, Nidirana) from Mt Daming, Guangxi, China</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68140/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 35-56</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.68140</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhi-Tong Lyu, Zhong Huang, Xiao-Wen Liao, Li Lin, Yong Huang, Ying-Yong Wang, Yun-Ming Mo</p>
					<p>Abstract: Nidirana guangxiensis sp. nov., a new music frog species, is proposed, based on a series of specimens collected from Mt Daming, Guangxi, southern China. The new species is close to N. yeae, N. daunchina, N. yaoica, and N. chapaensis from southwestern and south-central China and northern Indochina, while the relationships among these species remain unresolved. Nidirana guangxiensis sp. nov. can be distinguished from all known congeners by the genetic divergences in the mitochondrial 16S and COI genes, the behavior of nest construction, the advertisement call containing 6–11 rapidly repeated regular notes, and a combination of morphological characteristics. Furthermore, the Nidirana populations recorded in Guangxi are clarified in this work, providing valuable new information on the knowledge of the genus Nidirana.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68140/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68140/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68140/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Sep 2021 17:46:51 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Systematic revision of Stegodera Martens, 1876 (Gastropoda, Stylommatophora, Camaenidae), with description of a new genus</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68385/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 1-21</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.68385</p>
					<p>Authors: Zhe-Yu Chen, Zhi-Tong Lyu, Min Wu</p>
					<p>Abstract: The monotypic genus Stegodera Martens, 1876 is systematically revised based on anatomical and morphological examination of freshly collected specimens. A new species from southern Hunan, which resembles Stegodera angusticollis, is confirmed to represent a new genus evidenced by comparative shell morphology and anatomy as well as by molecular phylogenetic analyses. The new genus might be more closely related to Stegodera and Nesiohelix Kuroda &amp; Emura, but differs anatomically from the latter two genera by the absence of a dart apparatus.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68385/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68385/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68385/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Sep 2021 17:17:26 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The termite genus Glyptotermes (Isoptera, Kalotermitidae) from Paraguay</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70500/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1059: 23-33</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1059.70500</p>
					<p>Authors: Rudolf H. Scheffrahn</p>
					<p>Abstract: A 2012 termite expedition yielded the first species of Glyptotermes known from Paraguay, G. hickmani sp. nov. and G. canellae (Müller, 1873), the latter previously known from Argentina and Brazil. Both are described based on the soldier and imago castes.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70500/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70500/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/70500/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 1 Sep 2021 17:17:22 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>The millipede tribe Brachyiulini in the Caucasus (Diplopoda, Julida, Julidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68628/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1058: 1-127</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1058.68628</p>
					<p>Authors: Boyan Vagalinski, Sergei I. Golovatch</p>
					<p>Abstract: The diplopod tribe Brachyiulini is represented in the fauna of the Caucasus by eight genera and 32 species, of which one genus and 14 species are described as new: Colchiobrachyiulus montanus Vagalinski, sp. nov., Iraniulus tricornis Vagalinski, sp. nov., Omobrachyiulus armatus Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. fasciatus Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. faxifer Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. kvavadzei Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. lazanyiae Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. ponticus Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. pristis Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. trochiloides Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. unugulis Vagalinski, sp. nov., O. zuevi Vagalinski, sp. nov., Svaniulus ryvkini Vagalinski, gen. nov., sp. nov., and S. waltheri Vagalinski, gen. nov., sp. nov. Colchiobrachyiulus Lohmander, 1936, a former subgenus of Megaphyllum, is here elevated to a full genus, and the genus Grusiniulus Lohmander, 1936 is downgraded to a subgenus of the genus Cyphobrachyiulus Verhoeff, 1900, both stat. nov., with their previously described species, Colchiobrachyiulus dioscoriadis (Lignau, 1915) and Cyphobrachyiulus redikorzevi (Lohmander, 1936), respectively, listed as comb. nov. Omobrachyiulus brachyurus (Attems, 1899) is formally established as a junior subjective synonym of O. caucasicus (Karsch, 1881), syn. nov., and Omobrachyiulus implicitus ritsensis (Golovatch, 1981) is formally synonymised with the typical Omobrachyiulus implicitus (Lohmander, 1936), syn. nov. Omobrachyiulus sevangensis (Lohmander, 1932), originally described in the genus Megaphyllum, is here transferred to the former genus, comb. nov. The diagnoses and descriptions of some genera and subgenera are refined and complemented. A key is given to all genera and species of Brachyiulini that occur in the Caucasus, and their distributions are mapped. Several species are recorded as new to the faunas of Armenia, Azerbaijan, Georgia, or Russia. The distribution patterns of the Caucasian Brachyiulini and their biogeographic implications are discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68628/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68628/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68628/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Monograph</category>
		    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:47:33 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Novel lures and COI sequences reveal cryptic new species of Bactrocera fruit flies in the Solomon Islands (Diptera, Tephritidae, Dacini)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68375/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 49-103</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.68375</p>
					<p>Authors: Luc Leblanc, Francis Tsatsia, Camiel Doorenweerd</p>
					<p>Abstract: Results from a snap-shot survey of Dacine fruit flies carried out on three of the Solomon Islands in April 2018 are reported. Using traps baited with the male lures cue-lure, methyl eugenol, and zingerone, 30 of the 48 species previously known to occur in the Solomon Islands were collected. Six species are newly described here: Bactrocera allodistincta sp. nov., B. geminosimulata sp. nov., B. kolombangarae sp. nov., B. quasienochra sp. nov., B. tsatsiai sp. nov., and B. vargasi sp. nov., all authored by Leblanc &amp; Doorenweerd. An illustrated key to the 54 species now known to be present in the country is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68375/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68375/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68375/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 19:34:46 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>          Synorthocladius federicoi sp. nov., a new species occurring in the middle basin of the Adige River, northern Italy (Diptera, Chironomidae, Orthocladiinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68175/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 105-116</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.68175</p>
					<p>Authors: Valeria Lencioni, Joel Moubayed</p>
					<p>Abstract: An adult male Synorthocladius was collected in the middle basin of the Adige River in the city of Verona, northern Italy. A combination of atypical characters for the genus signalled a new species. Synorthocladius federicoi sp. nov. is here diagnosed and described. The new species is known only from its type locality and is presumed to be a local biogeographical representative of the Italian Pre-Alps. An emended generic diagnosis, a key to known Synorthocladius from Europe and comments on the taxonomic position of the new species are given.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68175/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68175/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/68175/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Short Communication</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 16:41:12 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A new species of Leucostethus (Anura, Dendrobatidae) from Gorgona Island, Colombia</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67621/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 185-208</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.67621</p>
					<p>Authors: Taran Grant, Wilmar Bolívar-García</p>
					<p>Abstract: We describe a new species of Leucostethus from Gorgona Island, a small (13 km2) island located 35 km from the Pacific coast of southern Colombia. The new species most resembles L. argyrogaster and L. fugax from western Amazonia at 340–870 m elev. in Peru and Ecuador, with which it shares pale ventral coloration and orange suffusion of the axilla, groin and concealed surfaces of the hind limb, but it is most closely related to L. bilsa from ca. 340 km SW in the southern Chocó at 420–515 m elev., northwestern Ecuador. We report miniscule white spots on the posteroventral surface of the thighs of the new species and, on the basis of our preliminary assessment of their taxonomic distribution, hypothesize that their presence is a synapomorphy of Dendrobatoidea with subsequent losses in a few groups. Given the apparent restriction of the new species to Gorgona Island, it is Vulnerable according to IUCN Red List criteria. In addition to naming the new species, we also propose the following new combinations: L. alacris (Rivero and Granados-Díaz, 1990) comb. nov., L. dysprosium (Rivero and Serna, 2000) comb. nov., and L. yaguara (Rivero and Serna, 1991) comb. nov.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67621/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67621/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/67621/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 10:04:12 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>A review of the Eviota zebrina complex, with descriptions of four new species (Teleostei, Gobiidae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66675/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 149-184</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.66675</p>
					<p>Authors: Luke Tornabene, David W. Greenfield, Mark V. Erdmann</p>
					<p>Abstract: The Eviota zebrina complex includes eight species of closely-related dwarfgobies, four of which are herein described as new. The complex is named for Eviota zebrina Lachner &amp; Karnella, 1978, an Indian Ocean species with the holotype from the Seychelles Islands and also known from the Maldives, which was once thought to range into the Gulf of Aqaba and the Red Sea eastward to the Great Barrier Reef of Australia. Our analysis supports the recognition of four genetically distinct, geographically non-overlapping, species within what was previously called E. zebrina, with E. zebrina being restricted to the Indian Ocean, E. marerubrum sp. nov. described from the Red Sea, E. longirostris sp. nov. described from western New Guinea, and E. pseudozebrina sp. nov. described from Fiji. The caudal fin of all four of these species is crossed by oblique black bars in preservative, but these black bars are absent from the four other species included in the complex. Two of the other species within the complex, E. tetha and E. gunawanae are morphologically similar to each other in having the AITO cephalic-sensory pore positioned far forward and opening anteriorly. Eviota tetha is known from lagoonal environments in Cenderawasih Bay and Raja Ampat, West Papua, and E. gunawanae is known only from deeper reefs (35–60 m) from Fakfak Regency, West Papua. The final two species are E. cometa which is known from Fiji and Tonga and possesses red bars crossing the caudal fin (but lost in preservative) and a 9/8 dorsal/anal-fin formula, and E. oculineata sp. nov., which is described as new from New Guinea and the Solomon Islands, and possesses an 8/7 dorsal/anal-fin formula and lacks red caudal bars. Eviota oculineata has been confused with E. cometa in the past.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66675/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66675/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66675/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 09:49:02 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>Revision of the genus Furusawaia Chûjô, 1962 (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae, Galerucinae)</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71451/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 117-148</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.71451</p>
					<p>Authors: Chi-Feng Lee, Jan Bezděk</p>
					<p>Abstract: Yunnaniata Lopatin, 2009 is regarded as a junior synonym of Furusawaia Chûjô, 1962 syn. nov. Yunnaniata konstantinovi Lopatin, 2009 comb. nov. is transferred to the genus Furusawaia Chûjô and redescribed. Furusawaia continentalis Lopatin, 2008 and F. yosonis Chûjô are recognized as valid species and redescribed. Four new species are described from Taiwan: F. jungchani sp. nov., F. lui sp. nov., F. tahsiangi sp. nov., and F. tsoui sp. nov. A key to Taiwanese and Chinese species of Furusawaia is provided.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71451/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71451/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/71451/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 09:42:18 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
		<item>
		    <title>New mimarachnids (Hemiptera, Fulgoromorpha, Fulgoroidea) in mid-Cretaceous Burmese amber</title>
		    <link>https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66434/</link>
		    <description><![CDATA[
					<p>ZooKeys 1057: 37-48</p>
					<p>DOI: 10.3897/zookeys.1057.66434</p>
					<p>Authors: Xiao Zhang, Yunzhi Yao, Dong Ren, Hong Pang, Huayan Chen</p>
					<p>Abstract: A new genus and species, Multistria orthotropa gen. et sp. nov., and a new species, Dachibangus hui sp. nov., of Mimarachnidae are described from the mid-Cretaceous Burmese amber. These new taxa display unique wing color patterns and extend the Mesozoic diversity of Mimarachnidae. The evolution of wing venation, phylogenetic placement of Mimarachnidae, and anti-predation defenses of this family in Burmese amber forest are briefly discussed.</p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66434/">HTML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66434/download/xml/">XML</a></p>
					<p><a href="https://zookeys.pensoft.net/article/66434/download/pdf/">PDF</a></p>
			]]></description>
		    <category>Research Article</category>
		    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 11:46:52 +0300</pubDate>
		</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
	